<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:44:36 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Australia politics live: Tim Wilson ejected and Angus Taylor warned to stop heckling during rowdy question time</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Follow updates live&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/29/australia-inflation-rate-cpi-consumer-price-index-figure-rba-reserve-bank"&gt;Inflation jumps to 3.2%, dashing hopes of a Melbourne Cup day rate cut for homeowners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Coalition is still in the middle of a fight over the future of its energy policy, with big fractures between members over whether the 2050 net zero target should be kept.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The party is working towards something of a compromise, but there are a few moderates who don’t want that target to change – including shadow housing minister &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Bragg&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look, I think we’ll get there on net zero. I know there’s a lot of interest in it. I think ultimately there’s an ability there for the Coalition to do this much better than Labor. Labor’s net zero [policy] has been a disaster …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we could do net zero better than Labor in terms of emissions and cost and environmental protection, &lt;strong&gt;but you’ve got to keep net zero&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that you probably find it all very interesting to talk about, but we do have a culture of openness in the Liberal party and the National party, and we seem to talk about a lot of things. I mean, frankly, &lt;strong&gt;I wonder what the nation will talk about if the Liberal party died, because I think we’d sort of run out of things to discuss.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communities around the country are trying to focus and talk about the issues that matter to them, not try to make some fake news thing out of a T-shirt the prime minister gets wearing off a plane. It’s ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look, there’s a lot to legitimately criticise the prime minister about trillion dollar debt, skyrocketing house prices and job losses in our heavy industrial sector wearing a T-shirt is not one of them … So yeah, get on with acting on antisemitism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:29:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli strikes kill 33 in Gaza, Hamas-run civil defence says, as Trump insists ceasefire remains</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgjdy5eevn2o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Israel and Hamas have both accused each other of breaking the US-brokered ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgjdy5eevn2o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:19:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan Says Peace Talks With Afghan Taliban Fail To Find 'Workable Solution'</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-negotiations-clashes-border/33575282.html</link><description>Negotiations for a lasting truce between Afghanistan and Pakistan have broken down, Pakistani Information Minister Attaullah Tarar said on October 29 after four days of negotiations brokered by Qatar and Turkey.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-negotiations-clashes-border/33575282.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:14:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzanian president poised to retain power as rivals barred from election</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Government critics abducted, killed or arrested in run-up to vote as Samia Suluhu Hassan faces first electoral test&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tanzania’s president looks on course to strengthen her grip on the country as it holds a general election on Wednesday against the backdrop of rapidly intensifying repression and the exclusion of opposition candidates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samia Suluhu Hassan, a former vice-president who took office after the death of her predecessor, John Magufuli, in 2021, has left nothing to chance for her first presidential and parliamentary electoral test.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:00:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korea is less interested in its European allies</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/south-korea-less-interested-european-allies/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</link><description>As Seoul concentrates on greeting relations with the U.S. on surer footing, it seems it has little time for the bloc or NATO.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.politico.eu/article/south-korea-less-interested-european-allies/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. crude inventories expected to fall by 0.2M barrels. API data indicated larger drops: crude -4.02M, gasoline -6.35M, distillate -4.36M barrels. Refinery utilization up 0.2%</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A poll released Tuesday indicated that U.S. crude oil stockpiles were expected to decline last week, along with inventories of gasoline and distillates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The poll of eight analysts, conducted before the release of weekly inventory data, projected an average decrease of approximately 200,000 barrels in crude inventories for the week ending October 24.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the week ending October 17, the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA) reported that crude inventories fell by 961,000 barrels to 422.8 million barrels. This contrasted with analysts’ expectations from a prior Reuters poll, which had anticipated a 1.2-million-barrel increase.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The poll also estimated that distillate inventories, including diesel and heating oil, fell by about 1.7 million barrels last week. Gasoline stockpiles were projected to have decreased by roughly 1.9 million barrels. The refinery utilization rate was estimated to have risen by 0.2 percentage points from the previous week’s 88.6% of total capacity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Market sources, citing figures from the American Petroleum Institute (API) on Tuesday, said that U.S. crude, gasoline, and distillate stocks all experienced declines last week. According to these anonymous sources, crude stocks decreased by 4.02 million barrels in the week ending October 24. Gasoline inventories dropped by 6.35 million barrels, while distillate inventories fell by 4.36 million barrels compared to the previous week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Reuters poll was conducted in anticipation of the weekly API report and the EIA report, the statistical branch of the U.S. Department of Energy, which is scheduled for release at Wed. All stock figures are given in millions of barrels, and refinery rate changes are measured in percentage points.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://starfeu.com"&gt;starfeu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/StarFEU-Commodity"&gt; /u/StarFEU-Commodity &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:52:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Validating a Predictive Recruitment Framework for U.S. Critical Sectors</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve developed a new data-driven recruitment framework for critical U.S. sectors such as Energy, Security, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure that has achieved remarkable results so far:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;• 0% turnover within the first 12 months • Process time reduced from 29 days to 9 • Recruitment costs reduced by 38% • Applied in 371 projects and over 29,000 candidates evaluated &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The model essentially eliminates subjectivity in hiring by applying data science principles to both client and candidate assessment. It protects organizations from the financial and operational impact of mis-hires, and it helps professionals make more sustainable career decisions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m now working to launch operations in the U.S., with headquarters planned for Washington, D.C., and two satellite offices in Austin and San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At this stage, my goal is to validate the business model locally and gather letters of intent from executives interested in testing or piloting the framework once operations begin. (This is not a binding contract, simply an expression of future business interest if feasibility is confirmed.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Given how supportive and experienced this community is, I thought it would be the right place to share the initiative.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If anyone would like to review the framework details, I’d be happy to share more information by email — and if there’s genuine interest, we can formalize an expression of intent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Would love to hear your thoughts or perspectives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Standard_Pangolin913"&gt; /u/Standard_Pangolin913 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:50:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Woman denies gas supply sabotage as police investigate death of elderly man at Sutherland hospital</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/sutherland-hospital-gas-supply-nsw-police-investigating-death-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;NSW police say ‘an investigation is under way following the death of a man at Sutherland hospital’ while Vanessa Moulton, 42, has denied sabotage charges&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police are investigating the death of a 72-year-old man at Sutherland public hospital, which occurred after a woman had &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/28/woman-arrested-allegedly-sabotaging-gas-supplies-sydney-hospitals-sutherland"&gt;allegedly sabotaged gas supplies&lt;/a&gt; at the facility.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New South Wales police on Tuesday charged Vanessa Moulton, 42, with cutting Kareena private hospital’s non-medical gas supply and water mains at 12.20am that day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/sutherland-hospital-gas-supply-nsw-police-investigating-death-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/sutherland-hospital-gas-supply-nsw-police-investigating-death-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:43:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel strikes Gaza after Netanyahu accuses Hamas of breaching ceasefire</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prime minister accuses Hamas of ‘clear violation’ of truce as far-right ministers clamour to resume war&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israeli warplanes struck Gaza on Tuesday night, shortly after Israel’s prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, ordered the military to carry out “powerful strikes” in Gaza, in the most serious test of the increasingly shaky US-brokered ceasefire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Witnesses reported seeing Israeli planes launch strikes on Gaza City, as well as explosions across the strip shortly after Netanyahu’s announcement. At least seven people were killed in separate strikes in Gaza City and Khan Younis, including two children, medical sources said.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:38:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Humpback whale calf dies off NSW coast while entangled in shark net</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/humpback-whale-calf-dies-off-nsw-coast-while-entangled-in-shark-net</link><description>&lt;p&gt;It is the first whale to have died out of 15 entangled in shark nets on Australia’s east coast so far this year&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A humpback whale calf has been found dead after becoming entangled in a shark net off the New South Wales coast.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 8-metre juvenile whale was found wrapped in netting north of Wollongong on Tuesday, in waters between Coledale and Wombarra.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/humpback-whale-calf-dies-off-nsw-coast-while-entangled-in-shark-net"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/humpback-whale-calf-dies-off-nsw-coast-while-entangled-in-shark-net</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:23:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rockylinux.org not hosted on Rocky Linux</title><link>https://rockylinux-org.vercel.app/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741877"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://rockylinux-org.vercel.app/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:20:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Court to reconsider ruling that allowed Trump to send troops to Portland</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President remains barred from deploying national guard as appeals court agrees to ‘en banc’ rehearing of case&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration remains barred from deploying the national guard in Portland, Oregon, following a federal appeals court ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ninth circuit court of appeals agreed on Tuesday that it would rehear a case over the president’s authority with a broader court of 11 judges. The appeals court also vacated a ruling from a three-judge panel last week that sided with the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump heads to South Korea amid deadlocked trade talks over $350bn deal on tariffs</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US president will meet his South Korean counterpart, Lee Jae Myung, but expectations of a breakthrough on tariffs are low&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump heads to South Korea on Wednesday to meet President Lee Jae Myung, with deadlocked talks over a $350bn trade deal between the two countries threatening to cast a shadow over the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After arriving on a flight from Tokyo, where he &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/donald-trump-sanae-takaichi-japan-prime-minister-rare-earths-agreement"&gt;signed a rare earths deal with Japan’s new prime minister&lt;/a&gt;, Sanae Takaichi, the US president is due to address a summit of CEOs and meet Lee in the town of Gyeongju, a historical city playing host to the annual Apec summit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:39:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian girls being 'hunted' by online crime gangs to commit violent acts</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0qpl7v7p0jo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Groups of young men are coercing and exploiting vulnerable girls "for fun", Australian police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0qpl7v7p0jo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:26:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Border patrol leader told to go to court every weekday to report on Chicago enforcement</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal judge gives orders to Gregory Bovino in exceptional bid to impose oversight over Trump officials’ raids in city&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A federal judge has ordered Gregory Bovino, a senior border patrol official leading the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt;’s immigration crackdown in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/chicago"&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, to appear in federal court each weekday to report on the day’s incidents in an exceptional bid to impose oversight over the government’s militarized raids in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The order came following a terse hearing on Tuesday morning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:26:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Storm of the century’: record-breaking Hurricane Melissa hits Jamaica</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minister says parish of St Elizabeth is ‘under water’ and that families are trapped in their homes in the community of Black River in western Jamaica&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-live-updates-category-5-storm-jamaica-landfall-latest-news"&gt;Hurricane Melissa – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-a-visual-guide-to-the-strongest-storm-to-hit-jamaica-in-almost-two-centuries"&gt;A visual guide to Jamaica’s strongest storm since 1851&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Melissa has made landfall as a category 5 storm in Jamaica, battering the country with ferocious winds, heavy flood waters and landslides from one of the strongest Atlantic hurricanes in history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jamaica’s minister of local government, Desmond Mckenzie, said on Tuesday afternoon that the south-western parish of St Elizabeth was “under water” and that at least three families were trapped in their homes in the community of Black River in western Jamaica. Emergency services were struggling to reach due them to the dangerous conditions, he said. He declined to confirm whether there were any deaths.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:17:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wole Soyinka, Nigerian Nobel laureate and Trump critic, says US visa revoked</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Soyinka, 91, who recently compared US president to Idi Amin, says ‘I have no visa – I am banned’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration has revoked the visa for Wole Soyinka, the acclaimed Nigerian Nobel prize-winning writer who has been critical of Trump since his first presidency, Soyinka revealed on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I want to assure the consulate … that I’m very content with the revocation of my visa,” Soyinka, who won the 1986 Nobel prize for literature, told a news conference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:14:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Project Shadowglass</title><link>https://shadowglassgame.com</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741391"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://shadowglassgame.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:06:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Inflation jumps to 3.2%, dashing hopes of a Melbourne Cup day rate cut for homeowners</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/29/australia-inflation-rate-cpi-consumer-price-index-figure-rba-reserve-bank</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The RBA has long anticipated a rebound in the headline inflation rate, driven by the rolling expiry of generous household power bill subsidies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Inflation has jumped to 3.2% in the year to September, from 2.1% in June, as waning government subsidies feed through to a spike in household power bills.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Any lingering chance of a rate cut next Tuesday – or potentially this year – was squashed after the Australian Bureau of Statistics figures also confirmed the first rise in underlying inflation in nearly three years.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/29/australia-inflation-rate-cpi-consumer-price-index-figure-rba-reserve-bank"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/29/australia-inflation-rate-cpi-consumer-price-index-figure-rba-reserve-bank</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:58:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Elderly woman left behind by cruise ship on Great Barrier Reef island found dead</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c62eww646wjo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The ship's crew realised the 80-year-old was missing several hours after they had left the island</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c62eww646wjo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:34:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AFP developing AI tool to decode gen Z slang amid warning about ‘crimefluencers’ hunting girls</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/afp-developing-ai-tool-to-decode-gen-z-and-alpha-slang-amid-warning-about-crimefluencers</link><description>&lt;p&gt;AFP commissioner Krissy Barrett says online crime networks of young boys and men are targeting vulnerable teen and preteen girls&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australian federal police will develop an AI tool to decode gen Z and Alpha slang and emojis in an effort to crackdown on sadistic online exploitation and “crimefluencers”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The AFP commissioner, Krissy Barrett, used a speech at the National Press Club on Wednesday to warn of the rise of online crime networks of young boys and men who are targeting vulnerable teen and preteen girls.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/afp-developing-ai-tool-to-decode-gen-z-and-alpha-slang-amid-warning-about-crimefluencers"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/afp-developing-ai-tool-to-decode-gen-z-and-alpha-slang-amid-warning-about-crimefluencers</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:28:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US Senate passes bill with Republican support to rescind Trump’s tariffs on Brazil</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans break ranks as vote passes 52-48 in rare bipartisan rebuke of US president’s trade policies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US Senate on Tuesday approved a measure that would terminate Donald Trump’s sweeping tariffs on Brazilian imports, including coffee, beef and other products, in a rare bipartisan show of opposition to the president’s trade war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation passed in a 52-48 vote, with five Republicans – senators Lisa Murkowski of Alaska, Susan Collins of Maine, Rand Paul of Kentucky, Thom Tillis of North Carolina and the former Republican leader Mitch McConnell of Kentucky – joining all Democrats in favor. The vote took place on &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/government-shutdown-senate-vote-fails"&gt;day 28&lt;/a&gt; of the federal government shutdown with both sides at loggerheads over spending legislation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:25:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Database backups, dump files and restic</title><link>https://strugglers.net/posts/2025/database-backups-dump-files-and-restic/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741050"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://strugglers.net/posts/2025/database-backups-dump-files-and-restic/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:13:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC journalist barred from leaving Vietnam and repeatedly interrogated</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BBC ‘deeply concerned’ for journalist’s wellbeing after Vietnamese police withhold their ID card and renewed passport&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese authorities have barred a BBC journalist from leaving the country and ​subjected them to days of interrogation, in a press freedom case that comes to light during a high-profile visit by Vietnam’s leader to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journalist, a Vietnamese citizen who lives and works in Thailand, had returned to their home country in August to renew their passport, according a source with knowledge of the situation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s super-rich are running down the planet’s safe climate spaces, says Oxfam</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Data shows wealthiest 0.1% of the US burn carbon at 4,000 times the rate of the world’s poorest 10%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US’s super-rich are burning through carbon emissions at 4,000 times the speed of the world’s poorest 10%, according to an analysis provided to the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These billionaires and multimillionaires, who comprise the wealthiest 0.1% of the US population, are also running down our planet’s safe climate space at 183 times the rate of the global average.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NHS makes morning-after pill available for free across pharmacies in England</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Those in need of free emergency contraception no longer have to see their GP or attend a sexual health clinic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NHS has made the morning-after pill available for free across pharmacies in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/england"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to reduce a “postcode lottery” of access to emergency contraception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost 10,000 pharmacies are now able to offer the pill without charge, saving those in need of free emergency contraception from having to visit their GP or to get an appointment at a sexual health clinic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 64 killed in Rio's largest police raid on gangs</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8x155engwpo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Fierce clashes erupted in the Brazilian city, with the Red Command gang dropping bombs with drones.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8x155engwpo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:35:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Trump and Xi Strike a Deal?</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/trump-xi-china-meeting-trade-tariffs-south-korea/</link><description>Both sides are sending positive signals ahead of a Thursday meeting, but a temporary truce may be more likely.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/trump-xi-china-meeting-trade-tariffs-south-korea/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:11:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>'No Trump! No China!': Caught in the middle, South Korea hosts rival superpowers</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy7eyg0808xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>South Korea's President Lee is in for a diplomatic dance as he hosts the leaders of US and China.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy7eyg0808xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:10:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Five more prisoners freed in error after sex offender’s release from Essex jail</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Union says staff shortages and confusion over early release schemes are driving a rise in mistakes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five other prisoners have also been released by mistake in the same week a convicted Ethiopian sex offender was allowed to walk free from an Essex jail, says the prison officers’ union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The disclosure of further mistakes highlights the intense pressure on prison staff, according to the Prison Officers’ Association (POA).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:09:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Irish man killed in first Australian mine explosion in a decade</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy71xkxr1do?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Ambrose McMullen, who was known as Ambie, from Cootehill, in County Cavan, is understood to have been killed at the Endeavor mine at Cobar.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cwy71xkxr1do?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:04:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Georgian Dream Demands Ban On Three Largest Opposition Parties</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/georgia-opposition-parties-papuashvili-ban-constitutional-court/33573960.html</link><description>Georgia's ruling party will ask the Constitutional Court to outlaw the three largest opposition parties, which are all strongly pro-Western, a senior member of the ruling Georgian Dream party said on October 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/georgia-opposition-parties-papuashvili-ban-constitutional-court/33573960.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:03:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Quelling public disquiet is worth extra cost of barracks asylum housing, says No 10</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/28/quelling-public-disquiet-hotels-worth-extra-cost-housing-refugees-barracks-says-government</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Government defends prospect of paying more for barracks, saying people ‘don’t want asylum seekers in hotels’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Downing Street has defended the prospect of paying more to house asylum seekers in disused barracks instead of hotels, arguing that quelling public disquiet was worth any extra cost.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As refugee organisations and local politicians described plans to house tens of thousands of people in ex-military sites as “fanciful” and “too expensive”, No 10 said that “communities don’t want asylum seekers housed in hotels, and neither does the government”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/28/quelling-public-disquiet-hotels-worth-extra-cost-housing-refugees-barracks-says-government"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/28/quelling-public-disquiet-hotels-worth-extra-cost-housing-refugees-barracks-says-government</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:02:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Keeping the Internet fast and secure: introducing Merkle Tree Certificates</title><link>https://blog.cloudflare.com/bootstrap-mtc/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45740214"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.cloudflare.com/bootstrap-mtc/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:39:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC 'deeply concerned' about journalist unable to leave Vietnam</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg70064d2vo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The journalist has been in Vietnam for several months while authorities have withheld their renewed passport.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvg70064d2vo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:27:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>“Utilities bills are rising” Q3 2025 update</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin8a1/utilities_bills_are_rising_q3_2025_update/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good summary of rate case filing outcomes (with links) and ways consumers can influence those outcomes&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The “cost of service” model is broken and has not been an effective mechanism for maintaining grid infrastructure for quite some time. IMO it behooves us all to become more familiar with the process, so that attention is steered toward the appropriate direction&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/jjllgg22"&gt; /u/jjllgg22 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://powerlines.org/wp-content/uploads/2025/10/1026_PowerLines_Rising-Utility-Bills-Q3-Update-2.pdf"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin8a1/utilities_bills_are_rising_q3_2025_update/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin8a1/utilities_bills_are_rising_q3_2025_update/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:14:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia’s Lukoil to sell off foreign assets as US sanctions bite</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin4as/russias_lukoil_to_sell_off_foreign_assets_as_us/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin4as/russias_lukoil_to_sell_off_foreign_assets_as_us/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Russia’s Lukoil to sell off foreign assets as US sanctions bite" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/wqYvFD0M1LcllQvojMX3ccXmbmLv7oCQgW3Jp06CNWM.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=10d97fc4b0e181ac18a9865e9164320d9a48f7be" title="Russia’s Lukoil to sell off foreign assets as US sanctions bite" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/AlertTangerine"&gt; /u/AlertTangerine &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.politico.eu/article/russia-lukoil-gas-energy-trade-kremlin-war-ukraine-donald-trump/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin4as/russias_lukoil_to_sell_off_foreign_assets_as_us/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oin4as/russias_lukoil_to_sell_off_foreign_assets_as_us/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:10:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. Government Shutdown Sorely Tests National Security State</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/us-government-shutdown-impacts-national-security-diplomacy-defense-troops/</link><description>One month into federal funding shortfall, U.S. defense and diplomacy resources are being stretched.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/us-government-shutdown-impacts-national-security-diplomacy-defense-troops/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 22:04:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Air traffic controllers receive $0 paychecks as government shutdown stretches</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/air-traffic-controllers-pay-government-shutdown</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 11,000 air traffic controllers, deemed essential workers, did not receive wages for two weeks of work&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Air traffic controllers and Transportation Security Administration employees have missed their first paycheck as the federal government shutdown rolls through its fourth week. They remain required to work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/28/us/politics/shutdown-air-traffic-controllers-duffy.html"&gt;Nearly 11,000 air traffic controllers&lt;/a&gt;, who are deemed essential workers, received a $0 paycheck on Tuesday, equating to two weeks of unpaid work. Sean Duffy, the transportation secretary, warned at a Tuesday press conference that another missed paycheck could be financially catastrophic for employees.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/air-traffic-controllers-pay-government-shutdown"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/air-traffic-controllers-pay-government-shutdown</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Potentially diseased lab monkey on the loose after truck crash in Mississippi</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/lab-monkey-escape-mississippi</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Several rhesus monkeys escaped after the interstate crash, but all but one were reportedly ‘destroyed’ by late Tuesday&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A group of potentially diseased lab monkeys escaped after a vehicle crash on a main interstate highway in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/mississippi"&gt;Mississippi&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A truck carrying rhesus monkeys was involved in a wreck on Interstate 59 on Tuesday afternoon, according to a &lt;a href="https://www.facebook.com/story.php?story_fbid=1270453581790302&amp;amp;id=100064770154293&amp;amp;mibextid=wwXIfr&amp;amp;rdid=oL7qL1IFGxk5Hvo6"&gt;Facebook post&lt;/a&gt; from the Jasper county sheriff’s department.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/lab-monkey-escape-mississippi"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/lab-monkey-escape-mississippi</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:47:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. Gunboat Diplomacy Will Only Embolden China</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/us-trump-boat-strikes-caribbean-china-pacific-law/</link><description>Trump’s aggression in Latin America has given a powerful boost to Beijing in the Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/us-trump-boat-strikes-caribbean-china-pacific-law/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:41:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tinkering is a way to acquire good taste</title><link>https://seated.ro/blog/tinkering-a-lost-art</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45739499"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://seated.ro/blog/tinkering-a-lost-art</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:31:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Man deported to Laos despite US court order blocking his removal, attorneys say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/ice-deportation-alabama-laos</link><description>&lt;p&gt;District judge told Ice to keep Alabama man in US while he showed what judge called ‘substantial claim’ to citizenship&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Immigration officials have deported a father living in Alabama to Laos despite a federal court order blocking his removal from the US on the grounds he has a claim to citizenship, the man’s attorneys said on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US district judge Shelly Dick last week ordered US Immigration and Customs Enforcement to keep Chanthila “Shawn” Souvannarath, 44, in the United States while he presented what the judge called his “substantial claim of US citizenship”, court records show. He was born in a refugee camp in Thailand but was granted lawful permanent residence in the US before his first birthday, according to court filings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/ice-deportation-alabama-laos"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/ice-deportation-alabama-laos</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 21:31:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US military kills 14 in attacks on vessels in the Pacific, according to Hegseth</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/latest-boat-strikes-caribbean-hegseth-trump</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US says one person survived latest strikes, having killed 51 people in attacks on at least 13 vessels in recent weeks&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US military killed 14 people and left one survivor in more strikes on alleged drug-trafficking boats in the eastern Pacific, the defense secretary, Pete Hegseth, said on Monday, as the Trump administration continued to expand its campaign beyond the Caribbean.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The latest strikes mean the US has now attacked at least 13 vessels and brought the officially acknowledged death toll to 51 people since the campaign began at the start of September.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/latest-boat-strikes-caribbean-hegseth-trump"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/latest-boat-strikes-caribbean-hegseth-trump</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:59:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Generative AI Image Editing Showdown</title><link>https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45739080"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://genai-showdown.specr.net/image-editing</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:58:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Fourth Intelligence Revolution: The Future of Espionage and the Battle to Save America</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/28/the-fourth-intelligence-revolution-the-future-of-espionage-and-the-battle-to-save-america/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Intelligence Revolution: The Future of Espionage and the Battle to Save America In The Fourth Intelligence Revolution: The Future of Espionage and the Battle to Save America, author Anthony Vinci explores how advances in artificial intelligence (AI) and U.S.-China competition are transforming global espionage, with implications for us all. Vinci’s eye-opening new book traces the evolution of espionage &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/28/the-fourth-intelligence-revolution-the-future-of-espionage-and-the-battle-to-save-america/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/28/the-fourth-intelligence-revolution-the-future-of-espionage-and-the-battle-to-save-america/"&gt;The Fourth Intelligence Revolution: The Future of Espionage and the Battle to Save America&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/28/the-fourth-intelligence-revolution-the-future-of-espionage-and-the-battle-to-save-america/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:41:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China vs. the U.S.: Who Will Win Over ASEAN?</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/china-asean-free-trade-deal-trump-tariffs-xi-apec/</link><description>Beijing is hoping to use an expanded free trade deal to portray itself as the bloc’s alternative to the United States.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/china-asean-free-trade-deal-trump-tariffs-xi-apec/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:40:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Strong winds and flying debris as Hurricane Melissa makes landfall</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cp8yz2jgk0go?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Storm surges of 13 feet (3.9m) above ground level and destructive waves are expected as the storm hits Jamaica.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/cp8yz2jgk0go?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:18:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Your Party to launch legal action against three of its ‘rogue’ founders, sources say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/28/your-party-to-launch-legal-action-against-three-of-its-founders-sources-say</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Leftwing party seeks to recover donations and data from company run by Andrew Feinstein, Jamie Driscoll and Beth Winter&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your Party, the leftwing party steered by Jeremy Corbyn and Zarah Sultana, says it is preparing legal action against a group of its own founders after a final deadline to hand over at least £800,000 in donations passed without payment, the Guardian understands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Figures close to the party accused directors of MoU Operations Ltd (MoU) of having “gone rogue”, holding supporters’ funds to ransom and undermining its founding process “despite direct pleas from Jeremy and Zarah”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/28/your-party-to-launch-legal-action-against-three-of-its-founders-sources-say"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/28/your-party-to-launch-legal-action-against-three-of-its-founders-sources-say</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 20:16:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Boring is what we wanted</title><link>https://512pixels.net/2025/10/boring-is-what-we-wanted/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45738247"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://512pixels.net/2025/10/boring-is-what-we-wanted/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 19:57:16 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>