<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 07:01:10 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>How is wood charcoal prepared?</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oixj07/how_is_wood_charcoal_prepared/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oixj07/how_is_wood_charcoal_prepared/"&gt; &lt;img alt="How is wood charcoal prepared?" src="https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/-gIAgaq3BzfPhrWfHamogR5QDun6429yim2YmuB4T8M.jpg" title="How is wood charcoal prepared?" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Wood charcoal preparation is the process of converting wood into a highly efficient fuel through appropriate methods. Traditionally, wood was carbonized in earthen kilns or pits, an inefficient and environmentally harmful process. Modern charcoal production combines traditional knowledge with modern technology to ensure wood charcoal quality while prioritizing environmental protection and resource utilization, providing a faster, cleaner, and more efficient solution. Here's how it works:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Basic Principles of Wood Charcoal Preparation&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;The core principle of wood charcoal preparation is high-temperature pyrolysis. In this process, wood or biomass is heated in an oxygen-deficient environment, gradually breaking down volatile compounds and leaving behind a carbon-rich solid residue known as charcoal. This method helps retain the energy density of wood while reducing smoke production, resulting in a cleaner burn and higher calorific value than raw wood.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.redd.it/irf5ehitwzxf1.jpg?width=700&amp;amp;format=pjpg&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=42491578b6ee90b8c307d0cd730229b9062ed664"&gt;Basic principles of wood charcoal preparation: biomass pyrolysis&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;h1&gt;Key Steps in Wood Charcoal Preparation&lt;/h1&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Raw Material Selection and Preparation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The first step in wood charcoal preparation is selecting the right raw material. Hardwoods, such as oak, beech, or walnut, are widely used due to their high density and carbon content. Other biomass raw materials can also be used for charcoal preparation: such as bamboo, wood chips, sawdust, fallen leaves and other forest waste, coconut shells, palm kernel shells, nut shells and other agricultural waste. Before carbonization, the wood undergoes pre-treatment, such as crushing and drying, to remove excess moisture and uniformize the wood size for easier handling.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Carbonization Process&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Charcoalization is a critical step in wood charcoal preparation. Dried wood is fed into a carbonization furnace or reactor, where it undergoes pyrolysis under oxygen-deficient (oxygen-limited) and high-temperature conditions. The temperature is typically controlled within a specific range, with the wood typically heated to high temperatures (400-600°C) to ensure the decomposition of organic matter while avoiding over-combustion. This thermal decomposition drives off volatile substances and gases, leaving behind solid charcoal and producing recyclable by-products such as wood vinegar and wood tar.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.redd.it/vqy1fv5ywzxf1.jpg?width=700&amp;amp;format=pjpg&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=5f748055534713eeed5ba6573805ff8b2c36ccc4"&gt;Carbonization process for wood charcoal preparation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Cooling and Collection&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;After carbonization, the resulting wood charcoal is typically extremely hot and requires forced cooling to reduce its temperature, prevent spontaneous combustion upon contact with air, and maintain the quality and structure of the charcoal. The cooled wood charcoal is collected and screened to remove debris and incompletely carbonized portions, ensuring the quality of the final product. The final charcoal product is packaged according to its intended use (barbecue, industrial, agricultural, or as activated carbon) and stored in a dry environment to prevent moisture absorption and compromise its combustion properties.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Charcoal Pressing (Optional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Products with specialized wood charcoal shape requirements can press the resulting charcoal powder into shapes. Common charcoal forms include bars, blocks, and pellets. After mixing the prepared charcoal with a binder, a charcoal press briquetting machine uses mechanical pressure to press the charcoal powder into the desired shape, improving its density, hardness, and uniform appearance. This process not only improves the charcoal's physical properties but also enables precise mold control to produce a variety of charcoal forms that meet market demands.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.redd.it/fas6o4bzwzxf1.jpg?width=700&amp;amp;format=pjpg&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=0c7f9c3d199d9f357f61f19b8e128c85c727d1e7"&gt;Charcoal press briquetting machine for different charcoal shapes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Through the above charcoal preparation process, we can obtain high quality charcoal for sale or other wide applications, such as metallurgy, barbecue fuel, soil improvement and activated carbon production. With technological advancements and increasing environmental protection requirements, modern charcoal preparation methods prioritize efficiency and environmental friendliness. Professional &lt;a href="http://www.bestpyrolysisplant.com/Product/carbonization_machine/biomass_carbonization_machine_412.html"&gt;carbonization machine&lt;/a&gt; allows for better control of carbonization temperature, time, and an oxygen-free environment, thereby increasing charcoal yields. Furthermore, byproducts can be recycled, achieving a resource-efficient process.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.redd.it/hknwqly0xzxf1.jpg?width=700&amp;amp;format=pjpg&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=255ce98f623917ac304d790052cba8a46c3c843e"&gt;Modern charcoal preparation methods and steps&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Modern charcoal-making machines are equipped with fume purification systems that process and recycle generated gases, converting them into heat for reuse and reducing pollutant emissions, making the entire process environmentally friendly and energy-efficient.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;As a manufacturer of charcoal making machine, DOING offers a wide range of charcoal production line models to help users optimize their charcoal preparation processes. Our equipment is designed for practicality and stability, making it suitable not only for small- and medium-scale production but also for large-scale charcoal production. If you are interested in &lt;a href="http://englishm.doinggroup.com/products/henan_doing/carbonization_machine"&gt;charcoal preparation machine&lt;/a&gt;, please contact us for more information. We will provide professional advice based on your needs and recommend the most suitable equipment model.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Metalsrecycling"&gt; /u/Metalsrecycling &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oixj07/how_is_wood_charcoal_prepared/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oixj07/how_is_wood_charcoal_prepared/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oixj07/how_is_wood_charcoal_prepared/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:48:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa live updates: category 3 storm nears Cuba; ‘extensive’ damage in parts of Jamaica</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/29/hurricane-melissa-live-updates-strengthens-cuba-extensive-damage-parts-of-jamaica</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reports of families trapped by floodwaters in Jamaica, as hurricane moves on to threaten Cuba’s second-largest city&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica"&gt;Hurricane Melissa makes landfall in Jamaica&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-a-visual-guide-to-the-strongest-storm-to-hit-jamaica-in-almost-two-centuries"&gt;Visual guide to Hurricane Melissa&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2025/oct/27/tell-us-if-youve-been-affected-by-hurricane-melissa"&gt;Tell us if you’ve been affected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As Cuba prepares for the storm to make landfall any minute, officials in Jamaica are preparing to assess the damage on Wednesday.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &lt;a href="https://x.com/JamaicaConstab/status/1983311743616221615"&gt;video&lt;/a&gt; shared by the Jamaican Constabulary Force shows officers surveying extensive destruction in Black River, close to where Hurricane Melissa made landfall on Tuesday as a Category 5 storm.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/29/hurricane-melissa-live-updates-strengthens-cuba-extensive-damage-parts-of-jamaica"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/29/hurricane-melissa-live-updates-strengthens-cuba-extensive-damage-parts-of-jamaica</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:44:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia news live: Sussan Ley had ‘a really strong point to make’ on Joy Division T-shirt, Melissa McIntosh says</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Follow updates live&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/29/australia-inflation-rate-cpi-consumer-price-index-figure-rba-reserve-bank"&gt;Inflation jumps to 3.2%, dashing hopes of a Melbourne Cup day rate cut for homeowners&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Coalition is still in the middle of a fight over the future of its energy policy, with big fractures between members over whether the 2050 net zero target should be kept.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The party is working towards something of a compromise, but there are a few moderates who don’t want that target to change – including shadow housing minister &lt;strong&gt;Andrew Bragg&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look, I think we’ll get there on net zero. I know there’s a lot of interest in it. I think ultimately there’s an ability there for the Coalition to do this much better than Labor. Labor’s net zero [policy] has been a disaster …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I think we could do net zero better than Labor in terms of emissions and cost and environmental protection, &lt;strong&gt;but you’ve got to keep net zero&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;I know that you probably find it all very interesting to talk about, but we do have a culture of openness in the Liberal party and the National party, and we seem to talk about a lot of things. I mean, frankly, &lt;strong&gt;I wonder what the nation will talk about if the Liberal party died, because I think we’d sort of run out of things to discuss.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Communities around the country are trying to focus and talk about the issues that matter to them, not try to make some fake news thing out of a T-shirt the prime minister gets wearing off a plane. It’s ridiculous.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Look, there’s a lot to legitimately criticise the prime minister about trillion dollar debt, skyrocketing house prices and job losses in our heavy industrial sector wearing a T-shirt is not one of them … So yeah, get on with acting on antisemitism.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:31:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Voting opens in Netherlands as polls suggest second Gert Wilders win</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/voting-opens-in-netherlands-as-polls-suggest-second-gert-wilders-win</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Major parties rule out coalition with rightwinger, giving his party little chance of being part of government&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Voting is under way in parliamentary elections in the Netherlands that polls suggest could again be won by the anti-immigration firebrand Geert Wilders’s Freedom party (PVV), although there is little chance of it being part of the next government.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The PVV, which &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/22/far-right-party-set-to-win-most-seats-in-dutch-elections-exit-polls-show"&gt;finished a shock first&lt;/a&gt; in the previous election and formed a four-party all-conservative coalition that lasted barely a year before collapsing, is &lt;a href="https://peilingwijzer.tomlouwerse.nl/"&gt;marginally ahead in the polls&lt;/a&gt; and forecast to return between 24 and 28 MPs to the 150-seat parliament.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/voting-opens-in-netherlands-as-polls-suggest-second-gert-wilders-win"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/voting-opens-in-netherlands-as-polls-suggest-second-gert-wilders-win</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:30:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hadush Kebatu, Epping sex offender, deported to Ethiopia, Home Office confirms</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/29/hadush-kebatu-epping-sex-offender-deported-to-ethiopia</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Home Office said Kebatu, who was wrongly freed from prison on Friday, was put on a flight to Ethiopia on Tuesday night and arrived on Wednesday &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hadush Kebatu has arrived in Ethiopia after being deported from the UK with no right to return, the Home Office has confirmed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian national was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/26/epping-sex-offender-back-in-custody-after-being-released-from-prison-in-error"&gt;wrongly freed from HMP Chelmsford &lt;/a&gt;on Friday morning instead of being sent to an immigration detention centre.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/29/hadush-kebatu-epping-sex-offender-deported-to-ethiopia"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/29/hadush-kebatu-epping-sex-offender-deported-to-ethiopia</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:22:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump lands in South Korea amid deadlocked trade talks over $350bn deal on tariffs</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US president to be presented with replica royal gold crown before meeting his South Korean counterpart, Lee Jae Myung, but expectations of a breakthrough on tariffs are low&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump landed in South Korea on Wednesday to meet President Lee Jae Myung, with deadlocked talks over a $350bn trade deal between the two countries threatening to cast a shadow over the event.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After arriving on a flight from Tokyo, where he &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/donald-trump-sanae-takaichi-japan-prime-minister-rare-earths-agreement"&gt;signed a rare earths deal with Japan’s new prime minister&lt;/a&gt;, Sanae Takaichi, the US president addressed a summit of CEOs ahead of a meeting with Lee in the town of Gyeongju, a historical city playing host to the annual Apec summit.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/trump-heads-to-south-korea-amid-deadlocked-trade-talks-over-350bn-deal-on-tariffs</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:06:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Setting The Force: 10 Steps for Resolving The Special Forces “Identity Crisis”</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/29/solving-special-forces-identity-crisis/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If Special Forces has an “identity crisis,” it is because we misunderstood and mislabeled the problems we were sent to resolve, and applied solutions rooted in how the problems were labeled and defined, rather than for what they were. The world had changed, and revisionist actors of every ilk had stolen a march on those overly wedded to an obsolete &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/29/solving-special-forces-identity-crisis/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/29/solving-special-forces-identity-crisis/"&gt;Setting The Force: 10 Steps for Resolving The Special Forces &amp;#8220;Identity Crisis&amp;#8221;&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/29/solving-special-forces-identity-crisis/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 06:00:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Israeli strikes kill 33 in Gaza, Hamas-run civil defence says, as Trump insists ceasefire remains</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgjdy5eevn2o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Israel and Hamas both accused each other of breaking the US-brokered ceasefire.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgjdy5eevn2o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:58:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tight race in Dutch election as anti-Islam populist Wilders' hope of power declines</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20p6z2j5dro?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Wilders was the clear winner last time Dutch voters went to the polls in November 2023, but this time the race is far tighter.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c20p6z2j5dro?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:58:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Storm in a teacup or dark clouds: why do people hate the BoM website redesign?</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/why-people-hate-bom-website-redesign</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Meteorology is on the back foot after its new website launched to a flurry of online – and political – anger&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Meteorology has been ordered to make changes to its new website after facing criticism from farmers and politicians over missing or hard-to-find features on the new-look site.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is it a ticking timebomb or all a storm in a teacup?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/why-people-hate-bom-website-redesign"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/why-people-hate-bom-website-redesign</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:56:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Victorian Labor forced to rely on One Nation and others to pass voluntary assisted dying bill after factional split</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/victorian-labor-forced-to-rely-on-one-nation-and-others-to-pass-voluntary-assisted-dying-bill-after-factional-split</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusive:&lt;/strong&gt; Reforms expected to pass parliament with support of motley crew of MPS after Labor’s SDA sub-faction attempts to curtail them&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Victorian government will be forced to rely on a motley crew of MPs including One Nation and the Liberals to pass its voluntary assisted dying laws after a group of Labor MPs railed against the legislation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The development comes as the lower house on Wednesday continued to debate amendments to the state’s laws that would allow &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/feb/20/victoria-scraps-gag-clause-banning-doctors-from-raising-voluntary-assisted-dying-with-patients"&gt;doctors to initiate conversations &lt;/a&gt;about voluntary assisted dying and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/15/her-death-was-tranquil-why-eve-is-urging-victorian-mps-to-make-access-to-voluntary-assisted-dying-easier"&gt;expand the eligibility timeframe&lt;/a&gt; for all terminal illnesses to 12 months, with MPs from both Labor and the Coalition granted a conscience vote.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/victorian-labor-forced-to-rely-on-one-nation-and-others-to-pass-voluntary-assisted-dying-bill-after-factional-split"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/victorian-labor-forced-to-rely-on-one-nation-and-others-to-pass-voluntary-assisted-dying-bill-after-factional-split</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:34:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Storm of the century’: record-breaking Hurricane Melissa hits Jamaica and heads for Cuba</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Minister says parish of St Elizabeth is ‘under water’ and that families are trapped in their homes in the community of Black River in western Jamaica&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/29/hurricane-melissa-live-updates-strengthens-cuba-extensive-damage-parts-of-jamaica"&gt;Hurricane Melissa – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-a-visual-guide-to-the-strongest-storm-to-hit-jamaica-in-almost-two-centuries"&gt;A visual guide to Jamaica’s strongest storm since 1851&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2025/oct/27/tell-us-if-youve-been-affected-by-hurricane-melissa"&gt;Tell us if you’ve been affected&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Melissa is heading for Cuba after it made landfall as a category 5 storm in Jamaica, battering the country with ferocious winds, heavy flood waters and landslides as one of the strongest Atlantic hurricanes in history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cuba’s president warned the country was in for a “very difficult night” as the category 4 storm headed for the island’s second-largest city, Santiago de Cuba.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/hurricane-melissa-makes-landfall-in-jamaica</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:27:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Who needs Graphviz when you can build it yourself?</title><link>https://spidermonkey.dev/blog/2025/10/28/iongraph-web.html</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742907"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://spidermonkey.dev/blog/2025/10/28/iongraph-web.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:17:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Director of Bataclan terror attack drama rejects accusations of ‘indecency’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/paris-bataclan-terror-attack-drama-director-rejects-accusations-of-indecency</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jean-Xavier de Lestrade defends decision to film mini-series inside Paris theatre where 130 people died in 2016&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Oscar-winning director of a TV mini-series about survivors of the 2015 terrorist attack at the Bataclan in Paris has rejected accusations his decision to film inside the theatre was “indecent”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jean-Xavier de Lestrade said the hostages on whose story the eight-part docudrama was based wanted their terrifying ordeal recreated inside the building and to film it elsewhere would have been “trickery”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/paris-bataclan-terror-attack-drama-director-rejects-accusations-of-indecency"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/paris-bataclan-terror-attack-drama-director-rejects-accusations-of-indecency</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:00:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Boris Johnson approved China’s London super-embassy proposal in 2018</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/29/boris-johnson-approved-chinas-super-embassy-proposal-in-2018</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Former PM gave consent while foreign secretary for Royal Mint Court complex, a project still in limbo seven years later&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boris Johnson approved the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/04/china-mega-embassy-dilemma-starmer"&gt;China’s super-embassy proposal&lt;/a&gt; in 2018 and welcomed the fact it would represent “China’s largest overseas diplomatic investment” anywhere in the world, the Guardian can disclose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a letter to Wang Yi, China’s top diplomat, Johnson gave his consent for Royal Mint Court to house a sprawling diplomatic complex in May 2018. The Chinese government bought the 20,000 sq metres site for £255m that same month.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/29/boris-johnson-approved-chinas-super-embassy-proposal-in-2018"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/29/boris-johnson-approved-chinas-super-embassy-proposal-in-2018</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:00:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump and Xi talks could end months of global economic chaos</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-xi-talks-rare-earths-tariffs-us-china</link><description>&lt;p&gt;High on agenda for the leaders of the US and China will be rare earths and tariffs, with a chance of a relationship reset&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ahead of Thursday’s long-awaited first &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/trump-and-xi-talks-what-will-be-on-the-agenda-when-us-president-meets-chinas-leader"&gt;meeting&lt;/a&gt; between Donald Trump and Xi Jinping since the US president’s return to office, officials from both sides have been hammering out the contours of what a trade deal between Washington and Beijing might look like, an agreement that could bring an end to months of global economic chaos caused by the US-China trade war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two leaders have not met in person since 2019. Since then, the war in Ukraine and increasing concern in Washington about China’s technological advances, as well as longstanding issues about the imbalanced US-China trade relationship, have strained the bonds between the two superpowers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-xi-talks-rare-earths-tariffs-us-china"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-xi-talks-rare-earths-tariffs-us-china</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ASEAN’s Mixed Feelings About U.S.-China Detente</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/29/asean-summit-us-china-trade-talks/</link><description>What if China ends up with a better deal than Southeast Asia?</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/29/asean-summit-us-china-trade-talks/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 05:00:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Merz, Erdogan und die neue Realpolitik</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/podcast/berlin-playbook-podcast/merz-erdogan-und-die-neue-realpolitik/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</link><description>Friedrich Merz reist als Kanzler in die Türkei. Es wird ein Besuch zwischen Realpolitik und Risiko. In Ankara trifft er Recep Tayyip Erdoğan, um über Sicherheit und Migration zu sprechen. Ein Gespräch, das Kooperation und Konflikt zugleich bedeutet; über Waffenlieferungen, Rechtsstaat und das Verhältnis zu Russland. Die Analyse dazu von Gordon Repinski. Im 200-Sekunden-Interview spricht [&amp;#8230;]</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.politico.eu/podcast/berlin-playbook-podcast/merz-erdogan-und-die-neue-realpolitik/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:42:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wacl – A Tcl Distribution for WebAssembly</title><link>https://github.com/ecky-l/wacl</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742616"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/ecky-l/wacl</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:25:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Allegations of violence, abuse and neglect in Victorian childcares jumped in 2024-25</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/allegations-violence-abuse-neglect-victoria-childcare-rise-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Children’s commission report reveals mandatory reporting in sector up 32% while total across all sectors increased by 18% compared with 2023-2024 &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reports of physical violence and neglect in Victorian childcare centres have surged, with mandatory reports up 32% in the last financial year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Victorian Commission for Children and Young People’s annual report, tabled in state parliament on Wednesday, reveals that there were 705 notifications of reportable allegations in the childcare sector in the 2024-25 financial year, each of which can include multiple alleged acts, an increase of 32% on the previous year’s 534.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/allegations-violence-abuse-neglect-victoria-childcare-rise-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/allegations-violence-abuse-neglect-victoria-childcare-rise-ntwnfb</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:17:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>All operational US liquefied natural gas terminals have violated pollution limits, says report</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/liquefied-natural-gas-terminal-pollution-limits</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Analysis of public records comes as Trump administration aims to fast-track approval of new LNG export terminals&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every fully operational liquefied natural gas (LNG) terminal in the US has violated federal pollution limits in recent years, a new report has found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The analysis of public records comes as the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; is aiming to fast-track the approval of new export terminals in an attempt to sell more domestic LNG to Europe and Asia. &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/joebiden"&gt;Joe Biden&lt;/a&gt; had previously placed a pause on LNG exports, which &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; lifted on the first day of his return to office.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/liquefied-natural-gas-terminal-pollution-limits"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/liquefied-natural-gas-terminal-pollution-limits</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:05:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Keep Android Open</title><link>http://keepandroidopen.org/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742488"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">http://keepandroidopen.org/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:03:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Military-Narrational Complex</title><link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/military-narrational-complex</link><description>What stories do in an age of conflict.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foreignaffairs.com/military-narrational-complex</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Structure Trumps Agency in the U.S.-China Relationship</title><link>https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/structure-trumps-agency-us-china-relationship</link><description>Why the competition is here to stay.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.foreignaffairs.com/united-states/structure-trumps-agency-us-china-relationship</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 04:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Bureau of Meteorology apologises for new website and promises changes after ‘flawed’ update</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/bureau-of-meteorology-bom-website-new-redesign-queensland-premier-criticism</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BoM’s statement comes after federal environment minister says site refresh ‘not meeting many users’ expectations’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/29/federal-politics-parliament-victoria-queensland-bom-labor-coalition-anthony-albanese-sussan-ley-abs-inflation-apec-summit-afp-press-club-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Bureau of Meteorology has apologised for unpopular changes to its website and said “adjustments” will be made, after its top brass was hauled in by the environment minister after negative public feedback.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changes to the website’s design and accessibility have been criticised by many users online, with minister Murray Watt saying the website was “not meeting many users’ expectations” and the federal opposition saying it had affected the ability of Queenslanders to prepare for recent rain events.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/bureau-of-meteorology-bom-website-new-redesign-queensland-premier-criticism"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/29/bureau-of-meteorology-bom-website-new-redesign-queensland-premier-criticism</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:59:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Too bad I can’t run, but we’ll see what happens, says Trump on unconstitutional third term</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-third-term-president-2028</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump says he has read about constitutional two-term limit preventing him from running for president in 2028 and it was ‘pretty clear’, but that he ‘would love to do it’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump said “it’s too bad” he is not allowed to run for a third term, conceding the constitutional reality even as he expressed interest in continuing to serve.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“If you read it, it’s pretty clear,” Trump told reporters on board Air Force One from Japan to South Korea on Wednesday. “I’m not allowed to run. It’s too bad.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-third-term-president-2028"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/29/trump-third-term-president-2028</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:58:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>uBlock Origin Lite Apple App Store</title><link>https://apps.apple.com/in/app/ublock-origin-lite/id6745342698</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742446"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://apps.apple.com/in/app/ublock-origin-lite/id6745342698</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:57:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tips for stroke-surviving software engineers</title><link>https://blog.j11y.io/2025-10-29_stroke_tips_for_engineers/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45742419"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.j11y.io/2025-10-29_stroke_tips_for_engineers/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:51:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ben &amp; Jerry's co-founder says Unilever blocked Palestine-themed ice cream</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1lqeqv9j9no?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Ben Cohen says he will independently create the new watermelon flavour in support of "permanent peace in Palestine".</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c1lqeqv9j9no?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:49:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pakistan Says Peace Talks With Afghan Taliban Fail To Find 'Workable Solution'</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-negotiations-clashes-border/33575282.html</link><description>Negotiations for a lasting truce between Afghanistan and Pakistan have broken down, Pakistani Information Minister Attaullah Tarar said on October 29 after four days of negotiations brokered by Qatar and Turkey.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-negotiations-clashes-border/33575282.html</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:14:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tanzanian president poised to retain power as rivals barred from election</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Government critics abducted, killed or arrested in run-up to vote as Samia Suluhu Hassan faces first electoral test&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tanzania’s president looks on course to strengthen her grip on the country as it holds a general election on Wednesday against the backdrop of rapidly intensifying repression and the exclusion of opposition candidates.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Samia Suluhu Hassan, a former vice-president who took office after the death of her predecessor, John Magufuli, in 2021, has left nothing to chance for her first presidential and parliamentary electoral test.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/tanzania-election-president-samia-suluhu-hassan-poised-to-retain-power</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:00:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>South Korea is less interested in its European allies</title><link>https://www.politico.eu/article/south-korea-less-interested-european-allies/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</link><description>As Seoul concentrates on greeting relations with the U.S. on surer footing, it seems it has little time for the bloc or NATO.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.politico.eu/article/south-korea-less-interested-european-allies/?utm_source=RSS_Feed&amp;utm_medium=RSS&amp;utm_campaign=RSS_Syndication</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 03:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. crude inventories expected to fall by 0.2M barrels. API data indicated larger drops: crude -4.02M, gasoline -6.35M, distillate -4.36M barrels. Refinery utilization up 0.2%</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;A poll released Tuesday indicated that U.S. crude oil stockpiles were expected to decline last week, along with inventories of gasoline and distillates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The poll of eight analysts, conducted before the release of weekly inventory data, projected an average decrease of approximately 200,000 barrels in crude inventories for the week ending October 24.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For the week ending October 17, the U.S. Energy Information Administration (EIA) reported that crude inventories fell by 961,000 barrels to 422.8 million barrels. This contrasted with analysts’ expectations from a prior Reuters poll, which had anticipated a 1.2-million-barrel increase.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The poll also estimated that distillate inventories, including diesel and heating oil, fell by about 1.7 million barrels last week. Gasoline stockpiles were projected to have decreased by roughly 1.9 million barrels. The refinery utilization rate was estimated to have risen by 0.2 percentage points from the previous week’s 88.6% of total capacity.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Market sources, citing figures from the American Petroleum Institute (API) on Tuesday, said that U.S. crude, gasoline, and distillate stocks all experienced declines last week. According to these anonymous sources, crude stocks decreased by 4.02 million barrels in the week ending October 24. Gasoline inventories dropped by 6.35 million barrels, while distillate inventories fell by 4.36 million barrels compared to the previous week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The Reuters poll was conducted in anticipation of the weekly API report and the EIA report, the statistical branch of the U.S. Department of Energy, which is scheduled for release at Wed. All stock figures are given in millions of barrels, and refinery rate changes are measured in percentage points.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://starfeu.com"&gt;starfeu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/StarFEU-Commodity"&gt; /u/StarFEU-Commodity &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oith83/us_crude_inventories_expected_to_fall_by_02m/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:52:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Validating a Predictive Recruitment Framework for U.S. Critical Sectors</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hello everyone,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’ve developed a new data-driven recruitment framework for critical U.S. sectors such as Energy, Security, Cybersecurity and Infrastructure that has achieved remarkable results so far:&lt;/p&gt; &lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;• 0% turnover within the first 12 months • Process time reduced from 29 days to 9 • Recruitment costs reduced by 38% • Applied in 371 projects and over 29,000 candidates evaluated &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt; &lt;p&gt;The model essentially eliminates subjectivity in hiring by applying data science principles to both client and candidate assessment. It protects organizations from the financial and operational impact of mis-hires, and it helps professionals make more sustainable career decisions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m now working to launch operations in the U.S., with headquarters planned for Washington, D.C., and two satellite offices in Austin and San Francisco.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;At this stage, my goal is to validate the business model locally and gather letters of intent from executives interested in testing or piloting the framework once operations begin. (This is not a binding contract, simply an expression of future business interest if feasibility is confirmed.)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Given how supportive and experienced this community is, I thought it would be the right place to share the initiative.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;If anyone would like to review the framework details, I’d be happy to share more information by email — and if there’s genuine interest, we can formalize an expression of intent.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Would love to hear your thoughts or perspectives.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Standard_Pangolin913"&gt; /u/Standard_Pangolin913 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oitfka/validating_a_predictive_recruitment_framework_for/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:50:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Israel strikes Gaza after Netanyahu accuses Hamas of breaching ceasefire</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Prime minister accuses Hamas of ‘clear violation’ of truce as far-right ministers clamour to resume war&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israeli warplanes struck Gaza on Tuesday night, shortly after Israel’s prime minister, Benjamin Netanyahu, ordered the military to carry out “powerful strikes” in Gaza, in the most serious test of the increasingly shaky US-brokered ceasefire.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Witnesses reported seeing Israeli planes launch strikes on Gaza City, as well as explosions across the strip shortly after Netanyahu’s announcement. At least seven people were killed in separate strikes in Gaza City and Khan Younis, including two children, medical sources said.&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/28/returned-body-parts-were-of-hostage-recovered-two-years-ago-israel-says</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:38:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Cameroon opposition leader to face legal action over election unrest, government says</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgm37ny34zo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The threat against Issa Tchiroma Bakary comes a day after he was declared the runner-up in disputed presidential polls.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cvgm37ny34zo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 02:34:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Court to reconsider ruling that allowed Trump to send troops to Portland</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops</link><description>&lt;p&gt;President remains barred from deploying national guard as appeals court agrees to ‘en banc’ rehearing of case&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration remains barred from deploying the national guard in Portland, Oregon, following a federal appeals court ruling.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The ninth circuit court of appeals agreed on Tuesday that it would rehear a case over the president’s authority with a broader court of 11 judges. The appeals court also vacated a ruling from a three-judge panel last week that sided with the Trump administration.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-appeals-court-trump-portland-troops</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australian girls being 'hunted' by online crime gangs to commit violent acts</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0qpl7v7p0jo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Groups of young men are coercing and exploiting vulnerable girls "for fun", Australian police say.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c0qpl7v7p0jo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:26:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Border patrol leader told to go to court every weekday to report on Chicago enforcement</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Federal judge gives orders to Gregory Bovino in exceptional bid to impose oversight over Trump officials’ raids in city&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A federal judge has ordered Gregory Bovino, a senior border patrol official leading the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt;’s immigration crackdown in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/chicago"&gt;Chicago&lt;/a&gt;, to appear in federal court each weekday to report on the day’s incidents in an exceptional bid to impose oversight over the government’s militarized raids in the city.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The order came following a terse hearing on Tuesday morning.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/chicago-immigration-crackdown-gregory-bovino</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:26:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wole Soyinka, Nigerian Nobel laureate and Trump critic, says US visa revoked</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Soyinka, 91, who recently compared US president to Idi Amin, says ‘I have no visa – I am banned’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration has revoked the visa for Wole Soyinka, the acclaimed Nigerian Nobel prize-winning writer who has been critical of Trump since his first presidency, Soyinka revealed on Tuesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I want to assure the consulate … that I’m very content with the revocation of my visa,” Soyinka, who won the 1986 Nobel prize for literature, told a news conference.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/books/2025/oct/28/wole-soyinka-nobel-us-visa-trump</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:14:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Project Shadowglass</title><link>https://shadowglassgame.com</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45741391"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://shadowglassgame.com</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 01:06:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US Senate passes bill with Republican support to rescind Trump’s tariffs on Brazil</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republicans break ranks as vote passes 52-48 in rare bipartisan rebuke of US president’s trade policies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US Senate on Tuesday approved a measure that would terminate Donald Trump’s sweeping tariffs on Brazilian imports, including coffee, beef and other products, in a rare bipartisan show of opposition to the president’s trade war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The legislation passed in a 52-48 vote, with five Republicans – senators Lisa Murkowski of Alaska, Susan Collins of Maine, Rand Paul of Kentucky, Thom Tillis of North Carolina and the former Republican leader Mitch McConnell of Kentucky – joining all Democrats in favor. The vote took place on &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/government-shutdown-senate-vote-fails"&gt;day 28&lt;/a&gt; of the federal government shutdown with both sides at loggerheads over spending legislation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/28/us-senate-trump-tariffs-brazil</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:25:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC journalist barred from leaving Vietnam and repeatedly interrogated</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated</link><description>&lt;p&gt;BBC ‘deeply concerned’ for journalist’s wellbeing after Vietnamese police withhold their ID card and renewed passport&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Vietnamese authorities have barred a BBC journalist from leaving the country and ​subjected them to days of interrogation, in a press freedom case that comes to light during a high-profile visit by Vietnam’s leader to the UK.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The journalist, a Vietnamese citizen who lives and works in Thailand, had returned to their home country in August to renew their passport, according a source with knowledge of the situation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/29/bbc-journalist-barred-from-leaving-vietnam-and-repeatedly-interrogated</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>America’s super-rich are running down the planet’s safe climate spaces, says Oxfam</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Data shows wealthiest 0.1% of the US burn carbon at 4,000 times the rate of the world’s poorest 10%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US’s super-rich are burning through carbon emissions at 4,000 times the speed of the world’s poorest 10%, according to an analysis provided to the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;These billionaires and multimillionaires, who comprise the wealthiest 0.1% of the US population, are also running down our planet’s safe climate space at 183 times the rate of the global average.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/29/americas-super-rich-running-down-planet-safe-climate-spaces-oxfam</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>NHS makes morning-after pill available for free across pharmacies in England</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Those in need of free emergency contraception no longer have to see their GP or attend a sexual health clinic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The NHS has made the morning-after pill available for free across pharmacies in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/england"&gt;England&lt;/a&gt; in an effort to reduce a “postcode lottery” of access to emergency contraception.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost 10,000 pharmacies are now able to offer the pill without charge, saving those in need of free emergency contraception from having to visit their GP or to get an appointment at a sexual health clinic.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/29/nhs-makes-morning-after-pill-available-for-free-across-pharmacies-in-england</guid><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:01:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At least 64 killed in Rio's largest police raid on gangs</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8x155engwpo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Fierce clashes erupted in the Brazilian city, with the Red Command gang dropping bombs with drones.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c8x155engwpo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:35:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Can Trump and Xi Strike a Deal?</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/trump-xi-china-meeting-trade-tariffs-south-korea/</link><description>Both sides are sending positive signals ahead of a Thursday meeting, but a temporary truce may be more likely.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/28/trump-xi-china-meeting-trade-tariffs-south-korea/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:11:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>'No Trump! No China!': Caught in the middle, South Korea hosts rival superpowers</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy7eyg0808xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>South Korea's President Lee is in for a diplomatic dance as he hosts the leaders of US and China.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cy7eyg0808xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:10:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Five more prisoners freed in error after sex offender’s release from Essex jail</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Union says staff shortages and confusion over early release schemes are driving a rise in mistakes&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Five other prisoners have also been released by mistake in the same week a convicted Ethiopian sex offender was allowed to walk free from an Essex jail, says the prison officers’ union.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The disclosure of further mistakes highlights the intense pressure on prison staff, according to the Prison Officers’ Association (POA).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/28/five-more-prisoners-freed-in-error-after-sex-offenders-release-from-essex-jail</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:09:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Georgian Dream Demands Ban On Three Largest Opposition Parties</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/georgia-opposition-parties-papuashvili-ban-constitutional-court/33573960.html</link><description>Georgia's ruling party will ask the Constitutional Court to outlaw the three largest opposition parties, which are all strongly pro-Western, a senior member of the ruling Georgian Dream party said on October 28.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/georgia-opposition-parties-papuashvili-ban-constitutional-court/33573960.html</guid><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 23:03:27 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>