<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:20:15 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Sharing a free tool to help dig through multiple PUC portals</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odsm9u/sharing_a_free_tool_to_help_dig_through_multiple/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odsm9u/sharing_a_free_tool_to_help_dig_through_multiple/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Sharing a free tool to help dig through multiple PUC portals" src="https://b.thumbs.redditmedia.com/pmm-aX76E-H8vK_ntzIPipDsgs32ROTuUkXjwz661Us.jpg" title="Sharing a free tool to help dig through multiple PUC portals" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone,&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;I’m currently working with &lt;a href="http://Halcyon.io"&gt;Halcyon.io&lt;/a&gt;, where we’re focused on improving regulatory transparency and data accessibility across the U.S. energy sector.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We recently developed a free tool called Halcyon Search, designed to help utility professionals, consultants, and regulators quickly find and monitor filings and dockets across all 50 state Public Utility Commissions. &lt;strong&gt;For anyone who’s ever had to dig through multiple PUC portals, this tool brings everything into one searchable interface&lt;/strong&gt;. You can use it to track filings on topics like &lt;em&gt;rate cases&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;interconnection&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;queues&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;resource planning&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;distributed energy programs&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;data center load growth&lt;/em&gt;. It also allows you to set custom alerts so you’re notified when new filings mention them across multiple states.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;For example, I’ve used it to trace how “grid modernization” appears in filings across different states and found early draft documents that would’ve taken a significant amount of time to locate manually.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;It’s completely free to use, we’re just looking for feedback on how it could better support the energy community. Feel free to try it here: [&lt;a href="https://app.halcyon.io/workspaces/preview"&gt;Halcyon Search&lt;/a&gt;] and please reach out with any questions or feedback!&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://preview.redd.it/1ih2eurm3swf1.png?width=3416&amp;amp;format=png&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=394709f20a1e946a23eeb938225fec8099934557"&gt;Halcyon Search: grid modernization results&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Specialist-Cream2963"&gt; /u/Specialist-Cream2963 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odsm9u/sharing_a_free_tool_to_help_dig_through_multiple/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odsm9u/sharing_a_free_tool_to_help_dig_through_multiple/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 03:13:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia news live: Andrew Hastie rules out One Nation defection and urges Barnaby Joyce to stick with Coalition</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/23/australia-news-live-pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-one-nation-nationals-weather-wind-damage-melbourne-sydney-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Follow today’s news live&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A five-decade-old cold case of a missing toddler which has attracted international attention and a $1m reward is set to take another turn, Australian Associated Press reports.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Three-year-old &lt;strong&gt;Cheryl Gene Grimmer&lt;/strong&gt; was abducted on 12 January 1970 outside a shower block at Fairy Meadow beach in Wollongong, on the NSW south coast, when she was enjoying a day at the beach with her mother and three brothers.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/23/australia-news-live-pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-one-nation-nationals-weather-wind-damage-melbourne-sydney-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:49:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US military kills five people in strikes on alleged drug-trafficking boats in Pacific</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/military-boat-strike-pacific-pete-hegseth</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Latest strikes were off coast of Colombia, while seven previous attacks in Caribbean killed at least 32&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US military has for the first time attacked and destroyed two boats on the Pacific side of South America, as part of its ongoing and controversial fight against what it says are drug-trafficking activities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The strikes – on Tuesday night and then early on Wednesday – killed five people according the US defense secretary, Pete Hegseth. Previous attacks have hit seven vessels in the Caribbean and killed at least 32 people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/military-boat-strike-pacific-pete-hegseth"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:42:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New Zealand ‘mega strike’: 100,000 public sector workers demand better conditions</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/new-zealand-mega-strike-teachers-nurses-workers-public-services</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Teachers, nurses and public service staff among those walking off job and also pressing for more government investment in health and education&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An estimated 100,000 nurses, teachers and public sector staff walked off the job in New Zealand on Thursday to call on the government to better fund and resource public services, in one of the country’s largest ever strikes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The so-called “mega strike” brought together workers from multiple sectors, including more than 60,000 school teachers, 40,000 nurses and salaried medical specialists and 15,000 public service staff.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/new-zealand-mega-strike-teachers-nurses-workers-public-services"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:38:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Mamdani, Cuomo and Sliwa fling zingers in New York mayoral debate as they try to win over voters</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/new-york-final-mayoral-debate-mamdani-sliwa-cuomo</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Final debate was marked by heated exchanges between the frontrunners, while Sliwa quipped at Cuomo’s expense&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/new-york"&gt;New York City&lt;/a&gt;’s three mayoral contenders had a fiery debate on Wednesday night in their final televised face-off less than two weeks before voters decide the city’s next leader on 4 November.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Democratic nominee &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/zohran-mamdani"&gt;Zohran Mamdani&lt;/a&gt;, independent &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/andrew-cuomo"&gt;Andrew Cuomo&lt;/a&gt; and Republican Curtis Sliwa participated in a tense and often chaotic discussion. The current mayor, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/eric-adams"&gt;Eric Adams&lt;/a&gt;, who dropped out of the race weeks earlier, once again did not attend.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/new-york-final-mayoral-debate-mamdani-sliwa-cuomo"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:18:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Family of Cheryl Grimmer say ‘what we want now is the truth’ after NSW MP names suspect in parliament</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/23/name-of-suspect-in-cheryl-grimmer-cold-case-revealed-by-nsw-mp-ntwnfb</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Girl’s family had told the man, known by pseudonym ‘Mercury’, to meet with them by Wednesday midnight or they would make his identity public&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/23/australia-news-live-pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-one-nation-nationals-weather-wind-damage-melbourne-sydney-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The family of Cheryl Grimmer has said “what we want now is the truth” after a New South Wales MP used parliamentary privilege to reveal the identity of a man who police previously alleged murdered the UK-born toddler 55 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cheryl vanished from outside a shower block while with her mother and three older brothers at Fairy Meadow beach in the Illawarra region of NSW on 12 January 1970.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/23/name-of-suspect-in-cheryl-grimmer-cold-case-revealed-by-nsw-mp-ntwnfb"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 02:08:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Inexperienced’ British surfer drowned in wild Melbourne weather alongside friend who jumped in to save him</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/23/drowned-men-melbourne-identified-inexperienced-british-surfer-friend-frankston-beach</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Two men who died in sea on Wednesday identified as 36-year-old British national and 43-year-old friend&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/live/2025/oct/23/australia-news-live-pauline-hanson-barnaby-joyce-one-nation-nationals-weather-wind-damage-melbourne-sydney-ntwnfb"&gt;Follow our Australia news live blog for latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;An “inexperienced” British surfer and a friend who jumped in to save him have been identified as the two men who died in rough waters off a popular pier in Victoria during wild winds on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Emergency services were called to Frankston beach in Melbourne’s south-east after reports of two men in trouble in the water about 5pm, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/22/sydney-weather-nsw-heat-bom-forecast-wind-warnings-australia"&gt;as the state was lashed by intense wind gusts.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/23/drowned-men-melbourne-identified-inexperienced-british-surfer-friend-frankston-beach"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:55:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New York unveils portal for public to share ICE footage after four US citizens arrested</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/new-york-chinatown-ice-raids-letitia-james</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Attorney general Letitia James urges residents to share video and photos amid outcry over Chinatown raid &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The New York state attorney general, Letitia James, rolled out a “&lt;a href="https://ag.ny.gov/federal-actions-form"&gt;Federal Action Reporting Portal&lt;/a&gt;” form urging New York residents to share photos and videos of federal immigration enforcement action across the state, just a day after a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/21/new-york-city-chinatown-ice-raids-protests"&gt;high-profile ICE raid&lt;/a&gt; rattled Manhattan’s Chinatown and prompted hundreds to come out in protest.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A US congressman revealed in a Wednesday press conference that four US citizens were arrested and held for “nearly 24 hours” after Tuesday’s raid. Protests broke out in New York on Tuesday and Wednesday evenings.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/new-york-chinatown-ice-raids-letitia-james"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 01:11:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New York City mayoral debate: Mamdani, Sliwa and Cuomo trade jabs over Israel, rent and Trump – as it happened</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/22/nyc-mayoral-debate-mamdani-cuomo-live-updates</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Candidates came out swinging as they vied for New Yorkers’ votes in final debate&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“It’s us versus them,” &lt;strong&gt;Curtis Sliwa&lt;/strong&gt;, the Republican candidate, says in his brief opening statement, in which he claims that he is the true representative of New Yorkers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andrew Cuomo&lt;/strong&gt;, the former New York governor, begins by urging the Knicks to win, and then pivots to attacking “my main opponent”, &lt;strong&gt;Zohran Mamdani&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/22/nyc-mayoral-debate-mamdani-cuomo-live-updates"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:59:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Drones Attack Kyiv For Second Night In A Row After US, EU Impose Sanctions On Russian Energy Sector</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-russia-war-sanctions-trump-putin-oil-rosneft-lukoil/33567454.html</link><description>Russian drones attacked the Ukrainian capital for the second night in a row on October 22, injuring four people, officials said within hours of an announcement from Washington imposing sanctions on Russia’s two largest oil companies.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:44:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Drones Attack Kyiv For Second Night In A Row After US, EU Impose Sanctions On Russian Energy Sector</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-russia-war-sanctions-trump-putin-oil-rosneft-lukoil/33567454.html</link><description>Russian drones attacked the Ukrainian capital for the second night in a row on October 22, injuring four people, officials said within hours of an announcement from Washington imposing sanctions on Russia’s two largest oil companies.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:44:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US forces kill two in strike on alleged drug boat in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd9k2w8ell0o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>This is the eighth US strike on alleged drug trafficking vessels near Latin America, the first on the Pacific side.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Pregnant women report medical neglect in ICE detention, rights groups say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/ice-pregnant-women-neglect-immigration</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Women report miscarriages, delayed care, being shackled and being held in solitary confinement, letter says&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pregnant women have reported bleeding, miscarriages, being shackled and other instances of medical neglect while in US immigration custody, according to a group of prominent civil rights organizations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The groups – which include the American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) and its Louisiana chapter, the National Immigration Project, Robert F Kennedy Human Rights, Sanctuary of the South and Sanctuary Now Abolition Project – sent a &lt;a href="https://www.aclu.org/documents/aclu-partners-demand-ice-release-pregnant-and-postpartum-people-from-ice-detention"&gt;letter&lt;/a&gt; to Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) and Senate committees on Wednesday, describing interviews with more than a dozen women.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/ice-pregnant-women-neglect-immigration"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:35:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Global Use Of Coal Hit Record High In 2024</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odozqq/global_use_of_coal_hit_record_high_in_2024/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odozqq/global_use_of_coal_hit_record_high_in_2024/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Global Use Of Coal Hit Record High In 2024" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/XhB3mEm9z8O-8tBK5LvCKbRmwwLKAMRSpBEmnoe4-yA.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=4f62b8047c0290f0ea3ac3223c5f5b122badede2" title="Global Use Of Coal Hit Record High In 2024" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/reddituser111317"&gt; /u/reddituser111317 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/22/global-use-of-coal-hit-record-high-in-2024"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odozqq/global_use_of_coal_hit_record_high_in_2024/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:17:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump poised to send scores of federal agents to San Francisco</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/trump-federal-agents-san-francisco</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Newsom calls move ‘right out of the dictator’s handbook’ as agents prepare for key immigration enforcement operation&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; appeared poised to send dozens of federal agents to the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/san-francisco"&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; Bay Area for a major immigration enforcement operation, prompting condemnation from &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/california"&gt;California&lt;/a&gt; leaders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Details of the deployment were still emerging, but it will reportedly involve more than 100 federal agents, &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/sf/article/s-f-mayor-lurie-punches-back-at-trump-s-surge-21114906.php"&gt;according&lt;/a&gt; to the San Francisco Chronicle. The agents are &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/sf/article/s-f-mayor-lurie-punches-back-at-trump-s-surge-21114906.php"&gt;reportedly set&lt;/a&gt; to begin using the US Coast Guard base in Alameda, a city located across the bay from San Francisco. It remained unclear whether national guard troops would also be involved.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/trump-federal-agents-san-francisco"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:02:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Putin talks 'don't go anywhere' as he imposes new sanctions</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cd6758pn6ylo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US has announced new sanctions on Rosneft and Lukoil, Russia's two largest oil companies over continued fighting in Ukraine.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:30:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trade Carbon Like a Pro: Seeking a Full Stack Developer !</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odnrmn/trade_carbon_like_a_pro_seeking_a_full_stack/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odnrmn/trade_carbon_like_a_pro_seeking_a_full_stack/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Trade Carbon Like a Pro: Seeking a Full Stack Developer !" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/s-SlhUqzxcre3BoKjRQgn2uB7pPd2NhI20v4wk36qlA.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=b26b57f8dfc2351e514965ffc06e38957094cbfa" title="Trade Carbon Like a Pro: Seeking a Full Stack Developer !" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/energxexchange"&gt; /u/energxexchange &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://energxexchange.com"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odnrmn/trade_carbon_like_a_pro_seeking_a_full_stack/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:21:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Tesla’s Profit Falls 37% After It Cut Car Prices</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/22/business/tesla-earnings-elon-musk.html</link><description>The company sold more cars but made less money on each one because of discounts and low-interest loans.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:17:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Temu agrees to remove rip-off greeting cards from its site more quickly</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2kpg9jyn0po?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Card firms say their designs are being copied costing them thousands in lost sales.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:08:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>BBC sitcom Two Doors Down to be adapted for the stage with full TV cast</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2025/oct/23/bbc-sitcom-two-doors-down-to-be-adapted-for-the-stage-with-full-tv-cast</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The hit Scottish comedy about suburban neighbours will move from screen to stage next year at Glasgow’s Hydro&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two Doors Down, the BBC comedy series about a suburban Scottish couple with constantly knocking neighbours, is to be &lt;a href="https://www.ticketmaster.co.uk/two-doors-down-live"&gt;brought to the stage&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Unusually, it will make that journey with the full cast from the hit TV show intact. Alex Norton and Arabella Weir will reprise their roles as Eric and Beth, whose house on Latimer Crescent is consistently besieged by the street’s residents, usually expecting a drink or two. Elaine C Smith will return as the oversharing Christine, and Doon Mackichan and Jonathan Watson are reuniting as a flashy couple, with an unhealthy interest in everyone’s intimate business. The younger couple on the street will again be played by Graeme Stevely and Joy McAvoy, while Jamie Quinn will be back as Eric and Beth’s son, Ian, with standup Kieran Hodgson once more playing his partner, Gordon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2025/oct/23/bbc-sitcom-two-doors-down-to-be-adapted-for-the-stage-with-full-tv-cast"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 23:01:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>VortexNet: Neural network based on fluid dynamics</title><link>https://github.com/samim23/vortexnet</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45676162"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:51:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Third night of unrest in Dublin as protesters target asylum hotel</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/22/stones-and-fireworks-again-thrown-at-dublin-police-as-protests-enter-third-night</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Officers pelted with stones and fireworks near Citywest facility after man charged over alleged assault on 10-year-old&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Twenty-three people were arrested after an hours-long standoff with Irish police, whose members were directly struck with fireworks, stones and other debris on a third consecutive night of disorder in Dublin.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two members of the Irish police service, An Garda Síochána, were taken to hospital with injuries sustained during clashes with protesters. One garda was struck on the head by a bottle while the other sustained a shoulder injury.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/22/stones-and-fireworks-again-thrown-at-dublin-police-as-protests-enter-third-night"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:41:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US imposes sanctions on Russian oil over Putin’s ‘refusal’ to end war in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/us-sanctions-russia-oil-vladimir-putin-refusal-ukraine-war</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Trump administration hardens stance against the Kremlin day after cancelling a planned summit with Russian leader&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US has sanctioned Rosneft and Lukoil, Russia’s two largest oil companies, as the Trump administration increased pressure on the Kremlin to negotiate an end to its war against Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sanctions were the first against Russia since Donald Trump returned to the White House in January, and were targeted to cut key revenues from oil sales that finance the Russian war machine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/us-sanctions-russia-oil-vladimir-putin-refusal-ukraine-war"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:22:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Iceland reports the presence of mosquitoes as climate warms</title><link>https://www.npr.org/2025/10/22/nx-s1-5582748/iceland-mosquitoes-first-time</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45675851"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:15:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Groceries via delivery apps like Uber Eats, DoorDash and Milkrun can be up to 39% more expensive</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/23/groceries-via-delivery-apps-like-ubereats-doordash-and-milkrun-can-be-up-to-39-more-expensive</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Seven out of 13 items at Aldi were priced higher on DoorDash than in store, while Milkrun charged more for 11 out of 13 items from Woolworths&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Convenience can come at a steep price, Choice has found, with Australian consumers paying up to 39% more for groceries ordered through rapid delivery apps.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.choice.com.au/grocerydeliverycosts"&gt;Choice compared in-store prices of 13 common grocery items &lt;/a&gt;available at Coles, Woolworths and Aldi with their equivalents on third-party apps Uber Eats, DoorDash and Woolworths-owned Milkrun.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/23/groceries-via-delivery-apps-like-ubereats-doordash-and-milkrun-can-be-up-to-39-more-expensive"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:13:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Last candidate to chair UK grooming gangs inquiry withdraws over ‘lack of trust’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/22/chair-uk-grooming-gangs-inquiry-lack-of-trust-panel-resign-adviser-louise-casey</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jim Gamble cites ‘vested interests’ and ‘political opportunism’, as Keir Starmer brings in Louise Casey as adviser&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Keir Starmer’s grooming gangs inquiry has descended into fresh turmoil after the only remaining candidate to be its chair blamed “political opportunism” and “a lack of trust” for his withdrawal as an applicant.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a key survivor called for a face-to-face meeting with the prime minister to save &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/21/why-is-there-a-national-inquiry-into-grooming-gangs"&gt;the inquiry&lt;/a&gt;, Jim Gamble, a former deputy chief constable, said the process to appoint a committee head was “toxic” and defined by “vested interests”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/22/chair-uk-grooming-gangs-inquiry-lack-of-trust-panel-resign-adviser-louise-casey"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:11:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says 'existing structure' of White House East Wing to be torn down</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czxn7lwzx5po?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US president previously said that his $250m (£186m) ballroom addition would not "interfere with the current building".</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:11:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Myanmar's army is taking back territory with relentless air strikes - and China's help</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c051m0jn392o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>China has thrown its weight behind the junta - and its widely condemned plan to hold an election in December.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:09:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Shabana Mahmood says damning report shows Home Office ‘not fit for purpose’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/shabana-mahmood-says-damning-report-shows-home-office-not-fit-for-purpose</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Home secretary vows overhaul after previously secret 2023 review lists series of perceived shortcomings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Shabana Mahmood has said the Home Office is “not yet fit for purpose” after the release of a damning report that was kept secret for years.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The review, written under the previous government, uncovered a series of perceived shortcomings including a “culture of defeatism” on immigration, a lack of trust from other departments, and “several confused and conflicting systems”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/shabana-mahmood-says-damning-report-shows-home-office-not-fit-for-purpose"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 22:01:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. Sanctions Major Russian Energy Companies</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/22/trump-sanctions-russian-oil-rosneft-lukoil-putin-ukraine-war/</link><description>The move follows a U.S. decision to cancel plans for a peace summit in Budapest.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:42:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Deep Roots of Afghanistan-Pakistan Border Violence</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/22/afghanistan-pakistan-border-violence-cease-fire-terrorism/</link><description>It’s not just terrorism concerns driving tensions.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:26:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Police take no further action against men arrested for Trump Windsor projections</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/police-to-take-no-further-action-against-men-arrested-for-trump-windsor-projections</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Investigation ends after Led By Donkeys stunt highlighting the US president’s relationship with Jeffrey Epstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No further action will be taken against four men arrested in connection with projecting an image of Donald Trump and the convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein on to Windsor Castle, police said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/sep/17/four-arrested-after-image-of-trump-and-epstein-projected-onto-windsor-castle-ahead-of-presidents-visit"&gt;stunt during Trump’s unprecedented second state visit&lt;/a&gt; on 16 September by the political campaign group Led By Donkeys attempted to draw attention to the US president’s long friendship with Epstein.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/police-to-take-no-further-action-against-men-arrested-for-trump-windsor-projections"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:14:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US Imposes 'Substantial' Sanctions On Russian Oil Companies Over Putin's 'Refusal To End Senseless War'</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-russia-oil-war-bessent-trump-putin-sanctions/33567131.html</link><description>The United States imposed what it said were "major" sanctions on Russian oil companies on October 22, saying the action was "a result of Russia’s lack of serious commitment to a peace process to end the war in Ukraine."</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:07:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US Imposes 'Substantial' Sanctions On Russian Oil Companies Over Putin's 'Refusal To End Senseless War'</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-russia-oil-war-bessent-trump-putin-sanctions/33567131.html</link><description>The United States imposed what it said were "major" sanctions on Russian oil companies on October 22, saying the action was "a result of Russia’s lack of serious commitment to a peace process to end the war in Ukraine."</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:07:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>InpharmD (YC W21) Is Hiring – NLP Engineer</title><link>https://inpharmd.com/jobs/inpharmd-is-hiring-ai-ml-engineer</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45675090"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 21:01:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>YASA beats own power density record pushing electric motor to 59kW/kg benchmark</title><link>https://yasa.com/news/yasa-smashes-own-unofficial-power-density-world-record-pushing-state-of-the-art-electric-motor-to-staggering-new-59kw-kg-benchmark/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45675020"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:54:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Google flags Immich sites as dangerous</title><link>https://immich.app/blog/google-flags-immich-as-dangerous</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45675015"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:53:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Keir Starmer prepares to miss key green target in effort to keep energy bills down</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/keir-starmer-green-pledge-2030-energy-bills</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Promise to remove almost all fossil fuels from UK’s electricity supply by 2030 may be quietly abandoned over cost&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministers are considering dropping one of their central green pledges in an effort to keep energy bills down, sources have told the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Government insiders say Keir Starmer is prepared to miss his own target of removing almost all fossil fuels from the UK’s electricity supply by 2030 if doing so proves much more expensive than building gas power instead.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/22/keir-starmer-green-pledge-2030-energy-bills"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:47:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rutte Holds a Last-Minute Meeting With Trump on Russia-Ukraine</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/22/mark-rutte-trump-russia-ukraine-cease-fire-putin-zelensky/</link><description>Ahead of the meeting, the NATO chief stoked the U.S. president’s ego and brushed off concerns about a lack of progress in cease-fire talks.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:35:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Reddit Accuses ‘Data Scraper’ Companies of Theft</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/22/technology/reddit-data-scrapers-perplexity-theft.html</link><description>In a lawsuit, Reddit pulled back the curtain on an ecosystem of start-ups that scrape Google’s search results and resell the information to data-hungry A.I. companies.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:23:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>South Africa Unveils New Energy Policy</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/22/south-africa-nuclear-gas-coal-eskom-integrated-resource-plan/</link><description>The continent’s largest emitter aims to cut coal and invest in nuclear and gas.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:22:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Insurgent Armies and State Formation after Victory | Irregular Warfare Podcast</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/22/insurgent-armies-and-state-formation-after-victory-irregular-warfare-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Episode 136 of the Irregular Warfare Podcast (Irregular Warfare Initiative&amp;#8217;s podcast) examines the fate of victorious rebel groups after civil wars—and why some remain loyal to post-war governments while others fragment, defect, or even overthrow the regimes they helped create. Our guests begin by exploring the core puzzle: conventional wisdom suggests that decisive victory produces stability, yet evidence shows that &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/22/insurgent-armies-and-state-formation-after-victory-irregular-warfare-podcast/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/22/insurgent-armies-and-state-formation-after-victory-irregular-warfare-podcast/"&gt;Insurgent Armies and State Formation after Victory | Irregular Warfare Podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:14:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why SSA Compilers?</title><link>https://mcyoung.xyz/2025/10/21/ssa-1/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674568"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:13:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Setting up a commercial EV charging station in a country with a poor electrical grid?</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odj2lq/setting_up_a_commercial_ev_charging_station_in_a/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Rooseveltdunn"&gt; /u/Rooseveltdunn &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/electricvehicles/comments/1od95vw/setting_up_a_commercial_ev_charging_station_in_a/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odj2lq/setting_up_a_commercial_ev_charging_station_in_a/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:09:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>No camera covered Louvre wall where jewel thieves broke in, director says</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9d6e2wv884o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Laurence des Cars said there was only one camera pointing on the gallery which was robbed.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:05:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Is a ‘Scarcity President’</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/22/america-trump-scarcity-president-greg-grandin-interview/</link><description>Pulitzer Prize-winning historian Greg Grandin on the end of the American myth of limitlessness.</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:05:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Serious consequences expected after refinery fire in Hungary: One neighbouring country could face the worst energy crisis</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odiwzj/serious_consequences_expected_after_refinery_fire/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/DailyNewsHungary"&gt; /u/DailyNewsHungary &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://dailynewshungary.com/consequences-refinery-fire-country-crisis/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1odiwzj/serious_consequences_expected_after_refinery_fire/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 20:03:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>ICJ orders Israel to allow aid into Gaza and says restrictions breached international obligations</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/22/icj-orders-israel-to-allow-aid-into-gaza-and-says-blockade-had-been-a-breach</link><description>&lt;p&gt;UN’s top court also finds Israel failed to justify blocking Unrwa and other relief agencies&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Israel must allow aid into Gaza, and its restrictions on doing so over the past two years have put it in breach of its obligations, the UN’s top court has found.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The stinging advisory opinion by the International Court of Justice in The Hague also found that Israel had a duty not to impede the supply of aid by UN organisations including the beleaguered UN Palestinian relief agency Unrwa, which has been in effect banned from the territory since January.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/22/icj-orders-israel-to-allow-aid-into-gaza-and-says-blockade-had-been-a-breach"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:43:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ovi: Twin backbone cross-modal fusion for audio-video generation</title><link>https://github.com/character-ai/Ovi</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674166"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:42:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Show HN: Cuq – Formal Verification of Rust GPU Kernels</title><link>https://github.com/neelsomani/cuq</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45674126"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 19:38:54 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>