<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 18:53:28 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Honduran immigrant dies while fleeing ICE, bringing raids death toll to three</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/honduran-immigrant-dies-trying-to-flee-ice</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Jose Castro Rivera, 24, was killed Thursday morning after running onto a highway and being struck&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 24-year-old Honduran man died while trying to flee Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE) agents in Virginia, bringing the death toll among those trying to escape detention in the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt;’s mass deportation crackdown to at least three people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jose Castro Rivera was killed on Thursday morning after running onto a busy highway and being struck and fatally injured while trying to evade ICE agents, local authorities said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/honduran-immigrant-dies-trying-to-flee-ice"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/honduran-immigrant-dies-trying-to-flee-ice</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 18:30:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Man arrested after viral video of alleged rape attempt on Paris train</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9d6q65llzwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Alerted by a woman's screams, another passenger pulled out her phone to film the alleged attack.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c9d6q65llzwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:28:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Catherine Connolly’s landslide shakes Ireland’s establishment – but not its politics</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connollys-landslide-shakes-irelands-establishment-but-not-its-politics</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Connolly’s stunning victory humbles old parties and energises the left, yet it’s no revolution: the presidency remains symbolic&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Catherine Connolly’s &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connolly-ireland-presidential-election-leftwing"&gt;landslide victory&lt;/a&gt; in Ireland’s presidential election is a stunning political feat that humiliates the establishment but does not signify a national swerve to the left.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There was nothing inevitable about her triumph, let alone its scale. In July, when she declared her candidacy, she was a one-woman act: an independent leftwing member of parliament from Galway who was unfamiliar to most voters.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connollys-landslide-shakes-irelands-establishment-but-not-its-politics"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connollys-landslide-shakes-irelands-establishment-but-not-its-politics</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:17:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Libera Chat receives legal advice that the Online Safety Act does not apply to</title><link>https://libera.chat/news/advised</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45705381"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://libera.chat/news/advised</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:07:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour demands clarity on Tory plan to strip thousands of right to stay in UK</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/labour-demands-clarity-on-tory-plan-to-strip-thousands-of-right-to-stay-in-uk</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anna Turley says legally settled people threatened by Katie Lam’s proposals deserve urgent clarification&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labour has called on the Conservatives to clarify their plan to strip the right to remain permanently in the UK from thousands of people, saying those affected had a right to know what was being proposed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anna Turley MP, the Labour chair, has written to Katie Lam, the shadow Home Office minister whose interview about the plans last weekend &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/20/tory-mp-criticised-after-demanding-legally-settled-families-be-deported"&gt;sparked renewed interest&lt;/a&gt; in the policy of retrospectively revoking indefinite leave to remain (ILR) status for large numbers of people.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/labour-demands-clarity-on-tory-plan-to-strip-thousands-of-right-to-stay-in-uk"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/labour-demands-clarity-on-tory-plan-to-strip-thousands-of-right-to-stay-in-uk</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 17:00:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump plan would allow oil rigs along entire California coast. “This administration is very punitive and wants to threaten California.” Trump is taking steps to open nearly all US coastal waters to new offshore oil and gas drilling, with Florida being an exception.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofwbvw/trump_plan_would_allow_oil_rigs_along_entire/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofwbvw/trump_plan_would_allow_oil_rigs_along_entire/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Trump plan would allow oil rigs along entire California coast. “This administration is very punitive and wants to threaten California.” Trump is taking steps to open nearly all US coastal waters to new offshore oil and gas drilling, with Florida being an exception." src="https://external-preview.redd.it/4sXnboBXWxr8ghCeXU8hNtAj6PeHmH5Wi6-3cjZfRKY.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=27b9f656dddef8e56550b3e7fa4608106327e36b" title="Trump plan would allow oil rigs along entire California coast. “This administration is very punitive and wants to threaten California.” Trump is taking steps to open nearly all US coastal waters to new offshore oil and gas drilling, with Florida being an exception." /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/mafco"&gt; /u/mafco &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/california/article/trump-offshore-drilling-21116334.php"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofwbvw/trump_plan_would_allow_oil_rigs_along_entire/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofwbvw/trump_plan_would_allow_oil_rigs_along_entire/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:47:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump backer Timothy Mellon identified as donor of $130m for US troop pay during government shutdown</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/timothy-mellon-donor-military-pay-shutdown</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reclusive Republican billionaire is descendant of gilded age industrialist and former treasury secretary Andrew Mellon&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A reclusive billionaire, anti-tax crusader and major financial backer of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; has been named as the anonymous private donor who gave $130m to the government to help pay US troops during the federal shutdown that is now in its fourth week, according to the &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/25/us/politics/timothy-mellon-donation-troops.html"&gt;New York Times&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Timothy Mellon, heir to the gilded age industrialist and former treasury secretary Andrew Mellon, is the secret donor whom Trump has described as a “friend”, “great American” and “patriot”, but has refused to name, the Times reported on Saturday, citing two anonymous sources familiar with the arrangement.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/timothy-mellon-donor-military-pay-shutdown"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/timothy-mellon-donor-military-pay-shutdown</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:37:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rock Tumbler Instructions: Turning Rough Rocks into Beautiful Tumbled Stones</title><link>https://rocktumbler.com/tips/rock-tumbler-instructions/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45705125"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://rocktumbler.com/tips/rock-tumbler-instructions/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:32:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How ‘screw Trump’ messaging may help California’s Proposition 50 prevail</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/california-prop-50-trump-redistricting</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Republican opposition to the effort to give House Democrats more safe seats may be no match for the fact that Californians really don’t like Trump&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are many ways to characterize Proposition 50, the single ballot initiative that Californians will be voting on this election season.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;You could say it’s about redrawing congressional district lines outside the regular once-a-decade schedule. You could say, more precisely, that it’s about counterbalancing Republican efforts to engineer congressional seats in their favor in Texas and elsewhere with a gerrymander that favors the Democrats. You could, like the measure’s detractors, call it a partisan power grab that risks undermining 15 years of careful work to make California’s congressional elections as fair and competitive as possible.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/california-prop-50-trump-redistricting"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/california-prop-50-trump-redistricting</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 16:00:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10/25/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/25/10-25-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Access National Security News HERE. Access Korean News HERE. National Security News: 1. As Putin Digs In, a Long—and Different—War With Ukraine Looms 2. Sanctioned Russian Oil Will Find New Ways to Flow 3. Pentagon Orders Aircraft Carrier to the Caribbean 4. Anonymous Donor Gives $130 Million to Pay Troops During Shutdown, Pentagon Says 5. Trump Says the Road to Gaza Ran Through Tehran 6. Western &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/25/10-25-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/25/10-25-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;10/25/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/25/10-25-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:59:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Met police urge Epping sex offender spotted in London to hand himself in</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/sex-offender-freed-by-mistake-search-london</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Former asylum seeker Hadush Gerberslasie Kebatu has been missing since being released from prison in error&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Police searching in London for a former asylum seeker and convicted sex offender who was released from prison in error have urged him to hand himself in.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian national Hadush Gerberslasie Kebatu was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/sep/23/asylum-seeker-at-centre-of-essex-hotel-protests-jailed-for-12-months"&gt;jailed for 12 months&lt;/a&gt; in September for sexually assaulting a woman and a 14-year-old girl and made the subject of a five-year sexual harm prevention order.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/sex-offender-freed-by-mistake-search-london"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/sex-offender-freed-by-mistake-search-london</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:54:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Awesome free night's promo update</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofup7b/awesome_free_nights_promo_update/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Patient-Freedom5692"&gt; /u/Patient-Freedom5692 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofup7b/awesome_free_nights_promo_update/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofup7b/awesome_free_nights_promo_update/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofup7b/awesome_free_nights_promo_update/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:41:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Direct Drive Wind Turbine Market to Reach USD 34 Billion by 2035, Growing at 9.7% CAGR | Enercon GmbH, Envision Energy</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofumws/direct_drive_wind_turbine_market_to_reach_usd_34/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the report, the global &lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/reports/direct-drive-wind-turbine-market-42497"&gt;direct drive wind turbine market&lt;/a&gt; is likely to grow from USD 13.5 Billion in 2025 to USD 34.0 Billion in 2035 at a highest CAGR of 11.2% during the time period. The global direct drive wind turbine market is continuing to grow with the quickening pace of evolution and modernization of the renewable energy sector, which is continuing to drive global demand for sustainable energy generation from a variety of operational perspectives in renewable energy generation, grid stability, and carbon footprint reduction. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Energy developers, technology developers, and manufacturers are placing innovative, advanced direct drive systems with permanent magnet generators, and AI enabled performance monitoring and predictive maintenance capabilities to maximize efficiencies, reliability and lower costs. In March 2025, Goldwind Science &amp;amp; Technology announced its new GD150-6.7 MW turbine that uses digital twin and smart condition monitoring technologies to improve performance in land-based installations worldwide. In June 2025, Ming Yang Smart Energy launched a new MySE-14X turbine with an innovative modular design and adaptive AI based control. Both of these advances would improve energy yield and lower operational downtime of turbines in the field. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/press-releases/direct-drive-wind-turbine-market-42497"&gt;Get the Detailed Industry Analysis (including the Table of Contents, List of Figures, and List of Tables) - from the Direct Drive Wind Turbine Market Research Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Prominent players operating in global direct drive wind turbine market include prominent companies such as Doosan Heavy Industries &amp;amp; Construction, Enercon GmbH, Envision Energy, Gamesa Electric, GE Renewable Energy (General Electric), Goldwind Science &amp;amp; Technology Co., Ltd., Hitachi ABB Power Grids, Leitwind Technology, MingYang Smart Energy Group, Nordex SE, ReGen Powertech Pvt. Ltd., Senvion (Now part of Siemens Gamesa), Siemens Gamesa Renewable Energy, Sinovel Wind Group Co., Ltd., Suzlon Energy Ltd., TPI Composites, Inc., United Power Technology Co., Ltd., Vestas Wind Systems A/S, Windar Photonics, XEMC Windpower Co., Ltd., along with several other key players. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/download-report-sample/direct-drive-wind-turbine-market-42497"&gt;To know more about the Direct Drive Wind Turbine Market - Download our Sample Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Key Trend: Shift toward Unified Platforms Enabling End-to-End Visibility in Direct Drive Wind Turbine Operations &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;There is a rising trend of integrated turbine management platforms to create an end-to-end view from performance monitoring and predictive maintenance to grid integration to improve operational oversight as well as operational efficiency. In March 2025, Enercon launched a single wind turbine control solution with real time performance dashboards and condition monitoring. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Likewise, Vestas launched AI-driven insights to detect faults and optimize energy yield. Since the trend of direct drive wind turbines accelerates in the offshore and onshore markets, these integrated and auditable platforms can become indispensable to break down operational silos, improve reliability of the assets, adherence to regulatory standards, and develop overall performance. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Contact: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Debashish Roy &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MarketGenics India Pvt. Ltd. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;800 N King Street, Suite 304 #4208, Wilmington, DE 19801, United States &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;USA: +1 (302) 303-2617 &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Email: [&lt;a href="mailto:sales@marketgenics.co"&gt;sales@marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;](mailto:&lt;a href="mailto:sales@marketgenics.co"&gt;sales@marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co"&gt;https://marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/InevitableWalrus6253"&gt; /u/InevitableWalrus6253 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofumws/direct_drive_wind_turbine_market_to_reach_usd_34/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofumws/direct_drive_wind_turbine_market_to_reach_usd_34/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofumws/direct_drive_wind_turbine_market_to_reach_usd_34/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:38:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour’s new deputy leader says party must pay more heed to its members</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/25/labour-new-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-party-must-pay-more-heed-to-members</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Lucy Powell, who was sacked as Commons leader by Starmer in September, says government should stop trying to ‘out-Reform Reform’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Labour’s new deputy leader, Lucy Powell, has said the government must listen to its members instead of being guided by a “narrow group of voices” as it battles to stave off electoral disaster in next May’s local elections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powell defeated the education secretary, Bridget Phillipson, in the deputy leadership contest, which concluded on Saturday. She said she had been given “a clear mandate that members want their voice to be heard at the top of the party”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/25/labour-new-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-party-must-pay-more-heed-to-members"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/25/labour-new-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-party-must-pay-more-heed-to-members</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:29:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Apollo Says AI Energy Gap 'Will Not Be Closed in Our Lifetime'</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofu2ye/apollo_says_ai_energy_gap_will_not_be_closed_in/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/bardsmanship"&gt; /u/bardsmanship &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://archive.is/46Ud4"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofu2ye/apollo_says_ai_energy_gap_will_not_be_closed_in/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofu2ye/apollo_says_ai_energy_gap_will_not_be_closed_in/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:15:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>GZR Observer — Global Daily — Oct 25, 2025</title><link>https://daily.gzr.observer/gzr-observer-global-daily-oct-25-2025-e2466a0476c5?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</link><description>&lt;div class="medium-feed-item"&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://daily.gzr.observer/gzr-observer-global-daily-oct-25-2025-e2466a0476c5?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/600/1*DQI-zyeQzzNDyYyCGGPo2A.png" width="600" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-link"&gt;&lt;a href="https://daily.gzr.observer/gzr-observer-global-daily-oct-25-2025-e2466a0476c5?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;Continue reading on GZR Observer v9 — Daily »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://daily.gzr.observer/gzr-observer-global-daily-oct-25-2025-e2466a0476c5?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:15:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China expands highway solar as provinces race to decarbonize transport</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftvdo/china_expands_highway_solar_as_provinces_race_to/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftvdo/china_expands_highway_solar_as_provinces_race_to/"&gt; &lt;img alt="China expands highway solar as provinces race to decarbonize transport" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/G1TYJw14RMfMfpTFvxDtj6iDBDbi3Ti6lp8D1EBYzMs.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=4426206ef49826a408bdec6db172a05b58a5a9a4" title="China expands highway solar as provinces race to decarbonize transport" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/bardsmanship"&gt; /u/bardsmanship &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2025/10/23/china-expands-highway-solar-as-provinces-race-to-decarbonize-transport/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftvdo/china_expands_highway_solar_as_provinces_race_to/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftvdo/china_expands_highway_solar_as_provinces_race_to/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:07:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Against SQL</title><link>https://www.scattered-thoughts.net/writing/against-sql/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45704419"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.scattered-thoughts.net/writing/against-sql/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 15:00:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New ammonia-tolerant microbe produces renewable natural gas from food leftovers</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftl5n/new_ammoniatolerant_microbe_produces_renewable/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftl5n/new_ammoniatolerant_microbe_produces_renewable/"&gt; &lt;img alt="New ammonia-tolerant microbe produces renewable natural gas from food leftovers" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/vXY3Yz9MF_x2fIMiOIFBtp7Xyr7FxWtI1hjXfBiAq28.png?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=c8aa4ef0a624ebb35cede53e911bdb798ac12ebd" title="New ammonia-tolerant microbe produces renewable natural gas from food leftovers" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Sackim05"&gt; /u/Sackim05 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://interestingengineering.com/energy/bacteria-turn-waste-into-natural-gas"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftl5n/new_ammoniatolerant_microbe_produces_renewable/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftl5n/new_ammoniatolerant_microbe_produces_renewable/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:56:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How America's Obsession With Light Exposes Its Energy Hypocrisy</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftag0/how_americas_obsession_with_light_exposes_its/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftag0/how_americas_obsession_with_light_exposes_its/"&gt; &lt;img alt="How America's Obsession With Light Exposes Its Energy Hypocrisy" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/b7yo7bxWoASn7Nk5gEDuMv9JLGWBt5EuqAPvz6fGSPI.jpeg?width=216&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=c90f67a0ac4eac7c3f58d3a740c8bded4d7cffaf" title="How America's Obsession With Light Exposes Its Energy Hypocrisy" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/UweLang"&gt; /u/UweLang &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://peakd.com/hive-112018/@levidesmond69/how-americas-obsession-with-light-exposes-its-energy-hypocrisy"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftag0/how_americas_obsession_with_light_exposes_its/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oftag0/how_americas_obsession_with_light_exposes_its/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:43:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Met police take over search for Epping sex offender after London sighting – as it happened</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/live/2025/oct/25/hadush-gerberslasie-kebatu-manhunt-met-police-sex-offender-london-latest-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This live blog is now closed, you can read our full report &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/25/sex-offender-freed-by-mistake-search-london"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The accidental release of the asylum seeker was a “mind-blowing” blunder, says the MP for Chelmsford.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Liberal Democrat MP &lt;strong&gt;Marie Goldman&lt;/strong&gt; said on Saturday: “My mind has blown. How this could possibly happen?”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He came out of the airlock, and kept saying to the officers there, ‘Where am I going? What am I doing? I don’t know where I’m going and what I’m doing.’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He was holding a pack of paperwork in his arms, and his bag of bits …&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;He knew he’d been deported. He came over to me and said, ‘I need you to help me.’&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/live/2025/oct/25/hadush-gerberslasie-kebatu-manhunt-met-police-sex-offender-london-latest-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/live/2025/oct/25/hadush-gerberslasie-kebatu-manhunt-met-police-sex-offender-london-latest-news</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:42:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Early voting starts for New York mayoral and New Jersey gubernatorial races</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/early-voting-new-york-new-jersey</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Zohran Mamdani is facing off against Andrew Cuomo in New York, and Jack Ciattarelli and Mikie Sherrill are competing in New Jersey&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Polling places opened on Saturday for the start of in-person voting for two of the year’s most closely watched elections: the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/new-york"&gt;New York City&lt;/a&gt; mayor’s race and the contest to pick &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/new-jersey"&gt;New Jersey&lt;/a&gt;’s next governor.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New Yorkers are choosing between Democrat &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/zohran-mamdani"&gt;Zohran Mamdani&lt;/a&gt;, Republican Curtis Sliwa and former New York governor &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/andrew-cuomo"&gt;Andrew Cuomo&lt;/a&gt;, a Democrat on the ballot as an independent. The incumbent mayor, Eric Adams, is also on the ballot but dropped out of the race last month and recently threw his support behind Cuomo.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/early-voting-new-york-new-jersey"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/early-voting-new-york-new-jersey</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:20:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘I am not done’: Kamala Harris says she may run for president again</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/kamala-harris-bbc-interview</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In a BBC interview, former vice-president says she isn’t done with politics and could ‘possibly’ be the next president&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/kamala-harris"&gt;Kamala Harris&lt;/a&gt; says she is not done with politics and strongly suggested that she is considering another bid for president in a new interview.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In an interview scheduled to air &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2n7k2veywo"&gt;on the BBC on Sunday morning&lt;/a&gt;, Harris says that she would “possibly” be the next president, making the clearest suggestion to date that she will make another run for the White House in 2028 despite lagging far behind in the polls.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/kamala-harris-bbc-interview"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/kamala-harris-bbc-interview</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:16:49 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hundreds of smartphones intensified India bus blaze - reports</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c15pnlz3gdvo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The bus was carrying 234 smartphones that likely ruptured, exacerbating the fire, officials told local media.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c15pnlz3gdvo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 14:11:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Synadia and TigerBeetle Commit $512k USD to the Zig Software Foundation</title><link>https://www.synadia.com/blog/synadia-tigerbeetle-zig-foundation-pledge</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45703716"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.synadia.com/blog/synadia-tigerbeetle-zig-foundation-pledge</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:24:14 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Leftwinger Catherine Connolly wins Ireland presidential election by landslide</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connolly-ireland-presidential-election-leftwing</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Heather Humphreys concedes defeat after early vote tallies show insurmountable gap between candidates&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The leftwing independent candidate, Catherine Connolly, has won a landslide victory in Ireland’s presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Her rival, Heather Humphreys, conceded defeat on Saturday afternoon after early vote tallies showed an insurmountable gap between the candidates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connolly-ireland-presidential-election-leftwing"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/catherine-connolly-ireland-presidential-election-leftwing</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:20:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump hopes China will help push Russia towards Ukraine peace talks</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn51yk9vgrko?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Struggling to broker a peace deal in Ukraine, Trump hopes Xi Jinping could influence Vladimir Putin.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn51yk9vgrko?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:07:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>As Trump Returns to Asia, It’s the “Small-State” Effect Worth Watching</title><link>https://medium.com/@makeyourmarcsg/as-trump-returns-to-asia-its-the-small-state-effect-worth-watching-2cb387e054c9?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</link><description>&lt;div class="medium-feed-item"&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@makeyourmarcsg/as-trump-returns-to-asia-its-the-small-state-effect-worth-watching-2cb387e054c9?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1248/1*m0SgplCPSy1mRUe_PUcDGQ.jpeg" width="1248" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-snippet"&gt;A repeat of the &amp;#x201c;Trump effect&amp;#x201d; from his Gulf Tour appears unlikely. The Indo-Pacific is not the Gulf&amp;#x200a;&amp;#x2014;&amp;#x200a;and Trump isn&amp;#x2019;t a hegemon here.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-link"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@makeyourmarcsg/as-trump-returns-to-asia-its-the-small-state-effect-worth-watching-2cb387e054c9?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;Continue reading on Medium »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@makeyourmarcsg/as-trump-returns-to-asia-its-the-small-state-effect-worth-watching-2cb387e054c9?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:01:50 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Making a micro Linux distro (2023)</title><link>https://popovicu.com/posts/making-a-micro-linux-distro/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45703556"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://popovicu.com/posts/making-a-micro-linux-distro/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 13:01:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Venezuela's Maduro says US 'fabricating war' as it deploys world's largest warship</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c891gzx7xn4o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The deployment marks a major escalation in what the US says is a campaign against drug traffickers, which Trump warns will include "land action".</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c891gzx7xn4o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:48:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Labour’s new deputy leader Lucy Powell says she wants Starmer to succeed but party must change – as it happened</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/25/new-labour-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-bridget-phillipson-uk-politics-latest-news-updates</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is now closed, you can read more on this story &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/25/lucy-powell-wins-labour-deputy-leadership-election"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lucy Powell&lt;/strong&gt; has paid tribute to former Labour deputy leader &lt;strong&gt;Angela Rayner&lt;/strong&gt;, saying she has some “big shoes to fill”, as she took to the stage to celebrate her win.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Powell spoke about how “division and hate” has increased. She said the desire for change is “palpable”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/25/new-labour-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-bridget-phillipson-uk-politics-latest-news-updates"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/25/new-labour-deputy-leader-lucy-powell-bridget-phillipson-uk-politics-latest-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:30:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>'I am not done' - Kamala Harris tells BBC she may run for president again</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2n7k2veywo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The former US vice-president made her strongest suggestion to date she will make another bid for the White House</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2n7k2veywo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 12:00:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Oct. 20-24, 2025)</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/122887/digest-recent-articles-just-security-oct-20-24-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-oct-20-24-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Series: International Law Weekend 2025 • U.S. strikes / Venezuela • Russia-Ukraine War • Israel-Hamas War • United Nations / Global inequality • Trump executive actions • Supreme Court / U.S. military • Series: When Guardrails Erode • Cyber • Violent extremism • Civilian harm • Civil society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/122887/digest-recent-articles-just-security-oct-20-24-2025/"&gt;Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Oct. 20-24, 2025)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/122887/digest-recent-articles-just-security-oct-20-24-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-oct-20-24-2025</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:41:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia Women’s Cricket World Cup players ‘touched inappropriately’ in India</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/25/australia-womens-cricket-world-cup-players-allegedly-touched-inappropriately-in-india</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two players were walking to a cafe from their Indore hotel&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;A man has been arrested after being identified on CCTV&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A man has been arrested for approaching two of Australia’s women cricketers and allegedly touching them inappropriately in Indore, Indian police said on Saturday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The incident occurred on Thursday in Indore, a day off for the team after their &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/22/womens-world-cup-australia-england-match-report"&gt;six-wicket victory over England&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/25/australia-womens-cricket-world-cup-players-allegedly-touched-inappropriately-in-india"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/25/australia-womens-cricket-world-cup-players-allegedly-touched-inappropriately-in-india</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:37:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wood Mackenzie records solar LCOE of $37/MWh in MENA region</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofp9mm/wood_mackenzie_records_solar_lcoe_of_37mwh_in/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofp9mm/wood_mackenzie_records_solar_lcoe_of_37mwh_in/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Wood Mackenzie records solar LCOE of $37/MWh in MENA region" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/Vppg4636LHCTfCVkt5wVVY7G07hZEgQVw0YaQn-eDJI.png?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=b7e6ad8b9f231b4feb33cb1122f6e4b53ff2dc05" title="Wood Mackenzie records solar LCOE of $37/MWh in MENA region" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/bfire123"&gt; /u/bfire123 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pv-magazine.com/2025/10/24/wood-mackenzie-records-solar-lcoe-of-37-mwh-in-mena-region/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofp9mm/wood_mackenzie_records_solar_lcoe_of_37mwh_in/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ofp9mm/wood_mackenzie_records_solar_lcoe_of_37mwh_in/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:32:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ousted Madagascan president stripped of citizenship</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c74jnngr1e3o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Andry Rajoelina, who was removed from power in a coup last week, had already acquired French nationality.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c74jnngr1e3o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:32:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese tourist dies in fall from Pantheon in Rome</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/japanese-tourist-dies-in-fall-from-pantheon-in-rome</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The 69-year-old man plunged 7 metres from an outer wall after becoming unwell and losing his balance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A Japanese tourist has died after falling from the outer wall of the Pantheon in Rome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The man, 69, had been sitting on the wall before he plunged 7 metres into the ancient landmark’s moat on Friday night, the Italian news agency, Ansa, reported.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/japanese-tourist-dies-in-fall-from-pantheon-in-rome"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/japanese-tourist-dies-in-fall-from-pantheon-in-rome</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:25:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At least four killed in Russian strikes overnight on Ukraine</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/russian-overnight-strikes-ukraine-zelenskyy-sanctions-oil</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Attacks come after Volodymyr Zelenskyy appeals to US for long-range missiles and urges allies to expand sanctions on Russian oil&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian missile and drone attacks on Ukraine overnight killed at least four people and wounded 17 others, local officials have said.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the capital, Kyiv, two people were killed and 13 wounded in a ballistic missile attack in the early hours of Saturday, Timur Tkachenko, head of Kyiv’s city military administration, said. Three of the wounded were hospitalised, according to Ukraine’s state emergency service.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/russian-overnight-strikes-ukraine-zelenskyy-sanctions-oil"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/russian-overnight-strikes-ukraine-zelenskyy-sanctions-oil</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:17:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Argentina goes to polls amid economic crisis and Trump ‘interference’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/argentina-president-javier-milei-polls-economic-crisis-trump</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Poor showing in Sunday’s election would deal hammer blow to country’s radical libertarian president, Javier Milei&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Argentina’s radical libertarian leader, Javier Milei, is facing a pivotal moment in his presidency with voters set to deliver their verdict on his two-year-old administration on Sunday against a backdrop of political and economic crisis and accusations that his ally Donald Trump is meddling in the country’s affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A poor showing in Sunday’s midterm election would be a hammer blow to Milei, who took power in December 2023 &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/dec/10/javier-milei-sworn-in-as-president-in-tipping-point-for-argentina"&gt;pledging&lt;/a&gt; to kickstart “a new era of peace and prosperity” by slashing spending and inflation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/argentina-president-javier-milei-polls-economic-crisis-trump"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/argentina-president-javier-milei-polls-economic-crisis-trump</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 11:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Japanese tourist falls to death at Pantheon in Italy</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8y529kl8yo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Local media reports the 69-year-old had been sitting on a wall when he lost his balance.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cp8y529kl8yo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:31:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Why Trump Turning on Putin Is a Good Thing: Finally, Peace Through Strength</title><link>https://medium.com/@billodonnel/why-trump-turning-on-putin-is-a-good-thing-finally-peace-through-strength-60c6bdcb8c64?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</link><description>&lt;div class="medium-feed-item"&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@billodonnel/why-trump-turning-on-putin-is-a-good-thing-finally-peace-through-strength-60c6bdcb8c64?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*2TdTK4WnjMZ5RYfgh8xQWA.jpeg" width="1024" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-snippet"&gt;For months, conservatives watched with unease as President Trump flirted with Vladimir Putin, dangling peace talks in Budapest and echoing&amp;#x2026;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-link"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@billodonnel/why-trump-turning-on-putin-is-a-good-thing-finally-peace-through-strength-60c6bdcb8c64?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;Continue reading on Medium »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@billodonnel/why-trump-turning-on-putin-is-a-good-thing-finally-peace-through-strength-60c6bdcb8c64?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:11:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he is open to meeting Kim Jong-un as he embarks on whirlwind Asia tour</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/trump-open-to-meeting-kim-jong-un-asia-tour-japan-korea-xi-jinping</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Trip will see him take part in high-stakes trade talks with Chinese leader Xi Jinping – but he also raised prospect of meeting North Korean leader&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-asia-tour-key-questions-xi-jinping-china-japan-south-korea-malaysia"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trump in Asia: five key questions as US president prepares for diplomatic tour&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump has set off for a tour of Asia where he is expected to take part in high-stakes trade talks with China’s leader, Xi Jinping – telling reporters he was also open to a meeting with the North Korean leader, Kim Jong-un.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trump, who left Washington on Friday night, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-asia-tour-key-questions-xi-jinping-china-japan-south-korea-malaysia"&gt;is set for a five-day trip&lt;/a&gt; to Malaysia, Japan and South Korea, his first visit to the region since taking office in January. He is due to arrive in Malaysia on Sunday morning local time.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/trump-open-to-meeting-kim-jong-un-asia-tour-japan-korea-xi-jinping"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/trump-open-to-meeting-kim-jong-un-asia-tour-japan-korea-xi-jinping</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 10:08:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>React vs. Backbone in 2025</title><link>https://backbonenotbad.hyperclay.com/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45702558"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://backbonenotbad.hyperclay.com/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 09:43:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says he wants to meet Kim Jong Un on Asia trip</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn09gg8v721o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US president says he has a "great relationship" with the North Korean leader and is "open" to a face-to-face chat.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn09gg8v721o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 09:10:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Y2K Kids Were the Last to Really Rage With No One Watching</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/25/arts/music/korn-nu-metal-rock-y2k.html</link><description>The angst of nu metal is being discovered by Gen Z, but with digital eyes always looming, the ephemeral catharsis of collectively going mad is a thing of the past.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/25/arts/music/korn-nu-metal-rock-y2k.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 09:00:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian Strikes On Ukraine Kill 4, Wound Around 20</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/25/russian-strikes-on-ukraine-kill-at-least-2-a90931</link><description>The attack comes as Kyiv's Western allies ratchet up pressure on Russia as the war enters its fourth winter.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/25/russian-strikes-on-ukraine-kill-at-least-2-a90931</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 08:05:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Colombia’s Managed Dependency: Why Petro’s Pursuit of Military Independence Is Still Out of Reach</title><link>https://medium.com/@jj.perezb/colombias-managed-dependency-why-petro-s-quest-for-military-sovereignty-remains-constrained-b3a625b33482?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</link><description>&lt;div class="medium-feed-item"&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-image"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@jj.perezb/colombias-managed-dependency-why-petro-s-quest-for-military-sovereignty-remains-constrained-b3a625b33482?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;&lt;img src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1920/1*refJqZxMI2gkHiCf-dBp4g.avif" width="1920" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-snippet"&gt;Gustavo Petro wants to achieve military independence. But after decades of U.S. aid and influence, that goal remains far reality. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p class="medium-feed-link"&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/@jj.perezb/colombias-managed-dependency-why-petro-s-quest-for-military-sovereignty-remains-constrained-b3a625b33482?source=rss------foreign_policy-5"&gt;Continue reading on Medium »&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/@jj.perezb/colombias-managed-dependency-why-petro-s-quest-for-military-sovereignty-remains-constrained-b3a625b33482?source=rss------foreign_policy-5</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:57:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At Least 4 Killed In Russian Strikes On Ukraine</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-missile-ukraine-kyiv-warehouse-fire/33570120.html</link><description>At least two people were killed and several were injured in Kyiv overnight after a wave of Russian ballistic missiles triggered powerful explosions and fires across the Ukrainian capital, city military authorities said on October 25.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-missile-ukraine-kyiv-warehouse-fire/33570120.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:55:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>At Least 4 Killed In Russian Strikes On Ukraine</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-missile-ukraine-kyiv-warehouse-fire/33570120.html</link><description>At least two people were killed and several were injured in Kyiv overnight after a wave of Russian ballistic missiles triggered powerful explosions and fires across the Ukrainian capital, city military authorities said on October 25.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/russia-missile-ukraine-kyiv-warehouse-fire/33570120.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:55:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In Ukraine, A Rare Moment Of Joy For Young Organ Recipients</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-children-organ-transplants/33567096.html</link><description>Ukrainian families recently gathered for a “Breakfast of Gratitude” with doctors who performed organ transplants on critically ill children. Some of the kids had endured life-saving surgeries just as air strikes were falling on Kyiv.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/ukraine-children-organ-transplants/33567096.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 07:10:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>