<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:48:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Donald Trump greeted by Emperor Naruhito in Japan before meeting new prime minister – US politics live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-japan-sanae-takaichi-asia-canada-trade-news-updates-us-politics-live</link><description>&lt;p&gt;First meeting between the US president and prime minister Takaichi will focus on trade as Trump continues his five-day Asia trip&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Indiana governor Mike Braun announced today that he is calling a special session to consider redrawing congressional districts in the state, the latest state to work on its maps ahead of 2026.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indiana is one of several Republican-led states that the Trump administration has pressured to undertake mid-decade redistricting to favor Republicans, which began with a push in Texas to redraw lines to add Republican seats.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-japan-sanae-takaichi-asia-canada-trade-news-updates-us-politics-live"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-japan-sanae-takaichi-asia-canada-trade-news-updates-us-politics-live</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:38:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Google’s Quantum Computer Makes a Big Technical Leap</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/22/technology/googles-quantum-computer-leap.html</link><description>Designed to accelerate advances in medicine and other fields, the tech giant’s quantum algorithm runs 13,000 times as fast as software written for a traditional supercomputer.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/22/technology/googles-quantum-computer-leap.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:35:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lithuanian PM says Belarus balloon incidents ‘call for united, resolute response,’ as it closes border with Russia’s ally – Europe live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/lithuania-airport-russia-belarus-viktor-orban-pope-leo-europe-live-news-updates</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Inga Ruginienė says ‘no hybrid attack will be tolerated’ and pledges to shoot down balloons after 66 objects spotted by radar overnight&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile over in the Czech Republic, &lt;strong&gt;the country’s president Petr Pavel has tasked the populist billionaire Andrej Babiš with leading talks on forming the new government after recent parliamentary election.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Babiš told the president – who defeated him in the 2023 presidential elections – that &lt;strong&gt;the coalition talks were already under way, and “promised to hand over the text of the coalition agreement and programme priorities” later this week&lt;/strong&gt;, according to &lt;a href="https://www.hrad.cz/cs/pro-media/tiskove-zpravy/aktualni-tiskove-zpravy/prezident-republiky-pozval-predsedu-hnuti-ano-andreje-babise-na-prazsky-hrad-18849"&gt;a readout&lt;/a&gt; issued by the presidential office.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/lithuania-airport-russia-belarus-viktor-orban-pope-leo-europe-live-news-updates"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/lithuania-airport-russia-belarus-viktor-orban-pope-leo-europe-live-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:33:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Minister insists government will get asylum seekers out of hotels and expects progress ‘within weeks’ - UK politics live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/27/asylum-hotel-report-steve-reed-wes-streeting-epping-offender-prison-news-updates-politics-live</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Housing secretary says purpose built ‘modular’ structures on sites like ex military bases is the answer to ending reliance on hotels&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Guardian would like to hear from parents who have had to live in temporary accommodation with children. There is more about the call-out here, including a form where you can submit a response.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;But the &lt;strong&gt;Commons home affairs committee&lt;/strong&gt;’s &lt;a href="https://committees.parliament.uk/publications/49900/documents/268016/default/"&gt;report &lt;/a&gt;is also critical of some aspects of what the Home Office has been doing on asylum hotels since Labour took power. Here are some of the points it makes about Labour’s record on this issue.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The committee expresses concerns about the government’s plan to move asylum seekers out of hotels and place them in “large sites” instead, such as former military bases.&lt;/strong&gt; (See&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/27/asylum-hotel-report-steve-reed-wes-streeting-epping-offender-prison-news-updates-politics-live?page=with%3Ablock-68ff25898f0837a8ea394310#block-68ff25898f0837a8ea394310"&gt; 9.23am&lt;/a&gt;.) It says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The [Home Office] is considering the use of large sites in its approach to asylum accommodation, having previously said it would move away from their use. In principle, large sites can provide suitable temporary accommodation. However, they have generally proved more costly to deliver than hotel accommodation and will not enable the department to drive down costs in the same way as expanding dispersal accommodation. If the department chooses to pursue large sites, it needs to fully understand and accept this trade off. It must learn the lessons from its previous mistakes in rushing to deliver short-term solutions that later unravel.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It says the government has still not set out a “clear strategy” for asylum accommodation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The government has committed to reducing the cost of the asylum system and ending the use of hotels by 2029. This is a stated Government priority, but making promises to appeal to popular sentiment without setting out a clear and fully articulated plan for securing alternative accommodation risks under-delivery and consequently undermining public trust still further. The Home Office has failed to share a clear strategy for the long-term delivery of asylum accommodation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It says the number of asylum seekers in hotels went up during Labour’s first 12 months in office.&lt;/strong&gt; It says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The number of asylum seekers in hotels is currently significantly lower than during the peak of hotel use—32,059 people as of June 2025, compared to 56,042 in September 2023—although the number of asylum seekers accommodated in hotels was 8% higher in June 2025 compared to June 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It says it is “extremely disappointing” that the Home Office abandoned a pilot programme giving refugees 56 days to find alternative accommodation if they have to leave Home Office housing (like a hotel) because their asylum application has been accepted. &lt;/strong&gt;The Home Office has reverted to 28 days’ notice, even though the 56 days’s notice system was said to reduce the number or refugees finding themselves homeless. It says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Given the high level of support we received for the 56 day move on period in the evidence we received, this decision is extremely disappointing.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/27/asylum-hotel-report-steve-reed-wes-streeting-epping-offender-prison-news-updates-politics-live"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/27/asylum-hotel-report-steve-reed-wes-streeting-epping-offender-prison-news-updates-politics-live</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:24:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Game-Changing Potential of Balcony Solar</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohdy9l/the_gamechanging_potential_of_balcony_solar/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohdy9l/the_gamechanging_potential_of_balcony_solar/"&gt; &lt;img alt="The Game-Changing Potential of Balcony Solar" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/2ppbABpvraQ6KXKDR3QzlcxD2mOtTVCARK7BZEpj1fc.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=2fdbc0702a1fcc96c524fba9e82a7298d6749ef5" title="The Game-Changing Potential of Balcony Solar" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Generalaverage89"&gt; /u/Generalaverage89 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://reasonstobecheerful.world/balcony-solar-renewables-technology-game-changing/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohdy9l/the_gamechanging_potential_of_balcony_solar/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohdy9l/the_gamechanging_potential_of_balcony_solar/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:08:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Moscow Court Jails Singer Monetochka in Absentia for Breaking ‘Foreign Agents’ Law</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/moscow-court-jails-singer-monetochka-in-absentia-for-breaking-foreign-agents-law-a90946</link><description>Monetochka left Russia shortly after the February 2022 invasion of Ukraine and continues to perform in exile.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/moscow-court-jails-singer-monetochka-in-absentia-for-breaking-foreign-agents-law-a90946</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:07:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How the Russian Orthodox Church Became a Weapon of Political Warfare</title><link>https://www.fpri.org/article/2025/10/how-the-russian-orthodox-church-became-a-weapon-of-political-warfare/</link><description>Bottom Line The Russian Orthodox Church (ROC) has become a central pillar of the Kremlin’s political and informational warfare strategy, which shapes narratives by fusing spirituality with nationalism. Through doctrines like the “Russian World” (Russkiy Mir) and appeals to shared Orthodox identity, Moscow weaponizes faith to justify aggression and extend [&amp;#8230;]</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.fpri.org/article/2025/10/how-the-russian-orthodox-church-became-a-weapon-of-political-warfare/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:03:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Weather tracker: Jamaica braces for its most powerful hurricane as Melissa reaches category 5</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/jamaica-powerful-hurricane-melissa-category-5-landfall-new-zealand-storm</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Record-breaking hurricane expected to make landfall on Tuesday with 160mph winds, while New Zealand reels from storm damage&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/hurricane-melissa-jamaica-cuba-caribbean-haiti-dominican-republic-live-news-latest-updates"&gt;Hurricane Melissa – follow latest updates live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Caribbean is &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/26/hurricane-melissa-strengthens-into-category-4-approaches-jamaica"&gt;bracing for Hurricane Melissa&lt;/a&gt;, one of the most powerful to ever strike the region. Melissa began as a cluster of thunderstorms off the coast of west Africa, which travelled west and developed into a depression, reaching tropical storm status to the north of Venezuela on 21 October. Rapid intensification over the weekend strengthened Melissa to category 4 as it slowly meandered west through the Caribbean Sea.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Melissa reached category 5 intensity on Monday morning with sustained winds of 160mph (257km/h). Melissa is forecast to take a turn to the north-east towards Jamaica on Monday afternoon, making landfall on Tuesday by about midday, maintaining it’s current strength, which would make it the strongest of only five hurricanes ever recorded to hit Jamaica directly.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/jamaica-powerful-hurricane-melissa-category-5-landfall-new-zealand-storm"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/jamaica-powerful-hurricane-melissa-category-5-landfall-new-zealand-storm</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:03:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lawsuits against banks with Epstein ties may shed new light on financier’s crimes</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/jeffrey-epstein-lawsuit-us-banks</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Experts say claim banks enabled Epstein will be difficult to prove but other outcomes could provide solace to victims&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For years, survivors of &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/jeffrey-epstein"&gt;Jeffrey Epstein&lt;/a&gt; have demanded justice. For a while, it seemed like they would get it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/ghislaine-maxwell"&gt;Ghislaine Maxwell,&lt;/a&gt; Epstein’s ex-girlfriend, was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2021/dec/29/ghislaine-maxwell-sex-trafficking-trial-verdict"&gt;found guilty&lt;/a&gt; of sex trafficking four years ago for her involvement in the late financier’s sexual abuse of teen girls – and &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2022/jun/28/ghislaine-maxwell-sentencing-sex-trafficking-epstein"&gt;sentenced&lt;/a&gt; to 20 years imprisonment.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/jeffrey-epstein-lawsuit-us-banks"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/jeffrey-epstein-lawsuit-us-banks</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 13:00:09 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Designating Antifa as a Foreign Terrorist Organization Could Threaten Civil Liberties</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/122643/antifa-threaten-civil-liberties/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=antifa-threaten-civil-liberties</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the Trump administration designates Antifa as an FTO, it could have implications extending beyond anti-fascist activists to the entire architecture of U.S. civil society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/122643/antifa-threaten-civil-liberties/"&gt;How Designating Antifa as a Foreign Terrorist Organization Could Threaten Civil Liberties&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/122643/antifa-threaten-civil-liberties/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=antifa-threaten-civil-liberties</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:59:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin Terminates Plutonium Disposal Agreement With U.S.</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/putin-terminates-plutonium-disposal-agreement-with-us-a90947</link><description>The agreement, which was already defunct, aimed to prevent both sides from building more nuclear weapons.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/putin-terminates-plutonium-disposal-agreement-with-us-a90947</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:54:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Efficiency gains from simple maintenance real world results</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohd9we/efficiency_gains_from_simple_maintenance_real/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Maximum_Mastodon_631"&gt; /u/Maximum_Mastodon_631 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/u_Maximum_Mastodon_631/comments/1ohd95h/efficiency_gains_from_simple_maintenance_real/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohd9we/efficiency_gains_from_simple_maintenance_real/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohd9we/efficiency_gains_from_simple_maintenance_real/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:39:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lithuania says it will shoot down smuggling balloons from Russia’s ally Belarus</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/lithuania-authorises-shooting-down-of-smuggling-balloons-from-belarus</link><description>&lt;p&gt;PM blames Alexander Lukashenko for not stopping ‘hybrid attacks’, which closed Vilnius airport four times last week&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/lithuania-airport-russia-belarus-viktor-orban-pope-leo-europe-live-news-updates"&gt;Europe live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lithuania’s prime minister has authorised the shooting down of smuggling balloons that cross the border from Russia’s ally Belarus, calling them “hybrid attacks” in an echo of the term used to describe Moscow’s destabilisation efforts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/weather-balloon-incursion-forces-lithuanias-biggest-airports-to-close"&gt;Incursions by balloons carrying contraband cigarettes&lt;/a&gt; prompted the Nato and EU member state to close Vilnius airport four times last week and shut its border crossings with Belarus temporarily.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/lithuania-authorises-shooting-down-of-smuggling-balloons-from-belarus"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/lithuania-authorises-shooting-down-of-smuggling-balloons-from-belarus</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:38:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia Grounds Siberian Airline Following Fatal Crash</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russia-grounds-siberian-airline-following-fatal-crash-a90945</link><description>Angara was one of the few airlines maintaining flights to isolated Siberian settlements where rail and road connections are limited or nonexistent.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russia-grounds-siberian-airline-following-fatal-crash-a90945</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:38:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Early Edition: October 27, 2025</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/123326/early-edition-october-27-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=early-edition-october-27-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Signup to receive the Early Edition in your inbox here. A curated guide to major news and developments over the weekend. Here’s today’s news: ISRAEL-HAMAS WAR – CEASEFIRE Egypt sent a team of experts to Gaza this weekend to help locate the bodies of deceased Israeli hostages, according to a spokesperson for Israeli Prime Minister [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/123326/early-edition-october-27-2025/"&gt;Early Edition: October 27, 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/123326/early-edition-october-27-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=early-edition-october-27-2025</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:32:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump ‘would love’ unconstitutional third term but rules out running for VP</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-third-term-vice-president</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Presidents are constitutionally limited to two elected terms but some had suggested unorthodox gambit to stay in office&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-japan-sanae-takaichi-asia-canada-trade-news-updates-us-politics-live"&gt;US politics – live updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; said on Monday morning that he would rule out running for the vice-presidency in the 2028 US election, an unorthodox approach that some of his supporters have floated to allow the Republican US president to serve a third term in the White House.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“I’d be allowed to do that,” Trump said, in an exchange with reporters aboard Air Force One while traveling from Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, to Tokyo, Japan, on Monday, the latest leg of a five-day trip to Asia which he hopes to cap with an agreement on a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/us-china-framework-trade-deal-xi-trump-meeting"&gt;trade war truce&lt;/a&gt; with the Chinese president, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/xi-jinping"&gt;Xi Jinping&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-third-term-vice-president"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/donald-trump-third-term-vice-president</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:23:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa could be strongest to ever hit Jamaica</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2dr0z57nygo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Melissa has been upgraded to a category five storm and could become Jamaica's strongest on record.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2dr0z57nygo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:19:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil and gas firm Petrofac files for administration, putting thousands of jobs at risk</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/27/oil-gas-petrofac-files-for-administration-jobs-north-sea</link><description>&lt;p&gt;North Sea contractor says move applies only to its ultimate holding company and it will continue to trade&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2025/oct/27/global-stocks-rally-us-china-trade-greencore-bakkavor-deal-uk-competition-business-live-news"&gt;Business live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Petrofac, one of the biggest North Sea oil and gas contractors, has filed for administration, putting more than 2,000 jobs in Scotland at risk.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The energy services provider said it had applied to the high court of England and Wales to appoint administrators, after it lost a big offshore wind project over its failure to meet contractual obligations.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/27/oil-gas-petrofac-files-for-administration-jobs-north-sea"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/27/oil-gas-petrofac-files-for-administration-jobs-north-sea</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:19:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Jack DeJohnette, versatile jazz drummer known for Miles Davis fusion recordings, dies aged 83</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/music/2025/oct/27/jack-dejohnette-versatile-jazz-drummer-miles-davis-fusion-dies-aged-83</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Drummer played on Bitches Brew and other landmark recordings, as well as making numerous albums as a bandleader&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jack DeJohnette, the jazz drummer celebrated as one of the genre’s true greats – who worked with stars including Miles Davis, Sonny Rollins and Charles Lloyd – has died aged 83. A press representative for ECM, the record label that released many of his recordings, confirmed the news, while his personal assistant added that he died from congestive heart failure.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Able to bring dynamic, highly musical playing to open-minded free jazz, R&amp;amp;B-leaning instrumental grooves and everything in between, DeJohnette is perhaps best known as the drummer in Davis’s fusion period, contributing to albums such as Bitches Brew, Jack Johnson and On the Corner. He was also celebrated as a regular sideman and bandleader on elegant, progressive fusion releases from ECM in the 1980s.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/music/2025/oct/27/jack-dejohnette-versatile-jazz-drummer-miles-davis-fusion-dies-aged-83"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/music/2025/oct/27/jack-dejohnette-versatile-jazz-drummer-miles-davis-fusion-dies-aged-83</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:18:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Red Cross accompanies Hamas in search for bodies of Israeli hostages in Gaza</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/red-cross-accompanies-hamas-in-search-for-bodies-of-israeli-hostages-in-gaza</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Exclusive: Red Cross acts as ‘neutral intermediary’ to recover hostages’ remains in areas under Israeli control&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The International Committee of the Red Cross (ICRC) accompanied members of Hamas inside areas of Gaza still under the control of the Israeli military to facilitate the search for the bodies of Israeli hostages, an official from the ICRC told the Guardian.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Under the US-brokered ceasefire, which took effect on 10 October, Hamas is required to return the remains of all Israeli hostages as soon as possible. In exchange, Israel has agreed to hand over 15 Palestinian bodies for each Israeli.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/red-cross-accompanies-hamas-in-search-for-bodies-of-israeli-hostages-in-gaza"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/red-cross-accompanies-hamas-in-search-for-bodies-of-israeli-hostages-in-gaza</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:14:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump cuts likely hindered warning process for Alaska storm that displaced hundreds, experts say</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/alaska-storm-emergency-response-trump-cuts</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Reductions in weather balloon launches could have degraded forecasts that residents depend on to prepare&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A faltering federal response to one of the worst storms in &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/alaska"&gt;Alaska&lt;/a&gt;’s history, which caused hundreds of people to become homeless, is drawing further scrutiny over the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt;’s efforts to dismantle federal weather and climate protections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/15/alaska-typhoon-halong-aftermath"&gt;The powerful remnants of Typhoon Halong hit remote communities&lt;/a&gt; in the Yukon-Kuskokwim delta of south-west Alaska on 12 October, inundating a vast low-lying area of tundra that is home to some of the most remote and inaccessible communities in the country.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/alaska-storm-emergency-response-trump-cuts"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/alaska-storm-emergency-response-trump-cuts</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:40 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How are data centers plugging into our electrical grid — and could this cause another major blackout like 2005?</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohch1w/how_are_data_centers_plugging_into_our_electrical/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/IronChefOfForensics"&gt; /u/IronChefOfForensics &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ask/comments/1ohcgt8/how_are_data_centers_plugging_into_our_electrical/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohch1w/how_are_data_centers_plugging_into_our_electrical/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ohch1w/how_are_data_centers_plugging_into_our_electrical/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Artifact (YC W25) is hiring engineers in NYC to build modern ECAD</title><link>https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719996</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719996"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719996</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 12:00:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trial begins for 10 accused of sexist cyber-bullying of Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce3knel0895o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The defendants are accused of spreading unsubstantiated claims over Mrs Macron's gender and sexuality.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/ce3knel0895o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:59:48 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Putin To Meet North Korean Foreign Minister in Moscow</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/putin-to-meet-north-korean-foreign-minister-in-moscow-a90944</link><description>The visit comes just after North Korean leader Kim Jong Un pledged to advance military ties with Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/putin-to-meet-north-korean-foreign-minister-in-moscow-a90944</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:57:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UN peacekeeping force in Lebanon shoots down Israeli drone</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjw9n1d7njyo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Unfil says the drone flew over a patrol in an "aggressive manner", but the Israeli military says it was gathering intelligence and posed no threat.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjw9n1d7njyo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:55:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>World’s oldest serving head of state declared winner in Cameroon election</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/cameroon-paul-biya-oldest-serving-head-of-state-declared-winner-in-election</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Paul Biya, 92, said to have won 53.66% of vote after volatile two weeks since election, when opponent claimed victory&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paul Biya, the world’s oldest serving head of state, has been declared the winner of Cameroon’s election, granting him an eighth term that could keep him in office until he is nearly 100.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The country’s constitutional council said Biya won 53.66% of the vote, while his former ally turned challenger, Issa Tchiroma Bakary, got 35.19%.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/cameroon-paul-biya-oldest-serving-head-of-state-declared-winner-in-election"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/cameroon-paul-biya-oldest-serving-head-of-state-declared-winner-in-election</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:53:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Overnight Drone Barrage Targets Moscow And Western Russia</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/western-russia-drone-moscow-attack/33571542.html</link><description>A large overnight drone strike on October 27 hit several regions in western Russia, including the Moscow area, according to Russian officials.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/western-russia-drone-moscow-attack/33571542.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:46:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian Energy Minister Blames ‘Panic Buying’ for Summer Fuel Price Spike</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russias-energy-minister-blames-panic-buying-for-summer-fuel-price-spike-a90942</link><description>“Messages about temporary shutdowns at some facilities also fueled panic buying and a jump in exchange prices,” Tsivilyov said.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russias-energy-minister-blames-panic-buying-for-summer-fuel-price-spike-a90942</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:42:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US and China agree ‘framework’ for trade deal ahead of Xi-Trump meeting | First Thing</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/first-thing-us-and-china-agree-framework-for-trade-deal-ahead-of-xi-trump-meeting</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US treasury secretary anticipates tariff truce with China will be extended, and that Beijing will revive substantial purchases of US soybeans. Plus, is Wikipedia’s Jimmy Wales the last decent tech baron?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/info/2018/sep/17/guardian-us-morning-briefing-sign-up-to-stay-informed"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t already get First Thing in your inbox? Sign up here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US and China have &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/us-china-framework-trade-deal-xi-trump-meeting"&gt;agreed a framework for a trade deal&lt;/a&gt; only days before Donald Trump and the Chinese president, Xi Jinping, are due to meet.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about other trade deals that are still up in the air?&lt;/strong&gt; There were hopes of a truce between the US and Brazil after what President Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva described as a positive meeting with Trump in Malaysia. He said their respective teams would start discussing tariffs and other matters “immediately”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;And Canada?&lt;/strong&gt; Trump said Saturday that he would &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/25/trump-tariffs-canada-ronald-reagan"&gt;raise US tariffs by 10%&lt;/a&gt; in retaliation for an &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-canada-trade-negotations-ontario-tariffs"&gt;advertisement&lt;/a&gt; sponsored by the Ontario government that accurately quoted Ronald Reagan at length saying tariffs don’t work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How many people have been killed in the airstrikes?&lt;/strong&gt; US forces in recent weeks have carried out at least eight strikes against boats in the Caribbean off Venezuela’s coast, killing about 40 people that the Trump administration has insisted were involved in smuggling drugs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/first-thing-us-and-china-agree-framework-for-trade-deal-ahead-of-xi-trump-meeting"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/27/first-thing-us-and-china-agree-framework-for-trade-deal-ahead-of-xi-trump-meeting</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:40:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump describes Russia’s new cruise missile test as ‘not appropriate’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/russia-cruise-missile-test-trump-putin</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US president says Vladimir Putin should focus on ending war with Ukraine rather than testing missiles&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/lithuania-airport-russia-belarus-viktor-orban-pope-leo-europe-live-news-updates"&gt;Europe live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump has described Vladimir Putin’s announcement of a nuclear-powered cruise missile test as “not appropriate” amid growing tensions between Moscow and Washington.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Putin said on Sunday that Russia had successfully tested its “unique” nuclear-capable Burevestnik cruise missile, which the Kremlin described as part of efforts to “ensure the country’s national security”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/russia-cruise-missile-test-trump-putin"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/russia-cruise-missile-test-trump-putin</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:36:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>You are how you act</title><link>https://boz.com/articles/you-are-how-you-act</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719788"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://boz.com/articles/you-are-how-you-act</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:35:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Kaye Adams says her name was ‘dragged through the mud’ after BBC Scotland suspension</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/kaye-adams-name-dragged-through-mud-bbc-scotland-suspension</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Radio host removed from morning show after what broadcaster reported as ‘a conduct complaint’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The award-winning broadcaster Kaye Adams has spoken of her distress after she was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/kaye-adams-yet-to-hear-complaint-two-weeks-after-being-taken-off-bbc-radio-scotland"&gt;taken off air&lt;/a&gt; by BBC Radio Scotland as a result of an unspecified “conduct complaint”, resulting in relentless media speculation.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In her first public comment on the matter, Adams said: “After three of the most distressing weeks of my professional life and seeing my previously untarnished name publicly dragged through the mud, BBC Scotland has still not provided me with any details of the allegations which have been made against me.”&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/kaye-adams-name-dragged-through-mud-bbc-scotland-suspension"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/kaye-adams-name-dragged-through-mud-bbc-scotland-suspension</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:32:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Javier Milei hails ‘tipping point’ as his far-right party wins Argentina’s midterm elections</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/javier-milei-president-far-right-party-wins-argentina-midterm-elections</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Result falls short of giving Milei a congressional majority but surprises many analysts after series of scandals&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The party of Argentina’s far-right president, Javier Milei, has won Sunday’s midterm elections after a campaign in which &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/25/argentina-president-javier-milei-polls-economic-crisis-trump"&gt;Donald Trump announced a $40bn bailout&lt;/a&gt; for the country and made continued aid &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/14/trump-threatens-to-cut-us-aid-to-argentina-if-milei-loses-election"&gt;conditional on the victory&lt;/a&gt; of his Argentinian counterpart.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With more than 99% of ballots counted, La Libertad Avanza secured 40.8% of the nationwide vote, in an election widely seen as a de facto referendum on the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2023/nov/20/who-is-javier-milei-argentina-new-president-far-right-what-does-he-stand-for"&gt;self-styled anarcho-capitalist’s&lt;/a&gt; nearly two years in power. The Peronist opposition, Fuerza Patria, secured 31.7%.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/javier-milei-president-far-right-party-wins-argentina-midterm-elections"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/javier-milei-president-far-right-party-wins-argentina-midterm-elections</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:29:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Microsoft needs to open up more about its OpenAI dealings</title><link>https://www.wsj.com/tech/ai/microsoft-needs-to-open-up-more-about-its-openai-dealings-59102de8</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719669"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.wsj.com/tech/ai/microsoft-needs-to-open-up-more-about-its-openai-dealings-59102de8</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 11:19:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lithuania Closes Border With Belarus Over Repeated Balloon Incursions</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/lithuania-closes-border-with-belarus-over-repeated-balloon-incursions-a90938</link><description>Last week, more than 170 flights were disrupted, affecting almost 30,000 passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/lithuania-closes-border-with-belarus-over-repeated-balloon-incursions-a90938</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:40:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ten people go on trial in Paris for online harassment of Brigitte Macron</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/trial-paris-brigitte-macron-online-harassment-jean-michel-trogneux</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Trial is latest phase in legal battle against false claim that French first lady is a man named Jean-Michel Trogneux&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ten people are to go on trial in Paris on Monday for online harassment of Brigitte Macron – the latest phase in a legal battle on both sides of the Atlantic against the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/jul/26/emmanuel-brigitte-macron-candace-owens-conspiracy-theory-jean-michel-trogneux"&gt;false claim&lt;/a&gt; that the French first lady is a man named Jean-Michel Trogneux.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French trial comes after the president, Emmanuel Macron, and his wife filed a defamation lawsuit in the US at the end of July, in connection with a rumour amplified and repeated online that Brigitte Macron was born a man.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/trial-paris-brigitte-macron-online-harassment-jean-michel-trogneux"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/trial-paris-brigitte-macron-online-harassment-jean-michel-trogneux</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:23:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Saudi Arabia, Rich With Oil, Wants to Be Known as the A.I. Exporter</title><link>https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/27/technology/saudi-arabia-ai-exporter.html</link><description>The kingdom is pouring money into data centers and working with U.S. and Chinese tech giants, landing its A.I. ambitions in the middle of a geopolitical tussle for tech power.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.nytimes.com/2025/10/27/technology/saudi-arabia-ai-exporter.html</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:23:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Man arrested on suspicion of racially aggravated rape in Walsall</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/man-arrested-racially-aggravated-rape-walsall</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Suspect, 32, apprehended in Birmingham after urgent appeal by police over alleged incident on Saturday&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A man has been arrested on suspicion of rape after police believe a woman was the victim of a racially aggravated attack.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;West Midlands police were called to the Park Hall area of Walsall just after 7.15pm on Saturday after a woman was reported to be distressed in the street.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/man-arrested-racially-aggravated-rape-walsall"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/27/man-arrested-racially-aggravated-rape-walsall</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:20:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hurricane Melissa strengthens to category 5 as evacuations ordered in Jamaica’s capital</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/26/hurricane-melissa-strengthens-into-category-4-approaches-jamaica</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Storm could intensify further, threatening to cause catastrophic flooding in northern Caribbean&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;• &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/27/hurricane-melissa-jamaica-cuba-caribbean-haiti-dominican-republic-live-news-latest-updates"&gt;Hurricane Melissa – follow latest updates live&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Melissa strengthened into a powerful category 5 hurricane on Monday, threatening days of catastrophic winds and rain in the northern Caribbean, while Jamaica’s government ordered mandatory evacuations for vulnerable areas across the country including in the capital, Kingston.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Jamaican officials had earlier urged those in low-lying and flood-prone areas to seek refuge as Melissa rapidly climbs up the &lt;a href="https://www.weather.gov/mfl/saffirsimpson"&gt;Saffir-Simpson hurricane wind scale&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/26/hurricane-melissa-strengthens-into-category-4-approaches-jamaica"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/26/hurricane-melissa-strengthens-into-category-4-approaches-jamaica</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:05:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Don't forget these tags to make HTML work like you expect</title><link>https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2025/dont-forget-these-html-tags/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719140"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.jim-nielsen.com/2025/dont-forget-these-html-tags/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:01:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Night-flying insects over UK in decline, weather radar study reveals</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/night-flying-insects-over-uk-in-decline-weather-radar-study-reveals</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Study of Met Office data one of first to show how nocturnal insects affected by factors such as light pollution&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Scientists have used Met Office radar data to track the trillions of insects flying above the UK for the first time, revealing a concerning decline in nocturnal species.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The team repurposed data from the UK’s network of 15 weather surveillance radars, which scan the sky hundreds of times a day.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/night-flying-insects-over-uk-in-decline-weather-radar-study-reveals"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/oct/27/night-flying-insects-over-uk-in-decline-weather-radar-study-reveals</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 10:00:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump's Ukraine Peace Stance ‘Radically’ Shifted Since Alaska Summit, Lavrov Says</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/trumps-ukraine-peace-stance-radically-shifted-since-alaska-summit-lavrov-says-a90936</link><description>Lavrov accused Europeans and Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelensky of exerting pressure on Washington to block any U.S.-Russia cooperation.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/trumps-ukraine-peace-stance-radically-shifted-since-alaska-summit-lavrov-says-a90936</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:53:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>UN pleads for safe passage for civilians trapped in war-hit Sudan city</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gw8w73lngo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The fall of el-Fasher would cement the RSF's control of the west and reinforces a de facto split in the nation.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gw8w73lngo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:52:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Grave fears for civilians after Sudanese paramilitary claims capture of El Fasher</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/fears-civilians-sudan-paramilitary-rsf-capture-el-fasher</link><description>&lt;p&gt;RSF says it has seized control of army’s main base in Darfur, home to famine-stricken displacement camp&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fears are growing for hundreds of thousands of civilians trapped in El Fasher, Sudan, after the paramilitary Rapid Support Forces said it had captured the city, which it has been besieging for more than a year in the country’s civil war.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The group said on Sunday that it had seized control of the army’s main base in the city in Darfur, where &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/article/2024/aug/01/sudan-el-fasher-darfur-famine-starvation-declared-fews-net"&gt;famine was declared&lt;/a&gt; in a displacement camp last year. It then released a statement saying it had “extended control over the city of El Fasher from the grip of mercenaries and militias”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/fears-civilians-sudan-paramilitary-rsf-capture-el-fasher"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/fears-civilians-sudan-paramilitary-rsf-capture-el-fasher</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:47:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rust cross-platform GPUI components</title><link>https://github.com/longbridge/gpui-component</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45719004"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/longbridge/gpui-component</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:44:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>WorldGrow: Generating Infinite 3D World</title><link>https://github.com/world-grow/WorldGrow</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45718908"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/world-grow/WorldGrow</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:31:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Argentina's Milei wins big in midterms with 'chainsaw' austerity</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gw8qpyvqdo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Milei's radical spending cuts have won favour with Donald Trump, but also attracted widespread criticism.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gw8qpyvqdo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:30:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia Says It Downed 193 Ukrainian Drones Overnight</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russia-says-it-downed-193-ukrainian-drones-overnight-a90937</link><description>Bryansk Governor Aleksandr Bogomaz said that a minibus had been struck in the village of Pogar, killing the driver and injuring five passengers.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/27/russia-says-it-downed-193-ukrainian-drones-overnight-a90937</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 09:29:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Open hostility has become normalised’: Dutch Muslims fear rise of far right as general election looms</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/geert-wilders-netherlands-dutch-muslims-fear-rise-of-far-right</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The poll is seen as a litmus test for the Netherlands and its democratic ideals, as activists decry a hardening of political discourse driven by Geert Wilders&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://x.com/geertwilderspvv/status/1952327110674313471?s=46&amp;amp;t=TgIN1rYSc6FWv2PjbytaHw"&gt;drawing depicted two women&lt;/a&gt;; a young blonde with a friendly expression and a scowling older woman wearing a headscarf. On top of the image was a nod to this month’s general election in the Netherlands, along with the phrase “The choice is yours.”&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The social media post, made by the far-right, anti-Muslim politician Geert Wilders, prompted a record 14,000 complaints to the country’s anti-discrimination hotline. “Many of those who called to report the image compared it to Nazi propaganda from the second world war,” the hotline &lt;a href="https://discriminatie.nl/blog/discriminatie-nl-neemt-actie-en-doet-aangifte-tegen-wilders/"&gt;said in a statement, &lt;/a&gt;adding that the 19 anti-discrimination agencies associated with the hotline had flagged the post to police, amid concerns that it could be an incitement to hatred.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/geert-wilders-netherlands-dutch-muslims-fear-rise-of-far-right"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/27/geert-wilders-netherlands-dutch-muslims-fear-rise-of-far-right</guid><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 08:53:04 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>