<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:58:47 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Woman gets rare whole-life sentence for murder of French schoolgirl</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjr07wqeerwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Dahbia Benkired is the first woman in France to receive a full life term following the shocking crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjr07wqeerwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:45:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Satellite images shows extent of demolition at the White House</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/c4gkrnn4892o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>New satellite images show the White House East Wing has been completely demolished in order to make way for President Trump's ballroom.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/videos/c4gkrnn4892o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:39:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Schumer says Democrats will force vote to overturn Canada tariffs as Carney says nation ‘stands ready’ to continue US trade talks – live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/24/donald-trump-trade-negotiations-canada-mark-carney-terminated-tariff-letitia-james-new-york-us-politics-live-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Democratic leader calls Canada tariffs ‘damaging’ and vows effort to overturn them; Canadian prime minister says he wants to see progress on trade negotiations&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-canada-trade-negotations-ontario-tariffs"&gt;US and Canada spar over anti-Trump tariff ad that suspended trade talks&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The US secretary of state has confirmed Donald Trump’s announcement that all trade negotiations with Canada have been suspended.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Marco Rubio spoke during a visit to a civil-military coordination centre in southern Israel.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/24/donald-trump-trade-negotiations-canada-mark-carney-terminated-tariff-letitia-james-new-york-us-politics-live-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/24/donald-trump-trade-negotiations-canada-mark-carney-terminated-tariff-letitia-james-new-york-us-politics-live-news</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:34:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine allies pledge to take Russian oil and gas off global market</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c17p54edxljo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>A "coalition of the willing" meeting in London seeks to increase pressure on Russia to end its war in Ukraine.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c17p54edxljo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:28:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US airstrike on ‘drug boat’ kills six as aircraft carrier sent to South America</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/us-military-strike-alleged-drug-boat-caribbean</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Pete Hegseth claims six ‘narco-terrorists’ killed in Caribbean as US military conducts 10th strike &lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/24/donald-trump-trade-negotiations-canada-mark-carney-terminated-tariff-letitia-james-new-york-us-politics-live-news"&gt;US politics live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States has carried out another military strike against a boat it claims was carrying illegal drugs in the Caribbean, killing six people onboard, the Pentagon chief, Pete Hegseth, said on Friday morning.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Later on Friday, the Pentagon &lt;a href="https://x.com/SeanParnellASW/status/1981759934539985132"&gt;said&lt;/a&gt; that an aircraft carrier was being moved to waters off South America, as part of the administration’s stated campaign to combat drug trafficking.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/us-military-strike-alleged-drug-boat-caribbean"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/us-military-strike-alleged-drug-boat-caribbean</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:10:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>It’s (Still) Henry Kissinger’s World</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/henry-kissinger-pbs-documentary-review/</link><description>A new documentary argues Nixon’s secretary of state learned the wrong lessons from his experiences with Nazi Germany.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/henry-kissinger-pbs-documentary-review/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 18:00:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sex offender who sparked UK asylum hotel protests released by mistake</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/sex-offender-who-sparked-uk-asylum-hotel-protests-released-by-mistake</link><description>&lt;p&gt;David Lammy said to be furious after Hadush Gerberslasie Kebatu, who was meant to go to an immigration detention centre to be deported, was accidentally freed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former asylum seeker who sparked nationwide protests after sexually assaulting a woman and a 14-year-old girl near an asylum hotel in Epping has been accidentally released from prison, sparking a police manhunt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ethiopian national Hadush Gerberslasie Kebatu was jailed for 12 months in September for sexual assault and made the subject of a five-year sexual harm prevention order.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/sex-offender-who-sparked-uk-asylum-hotel-protests-released-by-mistake"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/sex-offender-who-sparked-uk-asylum-hotel-protests-released-by-mistake</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:59:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Local election wipeout would see off Starmer, MPs say after Caerphilly rout</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/labour-mps-keir-starmer-would-not-survive-local-elections-wipeout</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Crushing defeat in Welsh byelection triggers renewed outpouring of anger and concern within Labour&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A wipeout for Labour in next May’s local elections would spell the end of Keir Starmer’s premiership, MPs have said, after the party suffered a crushing defeat in its traditional heartland in Wales.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Though &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/plaid-cymru-wins-caerphilly-byelection-result"&gt;Plaid Cymru beat Reform UK&lt;/a&gt; to capture the Senedd seat in Caerphilly, the result highlighted a striking collapse of Labour’s vote, prompting fears in Westminster that Labour could be reduced to third place in Wales, a loss that would leave the leader’s position unrecoverable.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/labour-mps-keir-starmer-would-not-survive-local-elections-wipeout"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/labour-mps-keir-starmer-would-not-survive-local-elections-wipeout</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:59:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hakeem Jeffries endorses Zohran Mamdani for New York City mayor</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/zohran-mamdani-hakeem-jeffries-endorsement</link><description>&lt;p&gt;US House minority leader ends four-month standoff that had left Democratic nominee without powerful backing&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;House minority leader &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/hakeem-jeffries"&gt;Hakeem Jeffries&lt;/a&gt; said on Friday that he is endorsing &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/zohran-mamdani"&gt;Zohran Mamdani&lt;/a&gt; for New York City mayor, ending a four-month standoff that left the Democratic nominee without the backing of one of the party’s most powerful figures until the day before early voting begins.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The announcement arrives after months of pressure from progressives in Congress and after the top Democrat has been repeatedly grilled by reporters about his reluctance to support his party’s candidate.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/zohran-mamdani-hakeem-jeffries-endorsement"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/zohran-mamdani-hakeem-jeffries-endorsement</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:55:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Prince Andrew under pressure to vacate Royal Lodge as negotiations ramp up, say reports</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/prince-andrew-royal-lodge</link><description>&lt;p&gt;King Charles’ aides reportedly in daily talks over prince’s home which has come under increased scrutiny this week&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prince Andrew is reportedly in advanced talks with King Charles’s senior aides over moving out of his &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/21/royal-lodge-or-mini-palace-the-30-room-house-caught-up-in-the-prince-andrew-scandal"&gt;Royal Lodge&lt;/a&gt; home after a week in which his “peppercorn” rent tenancy has come under scrutiny.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Pressure has mounted on the royal family for Andrew to vacate the 30-room mansion in Windsor Great Park amid the continuing controversy over his links to sex offender Jeffrey Epstein, and the posthumous publication of the memoirs of the prince’s sexual assault accuser Virginia Giuffre.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/prince-andrew-royal-lodge"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/prince-andrew-royal-lodge</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:53:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Ukraine’s future is our future’, says Starmer, as he vows coalition will take Russian oil and gas off market to choke funding – as it happened</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/24/volodmyr-zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-vladimir-putin-sanctions-keir-starmer-coalition-of-the-willing-military-support-europe-live-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy, Starmer and members of ‘coalition of willing’ held talks in London. This live blog is closed&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-london-meeting-european-leaders"&gt;Ukraine wants US to stay involved, says Zelenskyy after meeting western allies&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;A forthcoming trip by German foreign minister, &lt;strong&gt;Johann Wadephul,&lt;/strong&gt; to China has been cancelled amid growing fears that Beijing’s restriction on semiconductor and rare earth exports could paralyse the country’s car industry.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“We are postponing the journey to a later time,” the spokesperson told a regular press briefing on Friday. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
 “The Chinese side was ultimately able to confirm only the appointment with the Chinese foreign minister, and could not confirm any other additional appointments,” a foreign ministry spokesperson said.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/24/volodmyr-zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-vladimir-putin-sanctions-keir-starmer-coalition-of-the-willing-military-support-europe-live-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/24/volodmyr-zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-vladimir-putin-sanctions-keir-starmer-coalition-of-the-willing-military-support-europe-live-news</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:49:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine wants US to stay involved, says Zelenskyy after meeting western allies</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-london-meeting-european-leaders</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ukrainian leader joined ‘coalition of the willing’ to discuss how to ramp up pressure on Russia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Volodymyr Zelenskyy said Ukraine wants the US to stay involved in efforts to end the war after a meeting of western allies in London that took place without president Donald Trump.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukrainian leader chose not to overtly lobby for the supply of US Tomahawk cruise missiles at a meeting of more than 20 mainly European leaders from the “coalition of the willing” but instead emphasised the need for the west to work together.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-london-meeting-european-leaders"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/zelenskyy-ukraine-russia-london-meeting-european-leaders</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:42:38 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Virginia Democrats aim to redraw maps to help party gain seats in Congress</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/virginia-redistrict-maps-democrats</link><description>&lt;p&gt;State becomes second to attempt to redistrict to benefit Democrats in response to Republicans’ efforts to gain seats&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/oct/24/donald-trump-trade-negotiations-canada-mark-carney-terminated-tariff-letitia-james-new-york-us-politics-live-news"&gt;US politics live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/virginia"&gt;Virginia&lt;/a&gt; has entered the national mid-cycle redistricting battle, with Democratic state lawmakers intent on redrawing the state’s congressional maps to deliver two or three additional Democrats to Washington.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Virginia currently has a 6-5 split in its delegation, favoring Democrats by one member. Don Scott, the Democratic Virginia house speaker, sent a letter on Thursday to members alerting them to a reconvening of a special session to consider legislation. The letter does not explicitly state that redistricting is on the agenda, but national organizations said they had been informed that this is the case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/virginia-redistrict-maps-democrats"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/virginia-redistrict-maps-democrats</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:37:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rishi Sunak only politician to see witness statement in China spy case</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/rishi-sunak-only-politician-see-witness-statement-china-spy-case</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Statement from security adviser, viewed by then prime minister, did not describe China as enemy &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rishi Sunak was the only politician to see a &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/16/china-spy-row-what-do-the-witness-statements-say-and-what-is-their-significance"&gt;witness statement&lt;/a&gt; by the deputy national security adviser at the centre of a controversy about the collapse of a case against two British men accused of spying for China.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to letters sent to the joint committee on the national security strategy, the statement from Matthew Collins in December 2023, which was seen by the then prime minister and his advisers, did not describe China as an enemy, another key element of the case.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/rishi-sunak-only-politician-see-witness-statement-china-spy-case"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/2025/oct/24/rishi-sunak-only-politician-see-witness-statement-china-spy-case</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:26:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Warsaw Ghetto survivor who resisted the Nazis dies</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgkzg5zmmp8o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Michael Smuss, an artist who helped make petrol bombs during the uprising, died in Israel aged 99.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cgkzg5zmmp8o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:19:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US investigates Tesla’s ‘Mad Max’ high-speed driver assistance mode</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/oct/24/tesla-mad-max-driver-assistance-investigation</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Some drivers say vehicles using new version of full self-driving system can travel above speed limits&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The US main transportation safety regulator said on Friday it is seeking information from &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/tesla"&gt;Tesla&lt;/a&gt; about a new driver assistance mode dubbed “Mad Max” that operates at higher speeds than other versions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some drivers on social media report that Tesla vehicles using the more aggressive version of its full &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/jun/29/elon-musk-tesla-robotaxi"&gt;self-driving (FSD) system&lt;/a&gt; could operate above posted speed limits.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/oct/24/tesla-mad-max-driver-assistance-investigation"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/technology/2025/oct/24/tesla-mad-max-driver-assistance-investigation</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:16:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>French biathlon star Julia Simon found guilty of theft and credit card fraud</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/24/french-biathlon-julia-simon-hearing-albertville</link><description>&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simon handed three-month suspended sentence and fine&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Olympic medallist admitted using teammate’s bank card&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The French biathlete Julia Simon was found guilty of theft and credit card fraud and handed a three-month suspended prison sentence by a French court on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simon was accused of repeatedly using the bank card of her France teammate, Justine Braisaz-Bouchet, and that of a French team staff member to make online purchases totalling more than €2,000 (£1,371).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/24/french-biathlon-julia-simon-hearing-albertville"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/sport/2025/oct/24/french-biathlon-julia-simon-hearing-albertville</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:08:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump’s Anti-Worker Foreign Policy</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/trump-labor-workers-rights-usaid-wages/</link><description>By cutting U.S. support for labor rights around the globe, Washington is hurting workers at home and abroad.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/trump-labor-workers-rights-usaid-wages/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 17:01:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>AI-Optimized Renewable Systems Market to Reach USD 5.5 Billion by 2035, Growing at 29.1% CAGR</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of30lq/aioptimized_renewable_systems_market_to_reach_usd/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to recent analysis, the global &lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/reports/ai-optimized-renewable-systems-market-33920"&gt;AI-optimized renewable systems market&lt;/a&gt; is expected to grow from USD 0.4 Billion in 2024 to USD 5.5 Billion by 2035, registering a robust CAGR of 29.1% during the forecast period. The combination of developing AI innovations, extending smart grid developments, and increasing spending on autonomous energy management is driving the AI-optimized renewable systems market into a growth phase that it has not seen before. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;AI can improve grid forecasting, load balancing performance, and variable renewable integration including solar, wind, and battery storage which is completely transforming energy ecosystems around the world. By 2025, companies such as Schneider Electric launched microgrid controllers that were powered by AI; GE Vernova employed predictive maintenance platforms across their fleet of wind systems; and IBM developed real-time energy demand optimization algorithms.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/press-releases/ai-optimized-renewable-systems-market-33920"&gt;Get the Detailed Industry Analysis (including the Table of Contents, List of Figures, and List of Tables) - from the AI-Optimized Renewable Systems Market Research Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Key players in the global AI-optimized renewable systems market include prominent companies such as ABB Ltd., Alpiq Group, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Atos SE, Avathon, Dexter Energy, &lt;a href="http://EnSights.ai"&gt;EnSights.ai&lt;/a&gt;, FlexGen Power Systems, General Electric (GE Vernova), Google (Elementl Power Partnership), IBM Corporation, Kraken Technologies, Microsoft Corporation, NextEra Energy, Schneider Electric, Siemens AG, Stem, Inc., Terabase Energy, Univers (Envision Group), UrbanChain, and other key players.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Recent Development and Strategic Overview: &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In March 2025, Amazon Web Services (AWS) has introduced its new AI-optimized renewable systems platform, designed for utility-scale solar and wind farms. This platform combines AI-based predictive analytics with real-time grid management tools to maximize energy production and maintain grid reliability. With scalable cloud infrastructure and improved security features, AWS's solution enables energy producers to minimize operating expenses and increase sustainability, while facilitating clean energy uptake in markets around the world. &lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;In April 2025, IBM Corporation announced its future-ready AI-optimized renewable systems suite designed for hybrid renewable plants and energy storage integration. The suite incorporates machine learning algorithms to enhance asset utilization and reduce asset downtime through accurate demand forecasting and predictive maintenance. In addition to these capabilities, IBM's suite provides easy integration with existing grid management systems, enabling industrial and utility customers everywhere to speed their shift to resilient, low-carbon, decentralized energy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Get the Detailed Industry Analysis (including the Table of Contents, List of Figures, and List of Tables) - from the&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co/press-releases/ai-optimized-renewable-systems-market-33920"&gt;AI-Optimized Renewable Systems Market&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Report Objectives:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;ul&gt; &lt;li&gt;Forecast market valuation across key segments and regions&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Identify growth drivers, challenges, and emerging opportunities&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Conduct in-depth micro and macro market trend analysis&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Evaluate competitive positioning and market entry strategies&lt;/li&gt; &lt;li&gt;Recommend actionable insights for stakeholders and investors&lt;/li&gt; &lt;/ul&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Contact:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Mr. Debashish Roy&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MarketGenics India Pvt. Ltd.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;800 N King Street, Suite 304 #4208, Wilmington, DE 19801, United States&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;USA: +1 (302) 303-2617&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Email: [&lt;a href="mailto:sales@marketgenics.co"&gt;sales@marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;](mailto:&lt;a href="mailto:sales@marketgenics.co"&gt;sales@marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a href="https://marketgenics.co"&gt;https://marketgenics.co&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Us&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;MarketGenics is a global market research and management consulting company empowering decision makers across healthcare, technology, and policy domains. Our mission is to deliver &lt;strong&gt;granular market intelligence combined with strategic foresight&lt;/strong&gt; to accelerate sustainable growth.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;We support clients across strategy development, product innovation, healthcare infrastructure, and digital transformation.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/InevitableWalrus6253"&gt; /u/InevitableWalrus6253 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of30lq/aioptimized_renewable_systems_market_to_reach_usd/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of30lq/aioptimized_renewable_systems_market_to_reach_usd/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of30lq/aioptimized_renewable_systems_market_to_reach_usd/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:53:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestinian factions say they agree to let independent technocrat committee run Gaza</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/palestinian-factions-say-they-agree-to-let-independent-technocrat-committee-run-gaza</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Administration will manage basic services ‘in cooperation with Arab brothers and international institutions’, says joint statement&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The main Palestinian factions have said they have agreed that an independent committee of technocrats would take over the running of Gaza after Hamas said it had received “clear guarantees” from mediators that “the war has effectively ended”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A joint statement published on the Hamas website said the groups had agreed in a meeting in Cairo to hand “over the administration of the Gaza Strip to a temporary Palestinian committee composed of independent ‘technocrats’, which will manage the affairs of life and basic services in cooperation with Arab brothers and international institutions”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/palestinian-factions-say-they-agree-to-let-independent-technocrat-committee-run-gaza"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/palestinian-factions-say-they-agree-to-let-independent-technocrat-committee-run-gaza</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:50:30 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Letitia James pleads not guilty in mortgage fraud case</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2kpvlvvx0xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Speaking outside court, James accused Trump of using the justice department as a "vehicle of retribution".</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c2kpvlvvx0xo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:50:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Six Britons acting for Wagner group jailed for arson attack on UK warehouse</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/six-britons-jailed-for-1m-arson-attack-on-warehouse-holding-aid-for-ukraine</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Judge says men imprisoned over fire at site storing Ukraine aid planned terrorist campaign in interests of Russia&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six Britons acting for Russia’s Wagner group have been jailed for &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/jul/08/three-men-found-guilty-over-london-arson-attack-on-ukraine-linked-firms"&gt;setting fire to a London warehouse storing humanitarian aid&lt;/a&gt; for Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sentencing the men, a judge at the Old Bailey said they had planned a “campaign of terrorism and sabotage” in the interests of the Russian state.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/six-britons-jailed-for-1m-arson-attack-on-warehouse-holding-aid-for-ukraine"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/six-britons-jailed-for-1m-arson-attack-on-warehouse-holding-aid-for-ukraine</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:47:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scottish fire engine destined for West Bank may return after 15-month Israeli seizure</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/scottish-fire-engine-destined-for-west-bank-may-return-after-15-month-israeli-seizure</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Dundee firefighters request return of donated appliance to avoid Nablus officials having to pay £16,000 Ashdod holding fees&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A fully equipped fire engine donated by Dundee firefighters to their counterparts in the West Bank city of Nablus could be sent back to Scotland after being impounded for more than a year by Israeli authorities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Firefighters in Dundee, which is twinned with Nablus, have regularly donated kit, equipment and medical supplies to the West Bank over the past 15 years, as well as bringing Palestinian firefighters to Scotland for training.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/scottish-fire-engine-destined-for-west-bank-may-return-after-15-month-israeli-seizure"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/24/scottish-fire-engine-destined-for-west-bank-may-return-after-15-month-israeli-seizure</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:47:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We installed solar panels and batteries and waiting for PTO from APS.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2sil/we_installed_solar_panels_and_batteries_and/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Logical_Row9493"&gt; /u/Logical_Row9493 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2sil/we_installed_solar_panels_and_batteries_and/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2sil/we_installed_solar_panels_and_batteries_and/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2sil/we_installed_solar_panels_and_batteries_and/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:44:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Surgeons remove up to 100 magnets from New Zealand teenager’s intestines</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/surgeons-remove-high-power-temu-magnets-new-zealand-teenagers-intestines</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Boy, 13, swallowed the high-power magnets after apparently buying them from the online retailer Temu&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A 13-year-old boy in New Zealand swallowed up to 100 high-power magnets he bought online, forcing surgeons to remove tissue from his intestines, doctors said on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After suffering four days of abdominal pain, the unnamed teenager was taken to Tauranga hospital in the North Island. “He disclosed ingesting approximately 80 to 100 5x2mm high-power (neodymium) magnets about one week prior,” said a report by hospital doctors in the New Zealand Medical Journal.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/surgeons-remove-high-power-temu-magnets-new-zealand-teenagers-intestines"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/surgeons-remove-high-power-temu-magnets-new-zealand-teenagers-intestines</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:42:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Scientists discover bacteria that eats battery waste, making toxic disposal safe</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2miy/scientists_discover_bacteria_that_eats_battery/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2miy/scientists_discover_bacteria_that_eats_battery/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Scientists discover bacteria that eats battery waste, making toxic disposal safe" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/6Q4lbdIuqa0yPw3EHbbBnv7q5Kyg7TWlolukHfLTOdQ.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=3248518f06bb029ecfc4d3608d57a1034370c41d" title="Scientists discover bacteria that eats battery waste, making toxic disposal safe" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Sackim05"&gt; /u/Sackim05 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://interestingengineering.com/energy/new-bacteria-offers-path-for-battery-recycling"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2miy/scientists_discover_bacteria_that_eats_battery/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of2miy/scientists_discover_bacteria_that_eats_battery/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:38:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US and Canada spar over ad of Reagan denouncing tariffs that led to derailed trade talks</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-canada-trade-negotations-ontario-tariffs</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Ontario premier says he plans to run ad featuring speech that sparked Trump’s ire again during World Series&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;After the US suspended all trade negotiations with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/canada"&gt;Canada&lt;/a&gt; over a 1987 speech by Ronald Reagan denouncing tariffs that appeared to spark &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt;’s ire, the premier of Ontario said he plans to run an ad featuring the speech again during the World Series on Friday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Doug Ford, whose government ran the Reagan ad in US markets this week, first posted on X that the two nations are “stronger together”, while Trump added his own string of social media posts trumpeting the supposed benefits of tariffs.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-canada-trade-negotations-ontario-tariffs"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/24/trump-canada-trade-negotations-ontario-tariffs</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:33:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>From government spin doctor to Cameroon president's main rival</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2n7dq24glo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Issa Tchiroma Bakary says he won the election and is not concerned about being arrested or put in jail.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2n7dq24glo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:30:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Still life that never moved: mystery of missing Picasso painting solved</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2025/oct/24/mystery-of-missing-picasso-still-life-painting-solved-spain</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Artwork that vanished en route from Madrid to Granada seemingly never made it on to van in first place&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fittingly enough for a still life, it would appear that the small Picasso painting that triggered a police investigation &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2025/oct/16/spanish-police-investigate-as-picasso-painting-vanishes-on-way-to-exhibition"&gt;after apparently vanishing&lt;/a&gt; while en route from Madrid to Granada for an exhibition earlier this month scarcely moved from its pickup point.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Officers from Spain’s Policía Nacional began searching for the gouache and pencil work &lt;em&gt;Naturaleza muerta con guitarra (&lt;/em&gt;Still Life with Guitar) after it failed to arrive on a van that was bringing a consignment of loaned exhibits from the capital to the CajaGranada foundation on 3 October.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2025/oct/24/mystery-of-missing-picasso-still-life-painting-solved-spain"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/artanddesign/2025/oct/24/mystery-of-missing-picasso-still-life-painting-solved-spain</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:14:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>3D solar tower increases capacity factor 50%, triples solar surface area</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of1rxo/3d_solar_tower_increases_capacity_factor_50/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of1rxo/3d_solar_tower_increases_capacity_factor_50/"&gt; &lt;img alt="3D solar tower increases capacity factor 50%, triples solar surface area" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/7A6Gt9U3yhCKsBD5fQ5E3AFtJErC9CgpnFu_yJLwMtw.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=64e7a0462406e78c8306532a298ce0ab770fb0df" title="3D solar tower increases capacity factor 50%, triples solar surface area" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/ObtainSustainability"&gt; /u/ObtainSustainability &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://pv-magazine-usa.com/2025/10/24/3d-solar-tower-increases-capacity-factor-50-triples-solar-surface-area/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of1rxo/3d_solar_tower_increases_capacity_factor_50/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of1rxo/3d_solar_tower_increases_capacity_factor_50/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:05:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Even Doomsday Will Divide Us</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/review-guardian-thief-megha-majumdar-climate-crisis-india/</link><description>Megha Majumdar’s “A Guardian and a Thief” interrogates how the have-nots get by in a climate catastrophe.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/review-guardian-thief-megha-majumdar-climate-crisis-india/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:03:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Mainframe Six (2022)</title><link>https://arcanesciences.com/os2200/app1.html</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45695956"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://arcanesciences.com/os2200/app1.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 16:01:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rubio says lots of countries willing to join Gaza security force</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn0gwn491dwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US secretary of state says Israel must be comfortable with participants, but it is unclear how such a force could be deployed without an understanding with Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn0gwn491dwo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:58:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Indian Farmers Struggle as Climate Change Warps Landscape</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/india-farmers-crops-climate-change/</link><description>Once-thriving crops are poorly adapting to new temperatures.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/24/india-farmers-crops-climate-change/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:46:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump administration finalizes plan to open pristine Alaska wildlife refuge to oil and gas drilling, renewing a long-simmering debate over whether to drill in one of the nation's environmental jewels. Conservationists and tribal leaders vowed a legal challenge to the agreement.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of16cn/trump_administration_finalizes_plan_to_open/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of16cn/trump_administration_finalizes_plan_to_open/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Trump administration finalizes plan to open pristine Alaska wildlife refuge to oil and gas drilling, renewing a long-simmering debate over whether to drill in one of the nation's environmental jewels. Conservationists and tribal leaders vowed a legal challenge to the agreement." src="https://external-preview.redd.it/gXfE7Uulo5lA2SN6HAvUTtyDQUYPKNJ56Z6O66yjpnc.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=696c106d53b017cacd4d14554b0d7d6e1a8e4534" title="Trump administration finalizes plan to open pristine Alaska wildlife refuge to oil and gas drilling, renewing a long-simmering debate over whether to drill in one of the nation's environmental jewels. Conservationists and tribal leaders vowed a legal challenge to the agreement." /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/mafco"&gt; /u/mafco &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/10/24/nx-s1-5584883/trump-alaska-wildlife-refuge-oil-gas-drilling"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of16cn/trump_administration_finalizes_plan_to_open/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of16cn/trump_administration_finalizes_plan_to_open/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:43:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Spectacular downfall of Georgia's ex-PM accused of having $6.5m in his flat</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjekw5jxw89o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Irakli Garibashvili, who was a loyal lieutenant of Georgia's de facto leader, is accused of corruption.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cjekw5jxw89o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:30:58 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Urals-India freight rates surged in Oct amid sanctions &amp; high exports. US &amp; EU imposed new sanctions, incl. against Lukoil &amp; Rosneft, and added 117 vessels to Russia's "shadow fleet"</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0sz0/uralsindia_freight_rates_surged_in_oct_amid/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Reuters sources, the cost of shipping Urals crude from Russia’s western ports to India saw a significant increase in October. This surge was fueled by robust export volumes combined with growing pressure from sanctions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, President Trump announced additional sanctions targeting Lukoil and Rosneft, Russia’s two biggest oil producers. Simultaneously, the European Union greenlit its 19th sanctions package against Moscow, adding 117 vessels, predominantly tankers, to its list of shadow fleet ships connected to Russia, bringing the total to 558.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;October witnessed consistently high crude oil loadings from Russia’s western ports, including Primorsk, Ust-Luga, and Novorossiisk, averaging around 2.3 million barrels per day (bpd). This figure is slightly lower than the record high of 2.5 million bpd recorded in September, which was attributed to volumes released due to unscheduled refinery maintenance.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;The freight rates for transporting Urals crude from the Baltic ports of Primorsk and Ust-Luga to India for November loading have now surpassed $8 million for Aframax tankers. This marks an increase from approximately $7 million for a one-way voyage at the beginning of October.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;One trader mentioned that offer prices for certain vessels have neared $10 million, though no transactions have been finalized at those prices. Sources indicate that Urals shipments from Russian ports are now predominantly managed by tankers from the shadow fleet, as Greek shipowners reduce their involvement in the market. One source stated that the number of active Greek shipowners has decreased substantially.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Since the beginning of 2025, the U.S. has implemented a new series of sanctions aimed at Russia’s oil industry. These measures, considered the most stringent to date, target major exporters, insurers, traders, and shipping companies, leading to a sharp escalation in freight rates.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://starfeu.com"&gt;starfeu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Gloomy-Presence-9831"&gt; /u/Gloomy-Presence-9831 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0sz0/uralsindia_freight_rates_surged_in_oct_amid/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0sz0/uralsindia_freight_rates_surged_in_oct_amid/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0sz0/uralsindia_freight_rates_surged_in_oct_amid/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:28:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>SPR refill</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0mx4/spr_refill/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;At what price, if any, does the DOE get more aggressive to buy cheap oil and refill the SPR at a faster pace. Even if they had to store some of the oil temporarily at Cushing it might make sense with WTI hovering around $60. I heard awhile back that there was/is a technical limit how much can be injected into the SPR caverns per day. Maybe they are hoping for WTI to hit $50 ?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/TwistedMind71"&gt; /u/TwistedMind71 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0mx4/spr_refill/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0mx4/spr_refill/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1of0mx4/spr_refill/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:22:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ex-Mayor of Rostov-on-Don Arrested Over Alleged Abuse of Power</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/24/ex-mayor-of-rostov-on-don-arrested-over-alleged-abuse-of-power-a90930</link><description>Logvinenko is accused of causing more than 47 million rubles ($583,300) in damages to the city budget.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/24/ex-mayor-of-rostov-on-don-arrested-over-alleged-abuse-of-power-a90930</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:02:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Napoleon’s soldiers who died in Russian retreat had unexpected diseases, study finds</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/napoleon-army-died-russia-unexpected-diseases</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Bacteria for paratyphoid fever and relapsing fever found in DNA from teeth of troops buried in mass grave&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When Napoleon ordered his army to retreat from Russia in October 1812, disaster ensued. Starving, cold, exhausted and struggling with sickness, an estimated 300,000 soldiers died.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers now say they have identified two unexpected diseases among soldiers who died in the retreat – paratyphoid fever and relapsing fever – which provide fresh insights into their plight.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/napoleon-army-died-russia-unexpected-diseases"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/napoleon-army-died-russia-unexpected-diseases</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:00:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US strikes another alleged drug boat in Caribbean</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c891gzx7xn4o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The Pentagon also plans to send the Gerald Ford carrier strike group to the area to help "disrupt narcotics trafficking".</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c891gzx7xn4o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:56:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Canada will restart trade talks when 'Americans are ready', says Carney</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cdjrlmd4pmeo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>President Trump abruptly ended negotiations over an advert that used Ronald Reagan speaking negatively about tariffs.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cdjrlmd4pmeo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:55:12 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Prosecution Seeks 440 Hours of Community Service for Opposition Politician Shlosberg</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/24/prosecution-seeks-440-hours-of-community-service-for-opposition-politician-shlosberg-a90929</link><description>Shlosberg faces up to five years in prison if found guilty. Authorities accuse Shlosberg of calling for a ceasefire in Ukraine during a January debate.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/24/prosecution-seeks-440-hours-of-community-service-for-opposition-politician-shlosberg-a90929</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:53:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>'It became one of the children' – Kenyan family on adopting orphaned cheetah cub</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gj4x4939qo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Their neighbours, who raise livestock, told the family to get rid of the wild animal.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c4gj4x4939qo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:50:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China's Renewable Energy Breakthrough: Surpassing 10 Trillion kWh and Establishing the World's Largest System</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oezng5/chinas_renewable_energy_breakthrough_surpassing/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oezng5/chinas_renewable_energy_breakthrough_surpassing/"&gt; &lt;img alt="China's Renewable Energy Breakthrough: Surpassing 10 Trillion kWh and Establishing the World's Largest System" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/U5mWRMraU1P5aCR14GTdzm4sHRWq5rVYl5ku7ekSxY4.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=e66b76b0174433768cc1f83f41a93618b0283622" title="China's Renewable Energy Breakthrough: Surpassing 10 Trillion kWh and Establishing the World's Largest System" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/DomS96"&gt; /u/DomS96 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://yuantrends.com/china-renewable-energy-breakthrough-10-trillion-kwh"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oezng5/chinas_renewable_energy_breakthrough_surpassing/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oezng5/chinas_renewable_energy_breakthrough_surpassing/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:44:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Might China Respond To US Sanctions On Russia's Biggest Oil Companies?</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/china-russia-oil-sanctions-lukoil-rosneft-evasion-ukraine-trump/33569580.html</link><description>Major Chinese state oil companies have reportedly stopped imports of Russian crude oil in response to US sanctions. But Beijing has its own playbook to follow as it navigates the latest energy sanctions.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/china-russia-oil-sanctions-lukoil-rosneft-evasion-ukraine-trump/33569580.html</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:25:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>As federal emissions rules loosen, states like Maryland are holding the line — how should businesses keep up?</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oeyvt4/as_federal_emissions_rules_loosen_states_like/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oeyvt4/as_federal_emissions_rules_loosen_states_like/"&gt; &lt;img alt="As federal emissions rules loosen, states like Maryland are holding the line — how should businesses keep up?" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/XnBRkCDihkBCHE7hjwZiWC7Vaas71m73X79TV7nRNnA.jpeg?width=216&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=2870427d67167ef79da38e81e1061bb1b74f6df7" title="As federal emissions rules loosen, states like Maryland are holding the line — how should businesses keep up?" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;While the federal government is scaling back or reconsidering some greenhouse gas regulations, states are moving in the opposite direction — tightening standards and enforcement. Maryland’s new Building Energy Performance Standards are a good example of how state-level policy is filling the gap.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick explainer from Pepco breaking down what building owners and facility managers in Maryland need to know: &lt;a href="https://homeenergysavings.pepco.com/md/article/marylands-new-energy-standards-what-building-owners-need-know-now"&gt;Maryland’s New Energy Standards: What Building Owners Need to Know Now&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Curious how others here see this trend playing out — if federal rules continue to loosen but states keep ramping up, how do multi-state businesses stay compliant? Should we expect more patchwork energy policy going forward, or could state standards end up setting the new national baseline?&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/CorpDevCorey"&gt; /u/CorpDevCorey &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://homeenergysavings.pepco.com/md/article/marylands-new-energy-standards-what-building-owners-need-know-now"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oeyvt4/as_federal_emissions_rules_loosen_states_like/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oeyvt4/as_federal_emissions_rules_loosen_states_like/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:14:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Asahi Linux Still Working on Apple M3 Support, M1n1 Bootloader Going Rust</title><link>https://www.phoronix.com/news/Asahi-Linux-M3-m1n1-Update</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45694767"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.phoronix.com/news/Asahi-Linux-M3-m1n1-Update</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:03:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Once Australia’s second priciest city, Melbourne has become more affordable. What happened – and will it last?</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/once-australias-second-priciest-city-melbourne-has-become-more-affordable-what-happened-and-will-it-last</link><description>&lt;p&gt;More homes and less property investor activity has seen Victoria’s capital rise up the affordability rankings&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2021, Melbourne’s median house price surpassed $1m, after a decade of rising by an average of more than $70,000 a year.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was Australia’s second most expensive housing market, after Sydney. The next year, prices began to fall.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/once-australias-second-priciest-city-melbourne-has-become-more-affordable-what-happened-and-will-it-last"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/once-australias-second-priciest-city-melbourne-has-become-more-affordable-what-happened-and-will-it-last</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:00:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Australia’s $20m ‘iron fist’ deal with Israel’s largest arms company signed two weeks before UN genocide finding</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/australia-20m-weapon-deal-israels-largest-arms-company-signed-two-weeks-before-un-genocide</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusive:&lt;/strong&gt; Experts criticise federal government’s contract with Elbit Systems as ‘troubling acceptance’ of Israel’s conduct in Gaza&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Australia’s $20m purchase of missiles from an Israeli arms company for its “iron fist” weapons system on infantry vehicles has been condemned as “morally questionable” and reflective of a “troubling acceptance” of Israel’s conduct in Gaza.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Australian defence department signed a contract with Israel’s largest weapons company, Elbit Systems, on 1 September, two weeks before a UN commission of inquiry found Israel was &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/sep/18/albanese-urged-to-end-double-standard-on-israel-after-un-commission-finds-genocide-occurring-in-gaza"&gt;committing genocide in Gaza&lt;/a&gt;. Details of the contract were not published on the Australian government’s contract database until last week.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/australia-20m-weapon-deal-israels-largest-arms-company-signed-two-weeks-before-un-genocide"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/25/australia-20m-weapon-deal-israels-largest-arms-company-signed-two-weeks-before-un-genocide</guid><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 14:00:46 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>