<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:41:05 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>After building huge new dam, Ethiopia warns of hydropower's drought risk. Wants to diversify to wind and solar in the face of climate-induced droughts.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe6gw8/after_building_huge_new_dam_ethiopia_warns_of/</link><description>&amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Splenda"&gt; /u/Splenda &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.climatechangenews.com/2025/10/03/after-building-huge-new-dam-ethiopia-warns-of-hydropowers-drought-risk/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe6gw8/after_building_huge_new_dam_ethiopia_warns_of/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe6gw8/after_building_huge_new_dam_ethiopia_warns_of/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:34:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China’s State Oil Giants Halt Seaborne Russian Crude Imports After New U.S. Sanctions – Reuters</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/chinas-state-oil-giants-halt-seaborne-russian-crude-imports-after-new-us-sanctions-reuters-a90918</link><description>Industry consultancies offer differing estimates of Chinese state-company imports from 250,000 barrels per day to 500,000 bpd.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/chinas-state-oil-giants-halt-seaborne-russian-crude-imports-after-new-us-sanctions-reuters-a90918</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:33:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Not guilty verdict for Soldier F in Bloody Sunday murder trial</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c993nlken18o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Thirteen people were shot dead and at least 15 others injured on Bloody Sunday in January 1972 at a civil rights demonstration in the Bogside area of Derry.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c993nlken18o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:19:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine should be able to use frozen Russian assets to buy and make weapons, says Zelenskyy – Europe live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/russia-sanctions-ukraine-loan-assets-zelenskyy-putin-european-council-latest-news-updates</link><description>&lt;p&gt;EU leaders earlier discussed proposal to use Russian assets for ‘reparations loan’, as Russia’s foreign ministry warned of ‘painful response’ if plan goes ahead&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Ukrainian president, &lt;strong&gt;Volodymyr Zelenskyy&lt;/strong&gt;, urged European Union leaders on Thursday to agree as soon as possible on a plan to use frozen Russian assets to support Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy, who is visiting Brussels, said on X that the proposed mechanism for using frozen Russian assets was entirely legal and fair. He said Ukraine would use a significant part of the assets to buy weapons from its European allies.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/russia-sanctions-ukraine-loan-assets-zelenskyy-putin-european-council-latest-news-updates"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/russia-sanctions-ukraine-loan-assets-zelenskyy-putin-european-council-latest-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:19:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>San Francisco Bay Area braces for Trump’s ‘aggressive’ immigration crackdown</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/san-francisco-federal-immigration-operation</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Administration has reportedly sent more than 100 federal agents to US Coast Guard base near the California region&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco Bay Area is bracing for a major federal immigration enforcement operation that could start as early as Thursday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The San Francisco Chronicle &lt;a href="https://www.sfchronicle.com/bayarea/article/federal-immigration-action-what-to-know-21114959.php"&gt;reported on Wednesday&lt;/a&gt; that the &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/trump-administration"&gt;Trump administration&lt;/a&gt; has sent more than 100 Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and other federal agents to the US Coast Guard base in Alameda, across the Bay from San Francisco, as part of a large-scale immigration enforcement plan.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/san-francisco-federal-immigration-operation"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/san-francisco-federal-immigration-operation</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:18:56 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US hits $38T in debt. Fastest accumulation of $1T outside pandemic</title><link>https://apnews.com/article/trump-treasury-debt-ceiling-bessent-09575f13ca95c2f1beb38234b2cbe85b</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682671"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://apnews.com/article/trump-treasury-debt-ceiling-bessent-09575f13ca95c2f1beb38234b2cbe85b</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:03:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Marine heatwave over Pacific Ocean could lead to flooding in north-west</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/pacific-ocean-marine-heatwave-north-west</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Severe ‘blob’ or marine heatwave can lead to increased inundation and wintery weather in eastern North America&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A marine heatwave known as a blob was especially severe this year in the north-western and central Pacific Ocean, which could lead in the coming months to increased flooding in the US Pacific north-west and especially wintery weather in eastern North America, according to climate scientists.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The temperature in August in the northern Pacific was 2.5C above preindustrial levels, according to &lt;a href="https://berkeleyearth.org/august-2025-temperature-update/"&gt;Berkeley Earth&lt;/a&gt;, a non-profit that studies global warming.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/pacific-ocean-marine-heatwave-north-west"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/pacific-ocean-marine-heatwave-north-west</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:00:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Three Key Questions About Trump’s War Against Drug Boats</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/23/us-boat-strikes-pacific-caribbean-venezuela-trump-drug-war-maduro/</link><description>Experts believe the operation is about regime change in Venezuela.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/23/us-boat-strikes-pacific-caribbean-venezuela-trump-drug-war-maduro/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 15:00:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Brazilian president will seek fourth term at age 80: ‘I’ve got as much energy as when I was 30’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/brazil-lula-president-fourth-term</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva, who first ran for elected office in 1982, announced he will run again in next year’s election&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Brazilian president, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/luiz-inacio-lula-da-silva"&gt;Luiz Inácio Lula da Silva&lt;/a&gt;, has announced he will seek a historic fourth term in next year’s presidential election, potentially extending one of the most remarkable and enduring political careers in modern Latin American history.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The former metalworker, who returned to the presidency in 2023 after beating the far-right incumbent, Jair Bolsonaro, confirmed his decision during a speech in Indonesia’s capital, Jakarta.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/brazil-lula-president-fourth-term"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/brazil-lula-president-fourth-term</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:57:31 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Commons to ask crown estate for details of Prince Andrew’s rent-free housing as inquiry moves closer – UK politics live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/23/jess-phillips-grooming-gangs-inquiry-keir-starmer-labour-uk-politics-latest-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Conservative chair of public accounts committee to raise questions about Andrew’s deal at Royal Lodge&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rachel Reeves&lt;/strong&gt; has announced &lt;a href="https://www.gov.uk/government/news/jobs-homes-and-better-transport-links-for-the-oxford-cambridge-growth-corridor"&gt;a £500m investment package&lt;/a&gt; for new homes and stronger transport links between Oxford and Cambridge as part of a bid to create “Europe’s Silicon Valley” in southern England, PA Media reports. PA says:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Cowley Branch railway line in Oxford will reopen with new stations in Littlemore and Cowley, which the Treasury said would support up to 10,000 new jobs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The investment will also go towards the development of affordable homes in Cambridge, with plans to launch a consultation on forming a new centrally led development corporation to support the growth of the city.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/23/jess-phillips-grooming-gangs-inquiry-keir-starmer-labour-uk-politics-latest-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/23/jess-phillips-grooming-gangs-inquiry-keir-starmer-labour-uk-politics-latest-news</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:55:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New rules will allow police misusing force in England and Wales to ‘walk away scot-free’</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/lenient-police-misconduct-rules-misusing-force-england-wales</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Critics warn boosting protections of officers at misconduct cases, introduced after fatal shooting of Chris Kaba, will undermine rule of law&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New rules in England and Wales will make it harder to punish police officers accused of wrongly using force, with critics saying it will lead to greater “impunity and injustice”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ministers hope to &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2024/oct/21/what-we-now-know-about-the-13-seconds-before-chris-kaba-was-shot"&gt;quell fears among firearms officers that they will be hounded &lt;/a&gt;for doing their job.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/lenient-police-misconduct-rules-misusing-force-england-wales"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/lenient-police-misconduct-rules-misusing-force-england-wales</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:53:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Dozens of Labour MPs warn of chaos for firms over gender recognition advice</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/23/dozens-of-labour-mps-warn-of-chaos-for-firms-over-gender-recognition-advice</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Nearly 50 backbenchers write to business secretary over potential costs and legal ‘minefield’ of upcoming guidance&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/politics/live/2025/oct/23/jess-phillips-grooming-gangs-inquiry-keir-starmer-labour-uk-politics-latest-news"&gt;UK politics live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dozens of Labour MPs have written to ministers warning that upcoming regulations on how to implement rules on gender recognition could cause chaos for many businesses.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a private letter to the business secretary, Peter Kyle, the MPs said they had been contacted by large numbers of firms that were deeply alarmed at the implications of the guidance, citing significant potential costs and a “minefield” of competing legal rights.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/23/dozens-of-labour-mps-warn-of-chaos-for-firms-over-gender-recognition-advice"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/society/2025/oct/23/dozens-of-labour-mps-warn-of-chaos-for-firms-over-gender-recognition-advice</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:47:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>King Charles makes history by praying publicly with Pope Leo</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-publicly-with-pope-leo</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Charles becomes first reigning British monarch to pray with a pope publicly since Henry VIII split from Rome in 1534&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-with-pope-historic-division"&gt;A rift that took 500 years to repair: King Charles prays with the pope&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;King Charles has made history after becoming the first reigning British monarch to pray publicly with a pope since Henry VIII split from Rome in 1534, an event perceived as a symbolic step in the reconciliation between the Catholic and Anglican churches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The monarch and his wife, Queen Camilla, joined Pope Leo for a service under Michelangelo’s ceiling frescoes in the Sistine Chapel, where in May Leo was elected the first US pontiff to lead the world’s 1.4 billion Catholics.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-publicly-with-pope-leo"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/uk-news/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-publicly-with-pope-leo</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:30:59 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New book details infighting behind Trump’s ‘obviously unqualified’ cabinet picks</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/retribution-jonathan-karl-book-trump-cabinet</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Retribution, by Jonathan Karl, describes backroom squabbling over Kristi Noem and Sean Duffy appointments&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/donaldtrump"&gt;Donald Trump&lt;/a&gt; picked Kristi Noem as homeland security secretary as a personal favour to his former campaign manager Corey Lewandowski despite objections that she was “obviously unqualified”, according to a new book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The factional infighting behind Trump’s cabinet selection, where inexperience was no barrier to success, is detailed by journalist Jonathan Karl in &lt;a href="https://sites.prh.com/jonathankarlbooks"&gt;Retribution: Donald Trump and the Campaign That Changed America&lt;/a&gt;. The Guardian obtained a copy.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/retribution-jonathan-karl-book-trump-cabinet"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/retribution-jonathan-karl-book-trump-cabinet</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:30:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Four members of Illinois politician’s family killed in helicopter crash</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/darren-bailey-family-killed-helicopter-crash</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Darren Bailey’s son, daughter-in-law and two grandchildren all killed in accident in Montana&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A former Illinois state senator running for governor in 2026 is mourning the deaths of four family members killed when their helicopter crashed in Montana on Wednesday.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Darren Bailey’s son Zachary, daughter-in-law Kelsey, and grandchildren Vada Rose, 12, and Samuel, seven, all perished in the incident, according to an announcement from his campaign on Thursday. The couple is survived by their 10-year-old son Finn, who was not on the aircraft.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/darren-bailey-family-killed-helicopter-crash"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/23/darren-bailey-family-killed-helicopter-crash</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:28:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian Mercenaries in Africa Exacerbate Arms Control Crisis – Report</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/russian-mercenaries-in-africa-exacerbate-arms-control-crisis-report-a90835</link><description>The findings highlight a gap in global arms monitoring systems as well as the fusion between conflict and organized crime.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/russian-mercenaries-in-africa-exacerbate-arms-control-crisis-report-a90835</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:26:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US axes website for reporting human rights abuses by US-armed foreign forces</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx30vnwd4do</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682169"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cqx30vnwd4do</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:25:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Zaporizhzhia nuclear plant reconnected to external power from Ukraine</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/zaporizhzhia-nuclear-plant-reconnected-to-external-power-from-ukraine</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Move ends month-long reliance on backup generators after power line was cut in September&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russian engineers have reconnected the occupied Zaporizhzhia nuclear power plant to external electrical power from Ukraine, ending a month-long emergency that had plunged the future of the six-reactor site into doubt.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ukrainian sources told the Guardian that Russian technicians had hoped to connect Europe’s biggest nuclear plant – which had been relying on backup generators since its last external power line was cut in September – to power from the Russian grid on 7 October as a birthday present for Vladimir Putin.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/zaporizhzhia-nuclear-plant-reconnected-to-external-power-from-ukraine"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/zaporizhzhia-nuclear-plant-reconnected-to-external-power-from-ukraine</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:25:16 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Anti-Kidnapping Unit of the Baja State Prosecutor’s Office in Tijuana Bombarded by Three Weaponized Cartel Drones</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/anti-kidnapping-unit-of-the-baja-state-prosecutors-office-in-tijuana-bombarded-by-three-weaponized-cartel-drones/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anti-Kidnapping Unit of the Baja State Prosecutor’s Office in Tijuana Bombarded by Three Weaponized Cartel Drones &amp;#124;  C/O Futures Cartel Research Note Series By Dr. Robert J. Bunker of SWJ 19 October 2025 (Revised) During the early evening of Wednesday, 15 October 2025, the facility containing the anti- kidnapping unit of the Fiscalía General del Estado de Baja California (Attorney &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/anti-kidnapping-unit-of-the-baja-state-prosecutors-office-in-tijuana-bombarded-by-three-weaponized-cartel-drones/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/anti-kidnapping-unit-of-the-baja-state-prosecutors-office-in-tijuana-bombarded-by-three-weaponized-cartel-drones/"&gt;Anti-Kidnapping Unit of the Baja State Prosecutor’s Office in Tijuana Bombarded by Three Weaponized Cartel Drones&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/anti-kidnapping-unit-of-the-baja-state-prosecutors-office-in-tijuana-bombarded-by-three-weaponized-cartel-drones/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:21:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>‘Quiet as a whisper’: German firm launches campaign after lift was used in Louvre heist</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/german-firm-campaign-lift-louvre-heist-bocker</link><description>&lt;p&gt;After watching the news about the Paris robbery, managers at Böcker decided to make the most of the publicity&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;A family run German business unwittingly became wrapped up in the crown jewel heist at the Louvre museum in Paris and is turning the use of one of its furniture lifts into a publicity coup.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;“When you need to move fast” is the new tongue-in-cheek advertising tagline for the company Böcker, which is based in the town of Werne near Dortmund, in &lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/DQBr9Xdgp_D/?hl=en"&gt;a campaign on Facebook and Instagram&lt;/a&gt; mounted within a day of the brazen thefts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/german-firm-campaign-lift-louvre-heist-bocker"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/german-firm-campaign-lift-louvre-heist-bocker</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:20:13 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rosenberg: Trump abandons carrot and wields stick over Putin in Ukraine talks</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnve5532v7yo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The BBC's Russia editor says Trump's decision to call of his Putin talks and impose oil sanctions will not go down well in Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cnve5532v7yo?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:18:28 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Microsoft puts Office Online Server on the chopping block</title><link>https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/22/microsoft_office_online_server/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45682067"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theregister.com/2025/10/22/microsoft_office_online_server/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:15:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Most Russian Businesses Plan to Raise Prices as Tax Hike Looms – Survey</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/most-russian-businesses-plan-to-raise-prices-as-tax-hike-looms-survey-a90915</link><description>The government's proposal to raise the VAT rate and lower the annual revenue threshold for VAT payments has put small businesses under pressure.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/most-russian-businesses-plan-to-raise-prices-as-tax-hike-looms-survey-a90915</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:14:45 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A rift that took 500 years to repair: King Charles prays with the pope</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-with-pope-historic-division</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Joint prayer in Sistine Chapel is symbolic act of rapprochement between Catholic church and Church of England after centuries of division&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Almost every British schoolchild is taught that Henry VIII, the swaggering Tudor king driven by lust and his quest for an heir, broke away from the Roman Catholic church in 1534 after the pope refused to annul his marriage to Catherine of Aragon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Henry created the Church of England, appointed himself its supreme governor, divorced Catherine and married Anne Boleyn (who lasted just three years before she was beheaded for treason).&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-with-pope-historic-division"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/king-charles-prays-with-pope-historic-division</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:12:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Oil price jumps and FTSE 100 hits new high after Trump puts sanctions on Russian firms</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/23/oil-price-jumps-after-trump-imposes-sanctions-on-two-russian-producers-rosneft-lukoil</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Assets in US belonging to Rosneft and Lukoil frozen as shares in Shell and BP rise by 3%&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/live/2025/oct/23/oil-price-us-sanctions-rosneft-lukoil-software-curbs-china-trade-war-business-live"&gt;Business live – latest updates&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Oil prices jumped and energy companies helped the FTSE 100 to a record high after Donald Trump announced new sanctions on Russia’s two biggest oil producers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Brent crude increased by 5.2% to $65.83 a barrel – a two-week high – after the news of the fresh restrictions on Rosneft and Lukoil, as the US president ramps up &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/oct/22/us-sanctions-russia-oil-vladimir-putin-refusal-ukraine-war"&gt;pressure on Vladimir Putin&lt;/a&gt; to end the war in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/23/oil-price-jumps-after-trump-imposes-sanctions-on-two-russian-producers-rosneft-lukoil"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/business/2025/oct/23/oil-price-jumps-after-trump-imposes-sanctions-on-two-russian-producers-rosneft-lukoil</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:11:07 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>India Warily Welcomes the Taliban</title><link>https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/23/india-afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-sindoor-jaishankar/</link><description>A diplomatic visit highlights the cautious engagement between New Delhi and Kabul.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://foreignpolicy.com/2025/10/23/india-afghanistan-pakistan-taliban-sindoor-jaishankar/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:09:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Ukraine Says Russia Returned 1,000 Bodies</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/ukraine-says-russia-returned-1000-bodies-a90917</link><description>The exchange of prisoners of war and killed soldiers is one of the few remaining areas of cooperation between Kyiv and Moscow.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/ukraine-says-russia-returned-1000-bodies-a90917</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:05:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says Australia will get the Aukus submarines – but the decision won’t be his to make</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/trump-says-australia-will-get-the-aukus-submarines-but-the-decision-wont-be-his-to-make</link><description>&lt;p&gt;If the US navy needs the subs, they cannot be sold to Australia, regardless of how much the president might wish it&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even by the standards of the Trumpian promise, the unvarnished commitment to Australia on US nuclear submarines – “they’re getting them” – is entirely unreliable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;They are not the US president’s boats to give.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/trump-says-australia-will-get-the-aukus-submarines-but-the-decision-wont-be-his-to-make"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/24/trump-says-australia-will-get-the-aukus-submarines-but-the-decision-wont-be-his-to-make</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:24 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Gone in 60 milliseconds: dramatic slow-motion snake bites reveal clues about how fangs and venom kill prey</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/slow-motion-snake-bites-how-fangs-and-venom-kill-prey</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Vipers target with precision, elapids bite repeatedly and colubrids saw their way in – and if they strike too fast, they might lose their teeth&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Venomous snakes must strike fast to sink their fangs in prey before they startle – as quickly as 60 milliseconds when hunting rodents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;New research has captured – in slow-motion footage – the differences in how venomous serpents bite their targets.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/slow-motion-snake-bites-how-fangs-and-venom-kill-prey"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/slow-motion-snake-bites-how-fangs-and-venom-kill-prey</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Labor needs to bow to Liberals or Greens or its environment law revamp is dead</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/labor-needs-to-bow-to-liberals-or-greens-or-its-environment-law-revamp-is-dead</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Albanese government will need to make major concessions to pass promised federal nature laws as Liberals attack ‘nature positive 2.0’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Albanese government will need to cough up major concessions to either the Coalition or the Greens to have any hope of overhauling federal nature laws after the two parties ruled out supporting the current plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The environment minister, Murray Watt, said he was open to working with either side, but wouldn’t speculate about possible changes, leaving the fate of the promised re-write of the Environment Protection and Biodiversity Conservation (EPBC) Act unknown ahead of its introduction to parliament in the upcoming sitting fortnight.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/labor-needs-to-bow-to-liberals-or-greens-or-its-environment-law-revamp-is-dead"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/labor-needs-to-bow-to-liberals-or-greens-or-its-environment-law-revamp-is-dead</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Revealed: some Australians have overpaid their Centrelink debt by more than $20,000</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/revealed-some-australians-have-overpaid-their-centrelink-debt-by-more-than-20000</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exclusive:&lt;/strong&gt; Services Australia spokesperson says automatic BPay payments and Centrelink being unable to contact customers may be to blame&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get our &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/email-newsletters?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;breaking news email&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://app.adjust.com/w4u7jx3"&gt;free app&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/series/full-story?CMP=cvau_sfl"&gt;daily news podcast&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Approximately 44,000 Australians who have a debt with Centrelink have overpaid it, some by $20,000 or more, Guardian Australia can reveal.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is the latest in a string of scandals to hit Centrelink after hundreds of thousands of people &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/sep/26/more-than-300000-australians-had-centrelink-payments-cancelled-illegally-new-analysis-shows"&gt;had their payments illegally cancelled&lt;/a&gt;, with &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/mar/05/australia-mutual-obligation-system-it-system-error"&gt;several reviews&lt;/a&gt; concluding the welfare system is not working legally and the government announcing plans to undertake at least three remediation processes for separate issues – &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/sep/04/robodebt-victims-win-record-settlement-centrelink-government-compensation"&gt;the robodebt class action&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/aug/27/about-3m-australians-affected-by-unlawful-centrelink-debt-calculation-to-be-eligible-for-up-to-600-compensation"&gt;income apportionment&lt;/a&gt; and overpaid debts.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/revealed-some-australians-have-overpaid-their-centrelink-debt-by-more-than-20000"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/australia-news/2025/oct/24/revealed-some-australians-have-overpaid-their-centrelink-debt-by-more-than-20000</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 14:00:20 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>We need to start doing web blocking for non-technical reasons</title><link>https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/WeShouldBlockForSocialReasons?showcomments</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45681850"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://utcc.utoronto.ca/~cks/space/blog/web/WeShouldBlockForSocialReasons?showcomments</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:54:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Solar energy is going to power the world much sooner than you think</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe3vmb/solar_energy_is_going_to_power_the_world_much/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe3vmb/solar_energy_is_going_to_power_the_world_much/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Solar energy is going to power the world much sooner than you think" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/IBI_7wiKlGCTXgDNUIcfo6iV0-QqPiwwqIs0DVI7svo.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=81dae17762560dffca755b82a8bbd9d18cd6db4f" title="Solar energy is going to power the world much sooner than you think" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/Amazing-Yak-5415"&gt; /u/Amazing-Yak-5415 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.newscientist.com/article/2500013-solar-energy-is-going-to-power-the-world-much-sooner-than-you-think/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe3vmb/solar_energy_is_going_to_power_the_world_much/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oe3vmb/solar_energy_is_going_to_power_the_world_much/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:53:54 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Palestinian women giving birth in rubble on roads, says senior UN official, as he compares Gaza to dystopian film – as it happened</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/israel-west-bank-gaza-rubio-middle-east-latest-news-updates</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This blog is now closed – &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/middleeast"&gt;see all our Middle East coverage here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Turkish&lt;/strong&gt; peacekeeping forces will continue to help boost the &lt;strong&gt;Lebanese&lt;/strong&gt; army’s capability under a renewed deployment mandate in Lebanon, &lt;strong&gt;Turkey’s defence ministry&lt;/strong&gt; said on Thursday, reports Reuters.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Turkey’s parliament passed a bill on Tuesday to renew the military’s deployment mandates in &lt;strong&gt;Syria&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Iraq&lt;/strong&gt; by three more years, and its deployment mandate under the &lt;strong&gt;UN Interim Force in Lebanon (Unifil)&lt;/strong&gt; by two years. The ministry said in a statement:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Efforts will continue to improve security conditions in the region, ensure stability and assist in the capacity building of the Lebanese armed forces, with the aim of establishing and maintaining peace in Lebanon.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/israel-west-bank-gaza-rubio-middle-east-latest-news-updates"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/oct/23/israel-west-bank-gaza-rubio-middle-east-latest-news-updates</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:45:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Broadway musicians union reaches tentative deal to avoid strike</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2025/oct/23/broadway-musicians-union-deal-avoid-strike</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Strike was set to begin later on Thursday if union did not reach agreement on new contract with Broadway League&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The union representing Broadway musicians reached a tentative deal on a new contract early on Thursday morning, avoiding a potential strike that had been set to begin later that day and would have threatened many top shows in New York.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a &lt;a href="https://www.local802afm.org/2025/10/broadway-musicians-announce-tentative-agreement/"&gt;statement&lt;/a&gt;, the American Federation of Musicians Local 802 said it had reached the tentative agreement with the Broadway League – the trade association representing theater owners, producers and operators – around 4.30am on Thursday, preventing a “strike scheduled to begin later today”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2025/oct/23/broadway-musicians-union-deal-avoid-strike"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/stage/2025/oct/23/broadway-musicians-union-deal-avoid-strike</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:42:36 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>New images show Israeli control line deeper into Gaza than expected</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2y00g4x29o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>Israel has placed boundary markers up to 520m deeper inside Gaza than expected under the ceasefire deal with Hamas.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cx2y00g4x29o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:35:35 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>10/23/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/10-23-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Access National Security News HERE. Access Korean News HERE. National Security News: 1. U.S. Lifts Key Restriction on Ukraine’s Use of European Long-Range Missiles 2. . U.S. Imposes Substantial New Sanctions on Russian Oil Giants 3. U.S. Widens Campaign Against Alleged Drug Boats With Eastern Pacific Strike 4. Trump’s Been Bombing Boats in the Caribbean. Is This Legal? 5. The New Militarized War on Drugs—Time &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/10-23-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/10-23-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;10/23/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/10/23/10-23-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:35:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Caribbean Strikes and the Collapse of Legal Oversight in U.S. Military Operations</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/123172/caribbean-strikes-legal-oversight-us-military/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=caribbean-strikes-legal-oversight-us-military</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Congress and the public must do more to address the dangerous pressures imposed on public servants and defend the guardrails that protect both U.S. forces and U.S. democracy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/123172/caribbean-strikes-legal-oversight-us-military/"&gt;The Caribbean Strikes and the Collapse of Legal Oversight in U.S. Military Operations&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/123172/caribbean-strikes-legal-oversight-us-military/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=caribbean-strikes-legal-oversight-us-military</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:12:10 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>When Sexism Endangers Lives: In Israel, Sidelining Women Comes at the Cost of Security</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/121419/gender-security-israel/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gender-security-israel</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The October 7th massacre and unprecedented war in Gaza compel Israel to rethink its conception of security. It must include a gender-based analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/121419/gender-security-israel/"&gt;When Sexism Endangers Lives: In Israel, Sidelining Women Comes at the Cost of Security&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/121419/gender-security-israel/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=gender-security-israel</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 13:04:34 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russian Stocks Slide as U.S. Sanctions Hit Oil Majors</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/russian-stocks-slide-as-us-sanctions-hit-oil-majors-a90913</link><description>The MOEX Russia Index fell as much as 3.6%, hitting a low of 2,546, its weakest level in more than a week.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/russian-stocks-slide-as-us-sanctions-hit-oil-majors-a90913</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:55:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Distorted Laws on “Foreign Agents” Threaten Democracy: Mobilizing a Response</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/123043/foreign-agents-democracy-response/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=foreign-agents-democracy-response</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Civil society can share knowledge, boost public support, and build coalitions to resist the spread of autocratic "foreign agents" laws.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/123043/foreign-agents-democracy-response/"&gt;Distorted Laws on “Foreign Agents” Threaten Democracy: Mobilizing a Response&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/123043/foreign-agents-democracy-response/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=foreign-agents-democracy-response</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:49:37 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>I spent a year of my life making an ASN.1 compiler in D</title><link>https://bradley.chatha.dev/blog/dlang-propaganda/asn1-compiler-in-d/</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45681200"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://bradley.chatha.dev/blog/dlang-propaganda/asn1-compiler-in-d/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:47:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rubio warns against West Bank annexation after Israel's parliament advances move</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn8xvj108z9o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US Secretary of State says such a step would threaten Washington's plan to end the conflict in Gaza.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn8xvj108z9o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:42:25 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>French coastguards demand halt to ‘deadly plans’ to intercept small boats</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/french-coastguards-demand-halt-plans-intercept-small-boats-channel</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Union says UK-French Channel deal is inhumane and contravenes international conventions&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;French coastguards have called for plans to intercept small boats in the Channel to be halted because of the risk to life. The intervention came as the Home Office confirmed France was reviewing its “maritime doctrine” about the plan.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In a letter to the French customs director general, Florian Colas, the customs union Solidaires Douanes, which includes coastguards among its members, describes the plans to intercept small boats up to 300 metres from the French shore as “a deadly doctrine, which contravenes international conventions to which France is a signatory”.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/french-coastguards-demand-halt-plans-intercept-small-boats-channel"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/2025/oct/23/french-coastguards-demand-halt-plans-intercept-small-boats-channel</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:35:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>In First, British Warship Shadows Russian Navy Vessel in North Sea Under NATO Command</title><link>https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/in-first-british-warship-shadows-russian-navy-vessel-in-north-sea-under-nato-command-a90914</link><description>The Portsmouth-based HMS Duncan tracked the Russian anti-submarine ship Vice Admiral Kulakov as it transited the North Sea.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.themoscowtimes.com/2025/10/23/in-first-british-warship-shadows-russian-navy-vessel-in-north-sea-under-nato-command-a90914</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:21:18 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>US kills three in second strike on alleged drug boats in the Pacific</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c98n54ek04go?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>This is the ninth US strike on alleged drug boats near Latin America, and the second in the Pacific.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/c98n54ek04go?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:16:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Trump says 'existing structure' of White House East Wing to be torn down</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czxn7lwzx5po?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The US president previously said that his $250m (£186m) ballroom addition would not "interfere with the current building".</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/czxn7lwzx5po?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:16:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Early Edition: October 23, 2025</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/123171/early-edition-october-23-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=early-edition-october-23-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Signup to receive the Early Edition in your inbox here. A curated weekday guide to major news and developments over the last 24 hours. Here’s today’s news: ISRAEL-HAMAS WAR – CEASEFIRE Israel yesterday handed over the bodies of 54 unidentified Palestinians, most of whom were then buried at a grave site in Deir al-Balah, Gaza. [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/123171/early-edition-october-23-2025/"&gt;Early Edition: October 23, 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/123171/early-edition-october-23-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=early-edition-october-23-2025</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:15:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Show HN: Deta Surf – An open source and local-first AI notebook</title><link>https://github.com/deta/surf</link><description>&lt;a href="https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=45680937"&gt;Comments&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://github.com/deta/surf</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:11:27 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>France backing away from pledge to intercept migrant boats, sources tell BBC</title><link>https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn8vr95n5n3o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</link><description>The commitment has been hit by delays, with political turmoil in France partly to blame.</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.bbc.com/news/articles/cn8vr95n5n3o?at_medium=RSS&amp;at_campaign=rss</guid><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 12:07:29 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>