<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>William's Aggregated Feed</title><link>https://example.com</link><description>Merged RSS feed</description><lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:42:32 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>PyRSS2Gen-1.1.0</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Top 10 Books: International Women’s Day 2025</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-international-womens-day-2025-ec9c153f4c0d?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;To mark International Women’s Day this year, the official celebratory website asks us to ‘Imagine a gender equal world … A world where difference is valued and celebrated.’ This might feel like an arduous, if not utopian, demand on creativity, in a world where the far right is on the rise and women’s rights are increasingly encroached upon. For anyone in need of inspiration, Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira has curated a selection of outstanding books written by women that have been reviewed in the journal over the past year. As will become apparent to those who read further, this list is also partly a celebration of the women of &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, who have contributed to our diverse research offering over the years. Find out what this means below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The micro-sociology of peace and conflict&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*J66rzH8jCHV9KpIS8KpIfw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Isabel Bramsen. Published in Cambridge by Cambridge University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Isabel Bramsen’s 2022 &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/article/98/3/933/6553579"&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; in &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; drew on peace talks in the Philippines to argue that diplomatic meetings can generate social bonds between conflicting parties. In her latest book, &lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt; &lt;em&gt;micro-sociology of peace and conflict&lt;/em&gt;, Bramsen has expanded on the scope of the article’s insights, engaging with ‘micro-moments’ from the peace talks in the Philippines and Northern Ireland, to the everyday interactions at West Bank checkpoints and the reciprocal violence of the Arab Spring uprisings. Armed with an auspicious theoretical framework and a focus on video footage analysis, the author showcases how the micro-dynamics of different interactions can (de-)energize participants and lead to varying degrees of bonding or tension, which ultimately exemplify the relevance of micro-sociological approaches in IR.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae186"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The women of the far right&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dtMcUybM1zfslkp1R7mF6Q.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Eviane Leidig. Published in New York by Columbia University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Cynthia Enloe was to delve into the literature on far-right radicalization and ask: ‘Where are the women?’, Eviane Leidig’s book would provide the answer. &lt;em&gt;The women of the far right &lt;/em&gt;presents a multifaceted analysis of north American ‘influencers’ and the online spaces they occupy and instrumentalize. Leidig details how these women have sought to make far-right movements relatable and to generate socio-political acceptance of their ideologies. The book offers many new insights, exploring how these influencers were radicalized themselves, shedding light on the business and lifestyle dimensions of their online radicalization activities and contextualizing their impact within wider transnational networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae242"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Inside the UN Security Council&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*6tyPeFdqeRLld25dLV_7gg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Jess Gifkins. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The war in Darfur, Sudan, lasted almost three decades and many have asked what international society could have done differently. &lt;em&gt;Inside the UN Security Council&lt;/em&gt; critically appraises how the UNSC’s decision-making processes and questions of legitimacy dictated its approach to the conflict in Darfur. Jess Gifkins, who has previously &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiad177"&gt;written&lt;/a&gt; for &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; on the importance of queering the Responsibility to Protect doctrine, turns here to the importance of informal, unwritten legitimation practices within the UNSC. The book will appeal to a wide audience, as it illustrates the previously underplayed role of the ten non-permanent members, challenges rational models that overlook when actors choose to take action for optics and points to the implications of China’s increasing influence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae257"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Autocracy, Inc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bLPz4r3UUsgevJ1YF9JmeQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Anne Applebaum. Published in London by Allen Lane.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anne Applebaum’s latest book indicts both the autocratic leaders with global ambitions and the western politicians and kleptocrats that enable and profit from the activities of the former. &lt;em&gt;Autocracy, Inc.&lt;/em&gt; combines a fascinating account of how the autocrat’s involvement in sanctions-busting, arms trade and drug-dealing, combined with an eye-opening description of the ways in which a host of western banks, lawyers, real-estate agents and media sympathizers have lined their pockets with the profits from money-laundering activities. While Applebaum rounds off the book with suggestions for financial regulations and ‘de-risking’, readers are not advised to skip ahead, as this well-researched wake-up call should be thoroughly digested.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf026"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The uncertainty doctrine&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*9B4EDKTS9_OMJ9tR5Oo7kQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Alexandra Homolar. Published in Cambridge by Cambridge University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this fresh and ambitious take on the role of narratives in US foreign policy, Alexandra Homolar questions why the end of the Cold War brought about many changes to the international arena but spelled continuity for US security strategy. The author yields her archive-based chapters impressively to demonstrate the messiness of narratives, despite IR scholars’ wishes and efforts to impose order on them. Resorting to illustrative metaphors, the book demonstrates how US foreign policy elites built a post-Cold War security narrative through a process of entanglement and negotiation, as opposed to developing a masterminded vision. Watch out for the budget-friendly paperback launch this month!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf035"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Cosmopolitan elites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CSQvPCsEnhYiXbUg7Xyr3g.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Kira Huju. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connoisseurs of Kira Huju’s 2022 &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; article, ‘&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiab220"&gt;Saffronizing diplomacy: the Indian Foreign Service under Hindu nationalist rule&lt;/a&gt;’, will find Huju’s first book eminently rewarding. In &lt;em&gt;Cosmopolitan elites&lt;/em&gt;, Huju picks up the Indian Foreign Service (IFS) once again, to expose how class, caste, gender and religion shape its composition. The author brings in everyday practices and domestic hierarchies to illustrate the exclusionary codes that dictate participation in international society. The book benefits from a broad historical scope that allows Huju to document the enduring tension between the influence of colonial ideals and the aspirations of a postcolonial India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae188"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;PeaceTech&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*yRkCEQGECrHM9b8xE-Ea6A.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Christine Bell. Published in Cham, Switzerland by Springer.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this open-access and timely book, Christine Bell re-energizes the debate on how emerging technologies can be deployed in conflict and peacebuilding settings. Bell warns against the appeal of ‘shiny new things’ and questions the assumption that digital innovation can automatically improve peacebuilding practices. The author explores the drivers behind the agendas and investment decisions that shape peacebuilding endeavours. Equally candid and inspirational, the book puts forward a twelve-step manifesto on ensuring that digital tools support peace processes. As a long-time practitioner and scholar, Bell is well placed to provide insights that will benefit anyone interested in the digitization of contemporary dynamics of peace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf047"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Governing the feminist peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*GRRJr6AyRFFAi4nTLPIWDA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Paul Kirby and Laura J. Shepherd. Published in New York by Columbia University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond its brilliantly illustrated cover, this co-authored book has a much wider appeal. Paul Kirby and Laura Shepherd have teamed up for a provocative and convincing critique of the Women, Peace and Security (WPS) agenda, as a product of specific global governance frameworks. Deploying some impressive empirical research, &lt;em&gt;Governing the feminist peace&lt;/em&gt; persuasively highlights the incoherent, contested and contingent nature of the WPS discourse, particularly as it features in the fields of policy and governance. In the words of our reviewer: ‘forgetting WPS, in the way that Kirby and Shepherd suggest, might provide an opportunity to expand the ethical imaginaries of war and peace’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae203"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Reluctance in world politics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sandra Destradi. Published in Bristol by Bristol University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*A3Ve8OoQmtovGx-BbmXdIg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last year, our November issue featured a highly popular special section on ‘&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae217"&gt;The effects of global populism&lt;/a&gt;’, guest-edited by Sandra Destradi with Daniel F. Wajner and Michael Zürn. As a multifaceted scholar, Destradi’s most recent book before that sought to explain why powerful states fail to act decisively in the face of crises within their spheres of influence. To explain this phenomenon, the author offers a new and multidimensional theory of reluctance that breaks with the idea that ‘reluctant hegemons’ are unwilling to lead. Destradi compares the case-studies of Brazil, Germany and India, illustrating their policy choices through an impressive combination of expert interviews and policy analysis.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae214"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10)&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Police peacekeeping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Lou Pingeot. Published in New York and Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*p4vtk9bZ46cfLB32auLcIQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Police peacekeeping&lt;/em&gt;, Lou Pingeot tackles the United Nations’ deployment of police units in its peace operations through the case-study of the UN mission in Haiti (2004–17). This impressive feat of ethnographic and interdisciplinary research traces the emergence of peacebuilding and global policing, offering a stark reminder of their colonial histories: policing models designed to pacify the populations deemed as a risk to social orders are deployed abroad with important implications for the global social order. In the words of our reviewer, this book is ‘essential reading for those researching and developing policy guidance for peacekeeping, military and humanitarian interventions, as well as for those interested in the reproduction of global inequalities’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae258"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our March 2025 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/2"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;social media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post regular call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=ec9c153f4c0d" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-international-womens-day-2025-ec9c153f4c0d"&gt;Top 10 Books: International Women’s Day 2025&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-international-womens-day-2025-ec9c153f4c0d?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 16:09:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top 10 books: The International Affairs Christmas reading list 2024</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-the-international-affairs-christmas-reading-list-b01a06458d70?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;The holidays offer the perfect excuse to read a book from cover to cover and our Christmas reading list has excellent suggestions for the international relations enthusiast. This year, Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira was inspired by the regional spread of the books reviewed for the journal and this hand-picked selection spotlights a wide range of locales, from Australia, Cuba, Egypt and Haiti, to India, Iran, Tanzania and Uganda. And because diversity is not simply a matter of geography, the books featured also vary thematically, speaking to issues of defence, interventionism, gender, postcolonial imaginations and more!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) The unfinished quest&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*jKOEVJ4yFn5XNBnJS0EBew.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by T.V. Paul. Published in New York by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;The unfinished quest&lt;/em&gt;, T.V. Paul examines India’s pursuit of great power status since it gained its independence in 1947. The book combines a historical view of origins, causes and drivers with an assessment of the country’s hard and soft power capabilities, including its domestic and international practices. Paul points to how the gap between India’s status ambitions and its material capabilities to achieve them is closing. Despite its promising progress, Paul contends that India must address certain human development challenges before it can achieve the greater recognition that it seeks. An excellent read, utterly timely and accessible.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae255"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) What really went wrong&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*q5OexdTZu5-7gV42s7TubQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Fawaz A. Gerges. Published in New Haven, CT by Yale University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of regional and distinguished veterans with a regional expertise, Fawaz A. Gerges’s latest book spotlights the West’s destabilizing role in the Middle East. The author argues that US interventions at the height of the Cold War largely contributed to the regional ‘failure of democracy’. The book features case-studies of Iran and Egypt, exploring the CIA’s toppling of Iran’s elected Prime Minister Mohammed Mossadegh in 1953 and the US’ alienation of Egyptian President Gamal Abdel Nasser. Gerges’s useful and tactful counterfactual approach to the ‘seeds of instability’ prompts readers to reflect on the political trajectories of both countries and on the realm of possibilities that western interventionism foreclosed in the region.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae252"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Intervention before interventionism&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Au3EPW10rxc3OwvybIboSg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Patrick Quinton-Brown. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this feat of genealogical prowess, Singapore-based Patrick Quinton-Brown traces and problematizes the origins and development of the concept of intervention in international relations. Drawing on a wealth of archival research, the book navigates the post-1945 debates on interventionism, sovereignty and self-determination, displacing the mainstream Westphalian discourses and recovering the global South perspectives and contributions. Our Review Forum on &lt;em&gt;Intervention before interventionism&lt;/em&gt; offers an instructive, careful and inspiring dialogue on the book’s aims to lay out ‘a series of alternatives at a time when non-intervention, quite suddenly, seems everywhere’. Explore contributions from Robbie Shilliam, Jennifer M. Welsh and more below.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the Review Forum &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae264"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Our comrades in Havana&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*8u6yZY3nrD_yR3kSgmHvkg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Radoslav Yordanov. Published in Stanford, CA by Stanford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While existing research focuses largely on the Soviet–Cuban bilateral ties, &lt;em&gt;Our comrades in Havana&lt;/em&gt; reveals the ‘complex and often adversarial relationship between the various actors’ without losing sight of Cuba’s agency and its international activism. Radoslav Yordanov foregrounds Cuba’s relationships with the Soviet bloc through a series of chronological events, including Cuba’s formal entrance and subsequent economic dependence on the Council for Mutual Economic Assistance. Yordanov’s dedication to recently declassified records from eastern European states allows the author to detail developments such as Cuba’s disappointment with the lack of support for its active role in the Third World and East Germany’s contributions to Cuba’s intelligence capabilities. This book broadens the horizons of Cold War historiography and whets the appetite of global history enthusiasts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae260"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) The face of the nation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*ODaMoiZqqtTLW7NxSQx8JA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Elise Stephenson. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The face of the nation&lt;/em&gt; integrates historical institutional analysis with women’s narratives to investigate the extent, nuance and dynamics of gender discrimination and sexism within the sphere of Australian international affairs. In it, Elise Stephenson, the deputy director of the Global Institute for Women’s Leadership, focuses on different institutions and pays special attention to the Department of Foreign Affairs and Trade (DFAT). While women’s representation within the DFAT has increased, the institution is shrinking in power and funding as other defence agencies are expanding. The book’s dozens of interviews with women in senior positions, including Australia’s first female prime minister, Julia Gillard, will also benefit anyone interested in diplomacy and women’s experiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae189"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6) NATO&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*fnQR0rfDsNoF_z_yXD-3Ug.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sten Rynning. Published in New Haven, CT by Yale University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt;’ first Review Forum of 2024 provides an in-depth appraisal of Sten Rynning’s timely book &lt;em&gt;NATO: from Cold War to Ukraine, a history of the world’s most powerful alliance&lt;/em&gt;. In the forum, four experts examine Rynning’s accessible history of the alliance, the author’s understanding of the most suitable role for NATO and his policy recommendations to ensure NATO remains at its best (in its classic Europe-focused format). The book does an excellent job of emphasizing the cyclical nature of NATO’s existence, from crisis to opportunities, and Rynning usefully navigates the current challenges that the alliance faces.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the Review Forum &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae150"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7) Wealth, power, and authoritarian institutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*OSuO8nSG5WE9OyslEaeAXw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Michaela Collord. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In her debut monograph, Michaela Collord develops a convincing comparison of how ruling elites, particularly party leaders, have accumulated and invested wealth with institutional repercussions for parliaments in Uganda and Tanzania. &lt;em&gt;Wealth, power, and authoritarian institutions&lt;/em&gt; draws contrasts between the neighbouring countries, showcasing how centralized resource accumulation has hindered legislative autonomy in Tanzania and how elite enrichment has made it almost impossible to instil party discipline in Uganda. Collord offers a persuasive account of east African politics and the key individuals that, through loyalty and prestige, have successfully leveraged elite factional rivalries within their respective parliaments.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae241"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8) Post-imperial possibilities&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*tok-KvY26AMCEWngJHsChw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Jane Burbank and Frederick Cooper. Published in Princeton, NJ and Oxford by Princeton University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you know of Jane Burbank and Frederick Cooper, then this recommendation is hardly necessary. However, if you are not acquainted with their ground-breaking 2010 work &lt;em&gt;Empires in world history&lt;/em&gt;, do yourself a favour: pick it up and quickly follow up with &lt;em&gt;Post-imperial possibilities&lt;/em&gt;. Burbank and Cooper are back (and better than ever) with this exploration of three hypothetical world visions that emerged in the global South during the wave of decolonization. The book investigates the origins, premises and merits of ideas of Eurafrica, Eurasia and Afroasia as future possibilities at a time of hopeful, rapid and drastic change. The book straddles both mid-twentieth-century history and more recent developments, questioning the inevitability of the nation-state model of statehood. An original and extraordinary book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae141"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9) The women of the far right&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*J1YMNh8DX6pkyZmJpk8JIA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Eviane Leidig. Published in New York by Columbia University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Cynthia Enloe was to delve into the literature on far-right radicalization and ask: ‘Where are the women?’, Eviane Leidig’s book would provide the answer. &lt;em&gt;The women of the far right&lt;/em&gt; presents a multifaceted analysis of north American ‘influencers’ and the online spaces they occupy and instrumentalize. Leidig details how these women have sought to make far-right movements relatable and to generate socio-political acceptance of their ideologies. The book offers many new insights, exploring how these influencers were radicalized themselves, shedding light on the business and lifestyle dimensions of their online radicalization activities and contextualizing their impact within wider transnational networks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae242"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10) Police peacekeeping&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0b7K17oF-LRyBxv9LgYbFg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Lou Pingeot. Published in New York and Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Police peacekeeping&lt;/em&gt;, Lou Pingeot tackles the United Nations’ deployment of police units in its peace operations through the case-study of the UN mission in Haiti (2004–17). This impressive feat of ethnographic and interdisciplinary research traces the emergence of peacebuilding and global policing, offering a stark reminder of their colonial histories: policing models designed to pacify the populations deemed as a risk to social orders are deployed abroad with important implications for the global social order. In the words of our reviewer, this book is ‘essential reading for those researching and developing policy guidance for peacekeeping, military and humanitarian interventions, as well as for those interested in the reproduction of global inequalities’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae258"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our November 2024 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/100/6#2022851-7852680"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;social media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post regular call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=b01a06458d70" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-the-international-affairs-christmas-reading-list-b01a06458d70"&gt;Top 10 books: The International Affairs Christmas reading list 2024&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-10-books-the-international-affairs-christmas-reading-list-b01a06458d70?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Thu, 12 Dec 2024 12:22:08 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Has Trump Changed?</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/has-trump-changed-b0c660da1858?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;h4&gt;Juliet Kaarbo discusses Trump’s ‘changed personality’ and how it may affect his second term.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*bsuh6Im_SKVksFgqjEGsaQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;In his first press conference after the 2024 US election, President-elect &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.pbs.org/newshour/politics/7-takeaways-from-trumps-1st-news-conference-since-his-reelection"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Donald Trump claimed that his personality changed&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; from his first term, and for the better. However, analysing Trump during the 2024 campaign, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/06/us/politics/trump-speeches-age-cognitive-decline.html"&gt;&lt;em&gt;others&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; have sounded alarm bells about his mental state and what that might mean for his leadership. Such speculation as to what might be different about a Trump 2.0 administration, and about Trump himself, begs the question: do leaders ever really change?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do leaders ever change?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Research in psychology supports the idea that leaders have stable personalities. This is because their general world-views, characteristics and motivations stem from their socio-cultural backgrounds and genetic factors, which do not change over time. This has been a long-held and broadly supported view in both psychology and the subfield of political psychology.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, some research challenges the notion that leaders are set in their ways. For example, &lt;a href="https://journals.sagepub.com/doi/10.5964/ps.6009"&gt;modern personality research&lt;/a&gt; highlights how humans undergo personality changes during periods of transition. Studies have also shown that &lt;a href="https://wires.onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/abs/10.1002/wcs.1539?casa_token=85SAnfWPfGkAAAAA%3Afd3NcXN8Q3vo1G7CuSdvBtVDMXT4cs62tgpHajvNjd35qSN-EreXIzTVFijBgxVpQee_2cIqMgr4cHo"&gt;belief systems are more pliable&lt;/a&gt; than once thought, and that leaders can experience &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaa221"&gt;significant changes&lt;/a&gt;. Moreover, power itself alters us, even &lt;a href="https://www.oveo.org/fichiers/power-changes-how-the-brain-responds-to-others.pdf"&gt;neurologically&lt;/a&gt;, often generating more &lt;a href="https://www.annualreviews.org/content/journals/10.1146/annurev-psych-010416-044153"&gt;self-confidence, self-entitlement and self-serving behaviours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Has Trump changed since 2016?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;So, what about Trump? Were four years of presidency enough to change him? Consistent with the ‘people are stable’ view, we would not expect Trump’s second term to be dramatically different to his first. Indeed, some of the traits that Trump displayed in his first presidency, such as his &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/09557571.2021.1879018"&gt;intense distrust of others&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/article/96/2/383/5722298"&gt;ultra-sensitivity to criticism, in addition to his tendency to challenge or ignore norms&lt;/a&gt; and his &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/article/99/2/605/7069031"&gt;transactional and ‘America First’ world-views&lt;/a&gt;, continue to reflect in his words and actions today.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yet, key developments could have changed Trump. For one, Trump is not as politically inexperienced as he was when he first took office. Thus, there is a possibility that he may be even less likely to listen to advice this time around. Furthermore, at 78, Trump may be experiencing age-related changes, perhaps thinking in short time horizons, &lt;a href="https://www.jstor.org/stable/45293419"&gt;reflecting on mortality&lt;/a&gt;, or experiencing the psychological effects of age-related medical conditions. While old age does not affect all people in the same way, we might expect cognitive decline, heightened emotionality and an increased focus on legacy, which could lead to more risk-taking and authoritarian practices. For example, &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/01/13/us/politics/trump-greenland-canada-history.html"&gt;Trump 2.0’s references to ‘manifest destiny’ and his threats to take Greenland&lt;/a&gt; may stem from a motivation to leave a legacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Another way Trump might have changed is in learning what did and didn’t work during his first term. For example, Trump seems to have concluded that loyalty, as a quality in his advisers, should be the predominant criterion for his appointments. We clearly see this in his new &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/11/14/podcasts/the-daily/trump-cabinet.html"&gt;cabinet choices &lt;/a&gt;which have been shaped more by candidates’ devotion to Trump than by their having suitable experience for the positions, and also in the &lt;a href="https://www.forbes.com/sites/tylerroush/2025/02/03/what-is-elon-musks-role-exactly-white-house-calls-him-special-government-employee-heres-what-that-means/"&gt;exceptional informal power Trump has granted Elon Musk&lt;/a&gt;. Additionally, in his first term Trump learned the constraints that bureaucracy can place on presidents. These limitations were highly incongruent with Trump’s previous experience as a CEO where he had much more autonomy. As a result, Trump learned to assert &lt;a href="https://trumpwhitehouse.archives.gov/presidential-actions/executive-order-creating-schedule-f-excepted-service/"&gt;greater control over non-political appointees&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/news/q-and-a/donald-trumps-plan-to-make-the-presidency-more-like-a-kingship"&gt;independent agencies&lt;/a&gt;. Such centralization of authority and decision-making may intensify to avoid the frustration he experienced in his first term. We already see this in Trump’s attempts to reshape the federal bureaucracy, which have included &lt;a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/articles/cdjdmx12j9no"&gt;threats to close agencies, such as USAID.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Finally, dramatic events in the first Trump administration and the inter-term period may have triggered key changes in Trump. The first impeachment trial, for example, reportedly infuriated him, affecting both his &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/04/29/podcasts/the-daily/second-trump-presidency.html?searchResultPosition=3"&gt;view of a ‘deep state’&lt;/a&gt; within his administration and his &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/article/99/2/605/7069031?searchresult=1"&gt;orientation toward Ukraine&lt;/a&gt;. His defeat in the 2020 election, and his inability to overturn the election results, only strengthened this vengeance motive against those who he feels wronged him. For example, in the early days of his second presidency, Trump &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/feb/01/trump-purge-at-justice-department-of-january-6-prosecutors-and-threat-to-fbi-agents"&gt;fired Justice Department personnel who were involved in January 6 investigations&lt;/a&gt; and also&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jan/23/mike-pompeo-brian-hook-john-bolton-security"&gt; revoked federal protection for his former advisers-turned-critics&lt;/a&gt;. Furthermore, Trump’s success in 2024 (and his survival of two assassination attempts) may have created a strong feeling of invincibility and &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/brain/article-abstract/132/5/1396/354862?redirectedFrom=fulltext"&gt;hubris syndrome&lt;/a&gt;. Trump’s bold self-confidence is evident early in his second term, and can be seen in his numerous, sweeping &lt;a href="https://www.federalregister.gov/presidential-documents/executive-orders/donald-trump/2025"&gt;executive orders&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/fact-sheets/2025/02/fact-sheet-president-donald-j-trump-imposes-tariffs-on-imports-from-canada-mexico-and-china/"&gt;extraordinary tariffs levelled against economic allies&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/gb/podcast/donald-trump-vs-the-world-plus-are-china-and/id1744345702?i=1000687499670"&gt;bullying of Panama and Colombia&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A heightened version of the same Trump?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Experiences of his first presidency, changes triggered by age and key events have not generated an entirely new Trump; rather, they have reinforced his existing beliefs, characteristics and motivations. So, what we likely have now is a more extreme and experienced version of Trump 1.0. He may have always been &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2024/10/11/podcasts/the-daily/trump-revenge.html"&gt;vindictive&lt;/a&gt; towards those he perceived as threatening, but now he has more targets and deeper knowledge of how to use the powers of presidency.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether any changes in Trump’s character will affect his policy-making and governance partly depends on where he focuses his efforts. As in his first term, Trump may be &lt;a href="https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/09557571.2021.1879018"&gt;predictably unpredictable&lt;/a&gt; regarding which policy areas and political actors attract his attention. But what we do know is that Trump 2.0 has come to office with a clearer focus on strengthening his powers and surrounding himself with like-minded people — these are the key differences thus far. How Trump interprets and builds on his experience in his second term can further alter (and reinforce) who he is, with significant consequences for the US and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Juliet Kaarbo, Professor of Foreign Policy, University of St Andrews, Leverhulme Trust Major Research Fellow.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more about this topic in the full article ‘&lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaa221"&gt;&lt;em&gt;New directions for leader personality research: breaking bad in foreign policy&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;’, published in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=b0c660da1858" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/has-trump-changed-b0c660da1858"&gt;Has Trump Changed?&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/has-trump-changed-b0c660da1858?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 15:42:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>What feminism can do for cybersecurity</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/what-feminism-can-do-for-cybersecurity-486035bc7d5a?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;h4&gt;Anwar Mhajne and Crystal Whetstone show why cybersecurity needs to be understood from a feminist lens.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0mxGMOaeY3EDXy8o4zZWLQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A woman walks past a tech fair during the CyberSec 2024 in Taipei on 14 May 2024. Photo by Sam Yeh / AFP via &lt;a href="https://www.gettyimages.co.uk/detail/news-photo/woman-walks-past-a-display-at-a-tech-fair-on-cyber-security-news-photo/2152327974?adppopup=true"&gt;Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, within International Relations (IR) cybersecurity has often been viewed through a realist, state-centric lens as an instrument of national security. However, viewing cybersecurity as such masks its implications for human rights and human security. For instance, not only do democratic and non-democratic governments exploit this conception of cybersecurity to justify espionage, censorship, surveillance and disinformation, but they may also label criticism as ‘fake news’ and pressure businesses for access to personal data to verify it. In this context, some scholars question the utility of the term ‘cybersecurity’ itself, believing it may perpetuate militarized policies. Others suggest adopting a ‘&lt;a href="https://www.research.ed.ac.uk/en/publications/what-can-a-critical-cybersecurity-do"&gt;pluriversal cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt;’ to encompass diverse perspectives beyond state and corporate security.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this blogpost, we build on our &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae234"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Affairs &lt;/em&gt;article&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to make the case for understanding cybersecurity from a feminist perspective. A feminist lens would help emphasize security’s multifaceted nature and provide interdisciplinary ways of thinking about cyber(in)security and violence. We show how this can be achieved by incorporating insights from feminist security studies (FSS) that can help decentre the state, shift the focus to human rights protections in cyberspace and interrogate who is served by traditional cybersecurity approaches.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What feminism can bring to cybersecurity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We use &lt;a href="https://www.taylorfrancis.com/books/mono/10.4324/9780429453458/global-gender-politics-anne-sisson-runyan"&gt;Anne Runyan’s &lt;/a&gt;gendered lens to develop a more comprehensive understanding of cybersecurity. This approach uses intersectionality to explore how gender, race, class and sexuality collectively influence people’s experiences under dynamic power structures and oppressions. It provides crucial insights into the everyday experiences of cyber violence, ranging from &lt;a href="https://www.unfpa.org/TFGBV"&gt;technology-facilitated gender-based violence&lt;/a&gt; (TF-GBV) and attacks on critical infrastructure to cyberharassment, all of which more significantly affect people from marginalized backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae234"&gt;A feminist cybersecurity: addressing the crisis of cyber(in)security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;FSS scholars contend that security extends beyond nation-states. Rather, they expand the mainstream notion of cybersecurity by focusing on the security of ordinary individuals. This approach captures many vulnerabilities that are often overlooked in traditional discussions on cybersecurity. For example, cyberharassment, particularly TF-GBV, impacts &lt;a href="https://www.unwomen.org/sites/default/files/2023-04/Technology-facilitated-violence-against-women-Taking-stock-of-evidence-and-data-collection-en.pdf"&gt;women, children, and gender diverse and queer people&lt;/a&gt; and those from &lt;a href="https://glitchcharity.co.uk/wp-content/uploads/2023/07/Glitch-Misogynoir-Report_Final_18Jul_v5_Single-Pages.pdf"&gt;marginalized backgrounds&lt;/a&gt; to a greater degree than it impacts men and other hegemonic groups due to racialization and their status as minorities. Yet, most governments and traditional security actors do not pay enough attention to this violence, given their limited focus on state security, as seen in the &lt;a href="https://www.whitehouse.gov/wp-content/uploads/2023/03/National-Cybersecurity-Strategy-2023.pdf"&gt;US government’s&lt;/a&gt; national cybersecurity strategy and &lt;a href="https://www.nato.int/cps/en/natohq/topics_78170.htm"&gt;NATO&lt;/a&gt;’s cyber defence policy. Ultimately, FSS challenges this by advocating for a more inclusive understanding that accounts for the diverse and everyday cyber insecurities faced by people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How a feminist cybersecurity can be achieved&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Feminist studies scholars recommend democratizing the theory and practice of cybersecurity. They encourage acknowledging the agency of those who directly experience cyber insecurities and actively involving them in matters of peace and security without relying on militarization. For example, instead of promoting a state-centred, top-down approach to designing frameworks to ‘secure’ cyberspace, international legislation could incorporate a gendered lens that engages civil society. Such efforts can address cyber-based human rights violations while avoiding a damaging cyber arms race.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;We recommend establishing a cybersecurity treaty for the protection of civil liberties and rights for all, informed by marginalized groups such as queer communities and those from the global South. Such a framework must avoid being co-opted by powerful nations and must be a participatory process that includes grassroots collaborations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initiatives in which the voices of marginalized communities are prioritized have proved effective in the past. For example, the &lt;a href="https://www.nti.org/education-center/treaties-and-regimes/treaty-on-the-prohibition-of-nuclear-weapons/"&gt;Treaty on the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons&lt;/a&gt; saw great participation by those in non-nuclear states and civil society, and demonstrates the effectiveness of the involvement of the global South and civil society in crafting solid protections. A bottom-up approach could create an inclusive cybersecurity standard, moving beyond a protector/protected binary centred only on looking after users in the West and fostering genuine global cooperation in safeguarding online civil liberties.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Building cybersecurity from a feminist perspective involves ensuring access to cyberspace with human rights protections for all, which can be achieved through demilitarization that addresses the unique insecurities of different groups. A feminist cybersecurity framework emphasizes the rights of marginalized communities by acknowledging harms caused by disinformation, cyberbullying, suppression and TF-GBV. An FSS approach reveals often unseen violence through intersectionality and a broader understanding of security. While insecurities in the cyber(in)security crisis cannot be fully eliminated, they can be reduced by everyday individuals working to democratize cybersecurity practices.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more about this topic in the full article &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae234"&gt;&lt;em&gt;‘&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;A feminist cybersecurity: addressing the crisis of cyber(in)security’&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;It was published in the November issue of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae234"&gt;A feminist cybersecurity: addressing the crisis of cyber(in)security&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Anwar Mhajne is an Associate Professor of Political Science and International Studies at Stonehill College, US. Crystal Whetstone is an Assistant Professor at the Department of International Relations at Bilkent University, Turkey.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=486035bc7d5a" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/what-feminism-can-do-for-cybersecurity-486035bc7d5a"&gt;What feminism can do for cybersecurity&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/what-feminism-can-do-for-cybersecurity-486035bc7d5a?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 14:12:57 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>2016 U.S.-Japan Security Seminar</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/2016-us-japan-security-seminar</link><description>&lt;span&gt;2016 U.S.-Japan Security Seminar&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Michael J. Green interviews JIIA President Yoshiji Nogami&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Fri, 02/26/2016 - 12:54
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/michael-j-green" hreflang="en"&gt;Michael J. Green&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Japan Chair&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" hreflang="en"&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/40649/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;AdobeStock_179685887.jpeg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The mission of the CSIS Japan Chair is to be the leading source of analytic insight and policy-relevant research on Japan, the U.S.-Japan alliance, and Japan’s leadership on the global stage&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://live-csis.pantheonsite.io/programs/japan-chair/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://live-csis.pantheonsite.io/programs/japan-chair/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/japan-chair-charter"&gt;Charter&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/japan-chair-archives"&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/projects/us-japan-security-seminar" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The U.S.-Japan Security Seminar&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/japan-chair/projects" hreflang="en"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/56678/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;GettyImages-72567357_cropped.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;A premier forum for intellectual exchange on prevailing themes in U.S.-Japan relations&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/58479/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;CSIS_ Geopolitics.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Geopolitics and Foreign Policy Department examines the key political, economic, security, and societal trends shaping the future of global governance and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With deep regional expertise and strong global relationships across Africa, Americas, Europe, Eurasia, Russia, Indo-Pacific, and Middle East, our experts offer comprehensive analysis to guide policymakers in navigating the evolving challenges to U.S. global leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Regions
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia" hreflang="en"&gt;Asia&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/japan" hreflang="en"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Fri, 03/04/2016 - 15:00
 - Fri, 03/04/2016 - 17:00

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/2016-us-japan-security-seminar</guid><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2016 17:54:32 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>China Reality Check: China's "Internet Sovereignty" Initiative: Origins and Consequences</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/china-reality-check-chinas-internet-sovereignty-initiative-origins-and-consequences</link><description>&lt;span&gt;China Reality Check: China's "Internet Sovereignty" Initiative: Origins and Consequences &lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please join us for a discussion on China’s initiative to promote Internet sovereignty as a key governing concept of the global Internet.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Tue, 02/16/2016 - 11:49
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/scott-kennedy" hreflang="en"&gt;Scott Kennedy&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chinese Business and Economics&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/economic-security-and-technology" hreflang="en"&gt;Economic Security and Technology&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/45102/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;230210_Trustee_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;We provide unparalleled thought leadership for the policy community by examining the hidden dynamics of China’s economy and its implications for industries and other countries&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://bigdatachina.csis.org/"&gt;Big Data China&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/blogs/trustee-china-hand"&gt;Trustee China Hand&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/podcasts/china-field-notes-scott-kennedy"&gt;China Field Notes Podcast&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/chinese-business-and-economics/newsletters"&gt;Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Freeman Chair in China Studies&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" hreflang="en"&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/65520/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;GettyImages-2059987068_cropped1.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Freeman Chair in China Studies is a leading source of insight and analysis on China’s evolving political system, domestic agenda, and foreign policy&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/interpret-china"&gt;Interpret: China&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/chinese-leadership-chart"&gt;Chinese Leadership Chart&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/past-projects/china-reality-check" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;China Reality Check&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/projects" hreflang="en"&gt;Projects &lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1195/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Kremlin.ru / Wikimedia&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The China Reality Check Series presents perspectives from academia, industry, and government in order to promote a sustained dialogue on critical and insufficiently understood issues related to China's reemergence as a global power&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/58479/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;CSIS_ Geopolitics.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Geopolitics and Foreign Policy Department examines the key political, economic, security, and societal trends shaping the future of global governance and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With deep regional expertise and strong global relationships across Africa, Americas, Europe, Eurasia, Russia, Indo-Pacific, and Middle East, our experts offer comprehensive analysis to guide policymakers in navigating the evolving challenges to U.S. global leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/economic-security-and-technology" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Economic Security and Technology&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59027/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_EST_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Economic Security and Technology Department examines the most pressing issues facing the United States and its partners in sustaining economic and technological advantages essential to prosperity, security, and resilience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With unique breadth and depth of expertise across economic policy, global markets, and advanced technologies, we provide strategic insights and practical solutions to drive competitiveness, technology leadership and economic security amid global threats.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Regions
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/china" hreflang="en"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/technology" hreflang="en"&gt;Technology&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/technology/technology-and-innovation" hreflang="en"&gt;Technology and Innovation&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Tue, 03/01/2016 - 12:00
 - Tue, 03/01/2016 - 13:30

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/china-reality-check-chinas-internet-sovereignty-initiative-origins-and-consequences</guid><pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2016 16:49:43 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The International Affairs summer reading list 2025</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/the-international-affairs-summer-reading-list-2025-25822cd8643f?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;There is nothing quite like spending the summer lost within the pages of a great book — or ten. Every year, Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira shares her top ten books, recently reviewed in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Affairs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, to help you navigate the latest titles and pick your summer reading with guaranteed success.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Explore the selection below, rich in new historical and theoretical perspectives as well as unexpected takes on global governance, which celebrate a variety of different publishers. And the cherry on top of the cake? More than half of the books are written by women, who — as the first title illustrates — have been consistently erased from the discipline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Erased&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*xviMfDfbSHEj_GSZC7u4dA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Patricia Owens. Published in Princeton, NJ by Princeton University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For fans of Patricia Owens’s previous collaborations, &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiac292"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Women’s international thought: a new history&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiab077"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Women’s international thought: towards a new canon&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Erased: a history of international thought without men&lt;/em&gt; is a highly anticipated and entirely complimentary book. In this new book, Owens unearths the contributions of 18 women to bury any narratives of the International Relations (IR) discipline as a story of elite white men. While spotlighting their academic merits, especially on the debate around empire and race in IR, Owens also enquires about these women’s careers and lives: where were they able to secure writing opportunities? Which powerful men played a role in their personal and professional lives? This unique intellectual history covers it all.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf132"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Rise of the international&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*0yV9DxlqeIndNcvIaUP65Q.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited by Richard Devetak and Tim Dunne. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since Jeremy Bentham coined the term ‘international’ in eighteenth-century England, the concept has travelled far and wide, often through the imperial and colonial channels. This dynamic edited volume brings historians and theorists of International Relations (IR) into conversation to investigate the diversity of internationals, their varied conceptualizations and the different contexts that led to their emergence. The chapters are actor-driven, focusing on how several conceived of the ‘international’ and showcasing how the concept was understood, contested and developed in different socio-political spaces. The ideal book for anyone who wants to understand the ways in which the ‘international’ always remains plural.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf126"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Living the Asian century&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*pIYru_c64WJYzQo5OBEkxg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Kishore Mahbubani. Published in New York by PublicAffairs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most contemporary international affairs observers, Kishore Mahbubani needs no introduction. However, if one must be offered, this memoir is the perfect window into the life of former Singaporean diplomat and leading thinker on the role of Asian superpowers in the declining US-led international order. In &lt;em&gt;Living the Asian century&lt;/em&gt;, Mahbubani draws on his decades of experience, including at the United Nations, to expose the US dominance in the organization and to offer sobering and inspiring advice for policy-makers from small states. Combining deeply personal experiences and anecdotes, Mahbubani’s lessons from and for diplomacy are wide-ranging and relevant for students of Asian politics and practitioners of world affairs.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf114"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Unexpected revolutionaries&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Y9VYWpL1ZMt4fGn3HPva7g.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Manuela Moschella. Published in Ithaca, NY by Cornell University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this brilliant addition to the literature, former Chatham House Associate Fellow Manuela Moschella looks at how central banks’ incentives to expand their toolboxes and their scope are largely a result of imperatives for institutional adaptation. The author analyses the success stories of the United States Federal Reserve and the European Central Bank to underscore her central argument that banks’ strategic behaviour matters and that they often enact changes to build support, preserve their power and maintain their independence. An insightful and timely book in the age of political backlash against technocratic decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf116"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Assembly by design&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_UOedt_q34To57VUQAi8qw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Olga Touloumi. Published in Minneapolis, MN by University of Minnesota Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;What does the architecture of the United Nations headquarters tell us about the organization? According to Olga Toulomi, efforts to make the UN architecturally different from its predecessor reveal the tension between the institution’s inclusionary and exclusionary impulses. This expertly titled book turns to spatial politics to illustrate the physical shape of these impulses, as well as the relationship between the core (UN headquarters) and its periphery (the UN’s operational field). As our reviewer concludes, the UN site confirms that ‘while the UN’s global interior is designed to speak to the world, it has a limited capacity to listen to it’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf122"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Good victims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*nYPHpLVnpSD8gllvGNhi3w.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Roxani Krystalli. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a book makes it to the British International Studies Association &lt;a href="https://www.bisa.ac.uk/news/lhm-ling-outstanding-first-book-prize-2025-shortlist-announced"&gt;outstanding first book prize shortlist&lt;/a&gt;, you know it is going to be worth your time. If it also receives a stellar review in &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt;, then you should be wondering why you have not read it yet. In her first book, Roxani Krystalli delves into the Colombian transitional justice context to provide a ‘caring and graceful’ examination of what it means to be a good victim in the eyes of the institutions and bureaucracies that dispatch justice in post-conflict settings. Krystalli’s exploration of the performative aspects of victimhood draws on more than 150 interviews to render visible the institutional expectations, costs and dangers of discreet identities of ‘good’ and ‘bad’ victims, in a contribution to feminist studies that will not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf077"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The derecognition of states&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*DEj-lAN9-4zPRk9Xpf46aw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Gëzim Visoka. Published in Ann Arbor, MI by Michigan University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The criteria for state sovereignty and state recognition have been widely debated in the disciplines for decades. But what about derecognition? In this open-access book, Gëzim Visoka draws on five case-studies to explain why states withdraw recognition, what rationales they offer and what regional consequences these processes can have. From Kosovo to Taiwan and Western Sahara, the examples showcase the complex interplay of political, strategic and diplomatic factors that drive derecognition efforts. As these states have found out the hard way, meeting statehood (or sovereignty) criteria is far less important than other geopolitical developments. A seemingly counter-intuitive yet entirely compelling argument, considering this book’s evidence.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf111"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Asia after Europe&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*jD2VLT1hA4l4-nHgb27lZA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sugata Bose. Published in Cambridge, MA by Belknap Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Mahbubani thinks the twenty-first century is shaping up to be Asian, Sugata Bose’s sweeping narrative reminds readers that those on the continent were far from inward-looking in the twentieth century. To underline this argument, &lt;em&gt;Asia after Europe&lt;/em&gt; draws on the interconnections between a cast of (Asian) characters and colonial history, from a Parsi trader’s role in the Opium Wars to Mahatma Gandhi’s solidarity with Muslims after the fall of the Ottoman empire. Bose’s fresh interpretation of global history extends to other familiar episodes, including the 1930s Great Depression and the 1955 Bandung Conference. The result is a challenging and reflective account of the ways in which Asian international solidarity consolidated and fractured over this transformative century.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf123"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;9.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;strong&gt;The soft power of non-western small states&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*evJ84SvXEgO3Gn4PRHDE8g.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sarina Theys. Published in Abingdon and New York by Routledge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Mahbubani provides practical experience of small states’ diplomacy, Sarina Theys turns to Bhutan and Qatar to challenge conventional notions of power and size. While Theys is not the first to recognize the influence of small states in global politics, her latest book offers an intersubjective understanding of smallness and identity. In other words, Theys takes into consideration Bhutan’s and Qatar’s efforts regarding identity projection, mapping out their multiple identities before observing how these efforts translate (or fail to translate) into soft power influence. Overall, this is an empirically rigorous and conceptually innovative book that pushes the boundaries of western-centric literature. Check out our review for additional insights on the rather serendipitous case-study selection.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf112"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10. Securing peace in Angola and Mozambique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Zd4hpTXg_gzf58Zcs8H7Jg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Miranda Melcher. Published in London by Bloomsbury.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every so often, a debut book makes its way onto our list of recommendations: this unassuming monograph is certainly worth the attention of students and scholars of peace and conflict studies. Drawing on United Nations archives and original interviews with a variety of relevant actors, Miranda Melcher offers a comprehensive analysis of two complete peace processes to expand readers’ knowledge of how to negotiate and implement a peace treaty. There is ample merit in Melcher’s comparative approach, especially as the civil wars in Angola and Mozambique allow for a significant reflection on lessons learned, including the importance of a balance between specificity and flexibility in peace deals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae294"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our July 2025 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/4#2222506-8178346"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=25822cd8643f" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/the-international-affairs-summer-reading-list-2025-25822cd8643f"&gt;The International Affairs summer reading list 2025&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/the-international-affairs-summer-reading-list-2025-25822cd8643f?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 10:48:15 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top 5 books: May 2025</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-may-2025-dc5e1f1a4564?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Unless you live near the Equator or at the geographical poles, Spring can be an unpredictable season (especially in the UK’s island of rain). Unlike the weather, the enjoyment of books in this selection from the May 2025 issue of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;is far from uncertain. While two excellent additions to the literature on the politics of victimhood in Colombia bookend this assortment curated by Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira, it also features cutting-edge research on the far right’s manifest destiny and on US and EU foreign policy-making.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Good victims&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*p1FXMLlihtMIeRVFVSD1ew.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Roxani Krystalli. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a book makes it to the British International Studies Association &lt;a href="https://www.bisa.ac.uk/news/lhm-ling-outstanding-first-book-prize-2025-shortlist-announced"&gt;outstanding first book prize shortlist&lt;/a&gt;, you know it is going to be worth your time. If it also receives a stellar review in &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt;, then you should be wondering why you have not read it yet. In her first book, Roxani Krystalli delves into the Colombian transitional justice context to provide a ‘caring and graceful’ examination of what it means to be a good victim in the eyes of the institutions and bureaucracies that dispatch justice in post-conflict settings. Krystalli’s exploration of the performative aspects of victimhood draws on more than 150 interviews to render visible the institutional expectations, costs and dangers of discreet identities of ‘good’ and ‘bad’ victims, in a contribution to feminist studies that will not disappoint.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf077"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) The EU High Representative&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*U-Ii8h04yT9WsbkqdWLZJw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Niklas Helwig. Published in Cham, Switzerland by Palgrave Macmillan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the Treaty of Lisbon entered into force in 2009, it provided for the appointment of the very first EU High Representative/Vice-President (HRVP). Combining two previous roles, the foreign policy chief and the vice-presidency of the European Commission, the &lt;em&gt;Guardian&lt;/em&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2009/nov/19/eu-high-representative-foreig-minister"&gt;described&lt;/a&gt; the role as ‘less senior, but more powerful’. Three EU HRVPs later, Niklas Helwig has taken on the challenge of comparing and assessing their mandates to ascertain which factors increase or restrain the HRVP’s effectiveness. In his ‘thoughtful exploration’, Helwig considers institutional constraints, leadership styles and the incumbent’s ability to leverage resources while navigating member-state interests as well as external challenges. Anyone interested in Europe’s role on the global stage will benefit greatly from this unassuming book.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf097"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) World of the right&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*CGX4CZ-DCg7bAKqFes_AqA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Rita Abrahamsen, Jean-François Drolet, Michael C. Williams, Srdjan Vucetic, Karin Narita and Alexandra Gheciu. Published in Cambridge by Cambridge University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you think that the far right is simply an outgrowth of socio-economic alienation, this star-studded line-up of leading scholars urges you to think again. &lt;em&gt;World of the right&lt;/em&gt; immerses readers in this cosmos, demonstrating that the political ambitions of far-right leaders are informing a ‘globally interconnected political and cultural alliance, committed to charting an illiberal and radically conservative future for the world’. Drawing on the appropriation of Antonio Gramsci’s work, the authors trace the radical right’s multilayered attempts to build its ‘own brand of hegemony’. From training and educating a global elite to cutting across North/South divides, the far-right international alliance makes an exceptionally timely object of study.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf082"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) The end of engagement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*wfzyOflie6cG-IaXbBpAng.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by David M. McCourt. Published in New York by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2021, David McCourt wrote an article for &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; outlining how the different national security fields in the UK, US and Australia produced different framings of China’s rise. McCourt’s latest book builds on this political sociological approach and extends his effort to add nuance to our understanding of two knowledge communities that feature prominently in the US national security context: the China and the Russia watchers. The book benefits from McCourt’s almost 200 interviews with individuals from these two groupings, to report on how three dynamics eroded US engagement policies with China and Russia in widely different ways. Moving away from the focus on top-level government advisers, McCourt’s framework bridges the gap between scholars and practitioners in a book that will appeal to both audiences.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf095"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Born of war in Colombia&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*J3dsskZgTqQN4CqpA5wnYQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Tatiana Sanchez Parra. Published in New Brunswick, NJ by Rutgers University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically, a books blog of this kind will prioritize showcasing the spread of our book reviews’ coverage. Exceptionally, we are returning to the Colombian post-conflict society to provide a fascinating companion read to Krystalli’s monograph. In this eye-opening account, Tatiana Sanchez Parra adopts a narrative voice to foreground the experiences of forced motherhood and reproductive violence and the political struggles of women and their children born of war. Sanchez Parra’s anthropological attention to these victims underscores the limitations of a ‘past-oriented and harm-centered model of transitional justice’ whereby ‘the gendered ways in which conflict continues to remake their lives, beyond sexual violence, fall largely outside the scope of the machinery of transitional justice’. An absorbing read.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf087"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our May 2025 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/3"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter/X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/international-affairs-journal/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/iajournal.bsky.social"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bluesky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=dc5e1f1a4564" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-may-2025-dc5e1f1a4564"&gt;Top 5 books: May 2025&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-may-2025-dc5e1f1a4564?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 10:24:46 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top 5 books: September 2024</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-september-2024-544999e68f7c?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As the new academic year kicks off, Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira returns with the highlights from the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/100/5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;September 2024&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; issue of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. All issues of the journal feature a comprehensive book reviews section, which surveys the latest writing on international politics. The titles below spotlight appraisals of the Women, Peace and Security agenda as well as of the British empire, and new writing on the often-overlooked impact of everyday foreign policy in Russia and India.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Governing the feminist peace&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*dClObJ_sfRDlJaEv_up73A.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Paul Kirby and Laura J. Shepherd. Published in New York by Columbia University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Beyond its brilliantly illustrated cover, this co-authored book has a much wider appeal. Paul Kirby and Laura Shepherd have teamed up for a provocative and convincing critique of the Women, Peace and Security (WPS) agenda, as a product of specific global governance frameworks. Deploying some impressive empirical research, &lt;em&gt;Governing the feminist peace&lt;/em&gt; persuasively highlights the incoherent, contested and contingent nature of the WPS discourse, particularly as it features in the fields of policy and governance. In the words of our reviewer: ‘forgetting WPS, in the way that Kirby and Shepherd suggest, might provide an opportunity to expand the ethical imaginaries of war and peace’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae203"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Empireworld&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*EtwoKbjN_n3lr37bA6obQQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sathnam Sanghera. Published in New York by Viking Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;With &lt;em&gt;Empireworld&lt;/em&gt;, British journalist Sathnam Sanghera has delivered an outstanding sequel to &lt;em&gt;Empireland&lt;/em&gt; (New York: Viking Press, 2021), exploring the impact of the British empire around the globe. Drawing on the colonial legacies in India, Barbados, Mauritius and Nigeria, the author sheds light on how Modi instrumentalizes imperialism in his electoral campaign; how former centres of the slave trade are demanding reparations; and how Nigerian democracy embodies the contradictions of empire. This lucid and accessible examination of the imperial spread of white supremacist ideas, and the mixed record of democracy promotion, will benefit those interested in British history as well as those working in diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae198"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Everyday foreign policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*GwbjJSOCBTwtTXMdUX4Qbw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Elizaveta Gaufman. Published in Manchester by Manchester University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Russia’s invasion of Crimea and its subsequent war in Ukraine has inspired a cottage industry of books on both countries. And yet, Elizaveta Gaufman has identified a significant gap when it comes to the complex intersection of Russian foreign policy with daily life. Combining seven thematic case-studies with interviews, &lt;em&gt;Everyday foreign policy&lt;/em&gt; examines Russia’s (in)effectiveness in spreading its values throughout society. The book uncovers the role of both hard and soft power while accounting for how ordinary Russians have experienced ‘their country’s turn to extreme nationalism over the last decade’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae193"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) Cosmopolitan elites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*mA4iL_7iSK2P60Sf7zyAwQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Kira Huju. Published in Oxford by Oxford University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Connoisseurs of Kira Huju’s 2022 &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; article, ‘&lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiab220"&gt;Saffronizing diplomacy: the Indian Foreign Service under Hindu nationalist rule&lt;/a&gt;’, will find Huju’s first book eminently rewarding. In &lt;em&gt;Cosmopolitan elites&lt;/em&gt;, Huju picks up the Indian Foreign Service (IFS) once again, to expose how class, caste, gender and religion shape its composition. The author brings in everyday practices and domestic hierarchies to illustrate the exclusionary codes that dictate participation in international society. The book benefits from a broad historical scope that allows Huju to document the enduring tension between the influence of colonial ideals and the aspirations of a postcolonial India.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae188"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) Memory fragmentation from below and beyond the state&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*lD3ADMvc3CmLaky2-QiN4Q.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited by Anne Bazin, Emmanuelle Hébert, Valérie Rosoux and Eric Sangar. Published in Abingdon and New York by Routledge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;No reading list is complete — this year at least — without the latest writing on memory politics. This excellent edited volume offers 17 chapters dedicated to two different logics of memory fragmentation: vertical and horizontal. The former focuses on conflict memory discourses resulting from how political communities use the past differently, whereas the latter maps out discourses that transcend national boundaries. The book’s sections are helpfully divided according to four different types of (largely non-state) actors that can shape memory discourses. Despite the limited geographical focus on European case-studies, this is a great addition to the literature; the contributions on the role of gender and women in memory are especially welcome.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae190"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our September 2024 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/100/5"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;social media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post regular call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=544999e68f7c" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-september-2024-544999e68f7c"&gt;Top 5 books: September 2024&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-september-2024-544999e68f7c?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 12:10:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Statesmen's Forum: Wang Yi, Minister of Foreign Affairs, PRC</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/statesmens-forum-wang-yi-minister-foreign-affairs-prc</link><description>&lt;span&gt;Statesmen's Forum: Wang Yi, Minister of Foreign Affairs, PRC&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please watch the live webcast of a discussion on Chinese foreign policy and US-China Relations&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Fri, 02/19/2016 - 17:13
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/john-j-hamre" hreflang="en"&gt;John J. Hamre&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/christopher-k-johnson" hreflang="en"&gt;Christopher K. Johnson&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Downloads
          
              
  
      
            Download Transcript Here
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/event/160225_statesmen_forum_wang_yi.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;160225_statesmen_forum_wang_yi.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Freeman Chair in China Studies&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" hreflang="en"&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/65520/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;GettyImages-2059987068_cropped1.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Freeman Chair in China Studies is a leading source of insight and analysis on China’s evolving political system, domestic agenda, and foreign policy&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/interpret-china"&gt;Interpret: China&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/freeman-chair-china-studies/chinese-leadership-chart"&gt;Chinese Leadership Chart&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-leaders-forum" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Global Leaders Forum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/40615/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Statesmens_Main.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Global Leaders Forum provides leaders the opportunity to present their views about critical issues to a Washington audience&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/geopolitics-foreign-policy" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Geopolitics and Foreign Policy&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/58479/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;CSIS_ Geopolitics.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Geopolitics and Foreign Policy Department examines the key political, economic, security, and societal trends shaping the future of global governance and institutions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With deep regional expertise and strong global relationships across Africa, Americas, Europe, Eurasia, Russia, Indo-Pacific, and Middle East, our experts offer comprehensive analysis to guide policymakers in navigating the evolving challenges to U.S. global leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/statesmens-forum" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Statesmen's Forum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  



              
      

  
    Regions
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/china" hreflang="en"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Thu, 02/25/2016 - 19:30
 - Thu, 02/25/2016 - 21:00

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/statesmens-forum-wang-yi-minister-foreign-affairs-prc</guid><pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2016 22:13:26 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Strategic Opportunities in the Indo-Asia-Pacific with Admiral Harry B. Harris</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/strategic-opportunities-indo-asia-pacific-admiral-harry-b-harris</link><description>&lt;span&gt;Strategic Opportunities in the Indo-Asia-Pacific with Admiral Harry B. Harris&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please join us for a discussion with Admiral Harry B. Harris, Commander, U.S. Pacific Command, on the Strategic Opportunities in the Indo-Asia-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Tue, 01/26/2016 - 11:20
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              Kathleen H. Hicks
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/john-j-hamre" hreflang="en"&gt;John J. Hamre&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;International Security Program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/34/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS International Security Program (ISP) is a constant source of reliable analysis on the international security and defense landscape, particularly with growing competition between the United States and such countries as China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/about-international-security-program"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/experts-and-affiliates"&gt;Experts and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/isp-programs"&gt;ISP Programs&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/media"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/archives"&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/events/military-strategy-forum" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Military Strategy Forum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/events" hreflang="en"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1206/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;CSIS hosts a series of senior military and civilian leaders from across the Department of Defense to present their unique insights and vision on the direction of U.S. national security and defense policy&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59030/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_DS_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Defense and Security Department&amp;nbsp;tackles&amp;nbsp;the most complex issues shaping the global security landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid a rapid shift in the global balance of power, our research&amp;nbsp;offers practical solutions&amp;nbsp;to the hardest national security strategy questions—from the state of U.S. readiness to the role of emerging tech in defense, and beyond. We get&amp;nbsp;national security, and we aim to make it stronger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Regions
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia" hreflang="en"&gt;Asia&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/australia-new-zealand-and-pacific" hreflang="en"&gt;Australia, New Zealand, and Pacific&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/china" hreflang="en"&gt;China&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/india" hreflang="en"&gt;India&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/japan" hreflang="en"&gt;Japan&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/korea" hreflang="en"&gt;Korea&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/asia/southeast-asia" hreflang="en"&gt;Southeast Asia&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/technology/military-technology" hreflang="en"&gt;Military Technology&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/defense-strategy-and-capabilities" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Strategy and Capabilities&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/geopolitics-and-international-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Geopolitics and International Security&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Wed, 01/27/2016 - 18:00
 - Wed, 01/27/2016 - 19:00

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/strategic-opportunities-indo-asia-pacific-admiral-harry-b-harris</guid><pubDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2016 16:20:53 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>U.S. sanctions against Rosneft &amp; Lukoil are cutting Russian oil revenue. Urals crude fell to $45.35/barrel, a low since March. Key Indian &amp; Chinese buyers pause purchases. US threatens further action</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1p01a1m/us_sanctions_against_rosneft_lukoil_are_cutting/</link><description>&lt;!-- SC_OFF --&gt;&lt;div class="md"&gt;&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Treasury Department stated on Monday that sanctions implemented against Russian oil giants Rosneft and Lukoil are already diminishing Russia’s oil revenues and are expected to further curtail the volume of Russian oil sales in the future.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;According to a statement from the Treasury’s Office of Foreign Assets Control (OFAC), an analysis of the initial market effects of the October 22 sanctions indicates they are succeeding in their goal of weakening Russian income. This is being achieved by driving down the price of Russian oil, thereby limiting the country’s financial capacity to support its military actions against Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;This Treasury initiative is among the most forceful U.S. sanctions enacted since Russia’s large-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022, and they represent the first direct sanctions imposed by the Trump administration on Russia. These sanctions established a deadline of November 21 for companies to cease transactions with Rosneft and Lukoil, with potential penalties including exclusion from the dollar-based financial network.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;However, the method of enforcement remains unclear, especially considering that China and India are the top two purchasers of Russian oil. OFAC’s assessment noted that several vital grades of Russian crude oil are being sold at their lowest prices in years and that about a dozen major Indian and Chinese buyers of Russian crude have publicly declared intentions to halt their Russian oil purchases for December deliveries.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Data from LSEG Workspace on Monday revealed that Urals crude, loaded at the Russian Black Sea oil hub of Novorossiysk (URL-NVRSK), was trading at $45.35 a barrel on November 12, which is the lowest price since March 2023. At that time, Russia was beginning to create a shadow tanker fleet to bypass a G7-imposed price cap of $60 per barrel, which began in December 2023.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;Brent crude futures (LCOc1) were priced at $62.71 on November 12 and traded at $64.03 on Monday. Urals Novorossiysk increased to $47.01 on Monday. Loadings at the Black Sea port have started again after being halted due to a Ukrainian drone and missile strike. Reuters reported earlier this month that Russian oil discounts relative to Brent crude had increased as major Indian and Chinese refiners reduced their purchases as a result of the U.S. sanctions.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;A Treasury spokesperson stated that these sanctions are weakening Putin’s war efforts and that the department is ready to take additional measures if needed to stop the senseless violence in Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://starfeu.com"&gt;starfeu.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;/div&gt;&lt;!-- SC_ON --&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/StarFEU-Commodity"&gt; /u/StarFEU-Commodity &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1p01a1m/us_sanctions_against_rosneft_lukoil_are_cutting/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1p01a1m/us_sanctions_against_rosneft_lukoil_are_cutting/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1p01a1m/us_sanctions_against_rosneft_lukoil_are_cutting/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 03:24:01 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Is Europe waking up to the China challenge? How geopolitics are reshaping EU and transatlantic strategy</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/is-europe-waking-up-to-the-china-challenge-how-geopolitics-are-reshaping-eu-and-transatlantic-strategy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;China’s rising global ambitions challenge both US and European interests. By examining the EU’s gradual shift toward “de-risking” and gaps in transatlantic policy, this report offers insights for developing a more coherent and coordinated strategy to address Beijing’s economic and security challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/is-europe-waking-up-to-the-china-challenge-how-geopolitics-are-reshaping-eu-and-transatlantic-strategy/"&gt;Is Europe waking up to the China challenge? How geopolitics are reshaping EU and transatlantic strategy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/is-europe-waking-up-to-the-china-challenge-how-geopolitics-are-reshaping-eu-and-transatlantic-strategy/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>International Affairs Early Career Prize 2025</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/international-affairs-early-career-prize-2025-42d1048ccee6?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;h4&gt;The International Affairs team is pleased to announce the three shortlisted articles and the winner of our Early Career Prize 2025.&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*2u3rS4IvqXsM_9FCBh0hqQ.png" /&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;A collage depicting the six issues published by &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; in 2024.&lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; team launched the Early Career Prize to celebrate research published in the journal by authors who have less than seven years of experience in the field of International Relations post-PhD. After a rigorous selection process, we are pleased to announce the winner of our 2025 prize, as well as the three articles which have made our shortlist for the 2025 prize.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;Why?&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;It has rarely been harder to launch a career in academia. The high expectations that PhD students and post-doctoral researchers face regarding teaching, course administration, outreach and, of course, research, have been well documented.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this context, we believe it is important to celebrate outstanding research produced by early career researchers. While the seniority of an author is not taken into account during the &lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt; editorial process, looking back at the high quality articles written by early career academics has been an immensely rewarding exercise.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;The winner&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;We are excited to announce that the &lt;em&gt;International Affairs &lt;/em&gt;Early Career Prize 2025 goes to &lt;strong&gt;Sebastian Haug&lt;/strong&gt; for his article ‘&lt;strong&gt;Mutual legitimation attempts: the United Nations and China’s Belt and Road Initiative&lt;/strong&gt;’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae020"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;The shortlist&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The following articles were shortlisted by the members of our editorial board. They are listed in order of the issue in which they were published.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;1. Respected individuals: when state representatives wield outsize influence in international organizations&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Timon Forster&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*9fvSqMkuUsCkMBYHZ-Dgwg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract: &lt;/strong&gt;States are keen to send representatives to international organizations, instructing them to pursue national interests and monitor staff. Yet academics tend to ignore these individuals and approximate state influence by vote shares and other state-level attributes. Against this background, I examine when state representatives in international organizations wield outsize influence on decision-making. Based on scholarship of bureaucrats in international organizations, European studies and an interdisciplinary literature on negotiation, I argue that state delegates matter beyond their national affiliation. Empirically, I study one especially powerful institution in global governance: the International Monetary Fund (IMF). Elite interviews with IMF state representatives demonstrate that delegates carefully plan their interventions, behaving independently while also extending their constituents’ interests. Based on the analysis of these interviews, I theorize ‘respected individuals’ to describe state representatives who can wield outsize influence on decision-making. Their prestige and impact depend on: first, perceived autonomy from their home governments; and second, relevant expertise, social skills and deliberative craft. In the IMF, respected individuals are most likely to represent relatively weak states; more generally, my work speaks to debates on the power of small states in international financial institutions and multilateral negotiations. Together, the findings explicate how individuals impact organizational decision-making, with important implications for practitioners in such institutions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiad226"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2. Mutual legitimation attempts: the United Nations and China’s Belt and Road Initiative&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sebastian Haug&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*4PMsVTOHI3nQ2wAB2q3rXA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;: The Belt and Road Initiative (BRI) has become a hallmark of China’s global rise. While the BRI has unfolded as a global platform focused on bilateral relations, the Chinese government has also tried to expand links between the BRI and international organizations, notably the United Nations. Available evidence about UN–BRI relations suggests, however, that an initial honeymoon phase with mushrooming projects and public endorsements was followed by a sharp decline in engagement. This article argues that a focus on inter-governor legitimation attempts helps understand the rise and fall of UN–BRI relations. Based on publicly available evidence, internal documentation and stakeholder interviews, it shows how legitimation informed motivations on both sides to invest in UN–BRI relations, and how western opposition subsequently led to UN entities reducing their engagement. Empirically, the article contributes to the literature on China’s global role, evolving power relations at the UN, and the proliferation of geopolitically motivated flagship initiatives across UN member states. Conceptually, it speaks to the expanding debate about legitimation in world politics through a more systematic engagement with relational legitimation dynamics. A focus on one-sided or mutual legitimation attempts offers a conceptual tool for analysing how interactions among global governors and their audiences unfold, and how international organizations try (and fail) to strengthen their resilience in light of an increasingly polarized membership.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae020"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;3. The Russian factor: emotions, narratives and reshaping China’s norms in international conflicts&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Xiaoyu Lu and Tinghao Zhang&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/800/1*0_nJHzElPzE0B9IWUTC0Ww.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract: &lt;/strong&gt;How did Russia, despite being in a weaker position, exercise a continuous and resilient influence on China’s normative approach to international conflicts from Syria to Ukraine? This article proposes a theoretical framework that connects the affective turn and norm studies in International Relations. It conceptualizes emotions as the affective infrastructure of norm scripts: shared political feelings create resonance, based on which persuasive narratives work to maintain solidarity and institutionalize normative changes. Drawing on primary Russian and Chinese resources and using process tracing to identify critical junctures in the partnership and institutional channels for Russian campaigns, this article demonstrates how China’s alignment with Russia is not solely based on geopolitical interests or constructed identities but rather a result of feelings of isolation and marginalization that firstly resonated with and then exploited by Russian actors. Furthermore, this article identifies three types of persuasive narratives used to construct continuity, analogy and identification in consolidating emotional resonance around the threat of a homogenous West and inducing normative convergence. This drives China to adopt policies in conflict with national interests and norms on sovereignty and territorial integrity that trigger a reflective assessment of the Russian influence, while underlining the growing importance of emotion diplomacy.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the article &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae126"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more information on International Affairs and how to submit your research, visit our &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;website&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;More information on the Early Career Prize and a list of the previous winners can be found &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/pages/early_career_prize"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=42d1048ccee6" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/international-affairs-early-career-prize-2025-42d1048ccee6"&gt;International Affairs Early Career Prize 2025&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/international-affairs-early-career-prize-2025-42d1048ccee6?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 15:01:39 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top 5 books: January 2025</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-january-2025-cfeb6622c665?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;Is there a better way to start the year than with a brand-new book? Yes, with a brand-new book that is unlikely to disappoint!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this blog, Book Reviews Editor Mariana presents five strong options from the &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/1"&gt;January 2025 issue&lt;/a&gt; of &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;&lt;em&gt;International Affairs&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Explore a varied selection below that is certain to be of interest to anyone curious about the European Union, peace processes in Africa, embassies or the aesthetics of armed conflict.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1) Crises of European integration&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*_XWJGCnbgRH_EOdSLi4LdQ.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Lucas Schramm. Published in London by Palgrave Macmillan.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;‘Voting in Europe during 2025 promises major political shifts.’ If the predictions from &lt;em&gt;Euronews&lt;/em&gt; are to be taken seriously, then Lucas Schramm’s new book will prove an invaluable read for anyone interested in the wider implications for the European Union and its path towards integration. Schramm carefully examines eight different crises that the EU has faced in the last seven decades, bringing in a commendable empirical scope. With systematic nuance, the book identifies the different processes of change — from stagnation, adaptation and regression — associated with successive crises. Schramm’s conclusions might surprise those who believe Jean Monnet’s famous dictum that Europe ‘will be built through crises’.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae299"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2) Securing peace in Angola and Mozambique&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Pf3Ve7CZ95AI5WUM1f6nwg.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Miranda Melcher. Published in London by Bloomsbury.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Every so often, a debut book makes its way onto our list of recommendations: this unassuming monograph is certainly worth the attention of students and scholars of peace and conflict studies. Drawing on United Nations archives and original interviews with a variety of relevant actors, Miranda Melcher offers a comprehensive analysis of two complete peace processes to expand readers’ knowledge of how to negotiate and implement a peace treaty. There is ample merit in Melcher’s comparative approach, especially as the civil wars in Angola and Mozambique allow for a significant reflection on lessons learned, including the importance of a balance between specificity and flexibility in peace deals.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae294"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3) Outposts of diplomacy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*uAOJElfoPg0PEFn5Bi1DYA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by G. R. Berridge. Published in London by Reaktion Books.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This entertaining and informative exploration of how embassies have developed over time, and of their persistent existence even in hostile environments, will provide a rare treat to a broad audience. G. R. Berridge successfully combines facts and anecdotes in a narrative that explores myriad themes, from embassy household politics to the negative connotations that diplomatic staff attributed to the ‘less honourable’ task of intelligence-gathering. As the book draws primarily on European and American diplomats’ experiences, its captivating storytelling calls for a sequel that delves into the perspectives of their global South counterparts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae312"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4) War and aesthetics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*gFHYpKKeUEJJQ2tbNI3-YA.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited by Jens Bjering, Anders Engberg-Pedersen, Solveig Gade and Christine Strandmose Toft. Published in Cambridge, MA by MIT Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;This edited volume features an impressive line-up of contributors; it invites readers to reconsider the concepts of technology, surveillance and artificial intelligence to reveal the aesthetic dimension of warfare. In doing so, the book raises many important questions about the ways in which the representational field of war is constructed, while simultaneously bringing to the forefront how art can counter the logic of warfare. The chapters are intriguing and theoretically driven, without losing sight of the empirical details: from questions of poetry and war to reflections on the relationship between fabrics and choreography on the one hand and armed conflict on the other.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae289"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5) India’s energy revolution&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*Xm_I0EM5uQ9wxyl2Vlpbqw.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Edited by Annika Bose Styczynski. Published in Abingdon and New York by Routledge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;While India is the third largest contributor to global greenhouse gas emissions, the literature on its energy sector is sparse. Annika Bose Styczynski’s edited volume seeks to fill precisely this gap, focusing on the supply side of the country’s energy policies. Featuring 12 contributed chapters, the book investigates India’s energy sources and offers useful assessments regarding their individual contributions to the Indian economy. From the challenges of phasing out coal to the successes in onshore wind power and the shortcomings of making nuclear energy a significant energy output, this is a timely reminder of how India’s energy portfolio will influence global energy markets.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiae302"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;here&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our January 2025 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/1#2087404-7942162"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://twitter.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;social media&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post regular call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=cfeb6622c665" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-january-2025-cfeb6622c665"&gt;Top 5 books: January 2025&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-january-2025-cfeb6622c665?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 10:23:05 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Future of the Grid—A View from ARPA-E</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/future-grid-view-arpa-e</link><description>&lt;span&gt;The Future of the Grid—A View from ARPA-E&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Energy and National Security Program is pleased to invite you to a discussion with Ellen Williams, Director of ARPA-E, the Advanced Research Projects Agency-Energy.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Thu, 02/25/2016 - 14:15
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              Sarah Ladislaw
          Francis O'Sullivan
              
      

  
    Downloads
          
              
  
      
            03102016_Williams.pdf
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/attachments/03102016_Williams.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;03102016_Williams.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Energy Security and Climate Change Program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/economic-security-and-technology" hreflang="en"&gt;Economic Security and Technology&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/40081/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;AdobeStock_228362757v2.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Securing the energy transition through leading research and independent analysis&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://stateenergy.csis.org/"&gt;Microsite&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program/podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/energy-security-and-climate-change-program/about-us"&gt;Our Team&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/economic-security-and-technology" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Economic Security and Technology&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59027/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_EST_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Economic Security and Technology Department examines the most pressing issues facing the United States and its partners in sustaining economic and technological advantages essential to prosperity, security, and resilience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With unique breadth and depth of expertise across economic policy, global markets, and advanced technologies, we provide strategic insights and practical solutions to drive competitiveness, technology leadership and economic security amid global threats.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Regions
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/regions/americas" hreflang="en"&gt;Americas&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/climate-change" hreflang="en"&gt;Climate Change&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/energy-and-sustainability" hreflang="en"&gt;Energy and Sustainability&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/energy-and-sustainability/energy-and-geopolitics" hreflang="en"&gt;Energy and Geopolitics&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/energy-and-sustainability/energy-innovation" hreflang="en"&gt;Energy Innovation&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/energy-and-sustainability/energy-markets-trends-and-outlooks" hreflang="en"&gt;Energy Markets, Trends, and Outlooks&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Thu, 03/10/2016 - 10:00
 - Thu, 03/10/2016 - 11:30

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/future-grid-view-arpa-e</guid><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2016 19:15:03 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Statesmen's Forum: The Right Honourable Theresa May, MP, Home Secretary, United Kingdom</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/statesmens-forum-right-honourable-theresa-may-mp-home-secretary-united-kingdom</link><description>&lt;span&gt;Statesmen's Forum: The Right Honourable Theresa May, MP, Home Secretary, United Kingdom&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please join the CSIS International Security Program for a discussion with UK Home Secretary Theresa May on counter-terrorism policy.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Fri, 02/12/2016 - 16:08
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              Kathleen H. Hicks
              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;International Security Program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/34/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS International Security Program (ISP) is a constant source of reliable analysis on the international security and defense landscape, particularly with growing competition between the United States and such countries as China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/about-international-security-program"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/experts-and-affiliates"&gt;Experts and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/isp-programs"&gt;ISP Programs&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/media"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/archives"&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/europe-russia-and-eurasia-program/archives/european-security-politics-and-economics/csis" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The CSIS Travel Guide to Brexit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/europe-russia-and-eurasia-program/archives/european-security-politics-and-economics" hreflang="en"&gt;European Security, Politics, and Economics&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1549/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;The CSIS Travel Guide to Brexit&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Your essential CSIS travel guide includes an array of resources and guideposts about Brexit, from commentaries and blog posts to videos and podcasts that deal with this historic, complex, and important event for the United Kingdom, the European Union, and the United States&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-leaders-forum" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Global Leaders Forum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/40615/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Statesmens_Main.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Global Leaders Forum provides leaders the opportunity to present their views about critical issues to a Washington audience&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59030/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_DS_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Defense and Security Department&amp;nbsp;tackles&amp;nbsp;the most complex issues shaping the global security landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid a rapid shift in the global balance of power, our research&amp;nbsp;offers practical solutions&amp;nbsp;to the hardest national security strategy questions—from the state of U.S. readiness to the role of emerging tech in defense, and beyond. We get&amp;nbsp;national security, and we aim to make it stronger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/statesmens-forum" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Statesmen's Forum&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  



              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/counterterrorism-and-homeland-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Counterterrorism and Homeland Security&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Wed, 02/17/2016 - 15:30
 - Wed, 02/17/2016 - 16:15

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/statesmens-forum-right-honourable-theresa-may-mp-home-secretary-united-kingdom</guid><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 21:08:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>11/17/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/11-17-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Access National Security News HERE. Access Korean News HERE. National Security News: 1. New Nuclear Arms Race Pits U.S. Against Both Russia and China 2. Opinion &amp;#124; Trump and a New ‘Arsenal of Freedom’ 3. Trump Says U.S. May Hold Talks With Venezuela’s Maduro 4. Pentagon Creating Amazon-Like Shopping Portal For Counter-Drone Equipment 5. Could America Have Lost the Revolutionary War? 6. China Coast Guard ship &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/11-17-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/11-17-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/"&gt;11/17/25 National Security and Korean News and Commentary&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/11-17-25-national-security-and-korean-news-and-commentary/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 13:54:42 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Vulnerabilities in Sukhoi Production: Clipping Russia’s Wings</title><link>https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/research-papers/vulnerabilities-sukhoi-production-clipping-russias-wings</link><description>&lt;p&gt;This research paper examines the critical vulnerabilities in the production of Russia’s Sukhoi combat aircraft and its implications for NATO and global defence markets.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rusi.org/explore-our-research/publications/research-papers/vulnerabilities-sukhoi-production-clipping-russias-wings</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The geopolitical trends shaping the EU’s policies on China</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/the-geopolitical-trends-shaping-the-eus-policies-on-china/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;European policies on China are shaped by four major geopolitical trends: intensifying US-China competition, uncertainty about sustained US engagement in Europe and globally, China’s support for Russia’s war on Ukraine, and Beijing’s growing economic and technological challenge to the EU.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/the-geopolitical-trends-shaping-the-eus-policies-on-china/"&gt;The geopolitical trends shaping the EU&amp;#8217;s policies on China&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/the-geopolitical-trends-shaping-the-eus-policies-on-china/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland’s policy on China: From partnership to skepticism</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/polands-policy-on-china-from-partnership-to-skepticism/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Despite its traditionally transatlantic orientation, Poland pursued an engagement policy toward China until the late 2010s. However, unmet economic promises and Beijing’s alignment with Moscow following Russia’s invasion of Ukraine shifted Warsaw’s view of China from economic partner to systemic challenger.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/polands-policy-on-china-from-partnership-to-skepticism/"&gt;Poland’s policy on China: From partnership to skepticism&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/polands-policy-on-china-from-partnership-to-skepticism/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Lipsky acknowledged in a RAND report on economic measures for deterrence, strengthening analysis on allied coordination, and policy design</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/lipsky-acknowledged-in-a-rand-report-on-economic-measures-for-deterrence-strengthening-analysis-on-allied-coordination-and-policy-design/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Read the full report here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/lipsky-acknowledged-in-a-rand-report-on-economic-measures-for-deterrence-strengthening-analysis-on-allied-coordination-and-policy-design/"&gt;Lipsky acknowledged in a RAND report on economic measures for deterrence, strengthening analysis on allied coordination, and policy design&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/lipsky-acknowledged-in-a-rand-report-on-economic-measures-for-deterrence-strengthening-analysis-on-allied-coordination-and-policy-design/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 16:23:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Top 5 books: IA goes nuclear</title><link>https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-ia-goes-nuclear-82c1467b9d36?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</link><description>&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/1024/1*g2qFnA7t29K-y2TMYHjKbQ.jpeg" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whether you like the autumn or not, we can all agree that having cooler weather is better than having no seasons (and no planet) at all. This is the likely scenario in the aftermath of a worldwide nuclear war or even a series of nuclear accidents, brought about by climate-induced changes.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Book Reviews Editor Mariana Vieira has selected a handful of the newest books offering nuanced explorations of nuclear-related issues in &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Relations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;. As some of these books warn and as others prove to be the case, the dangers of nuclear weapons, nuclear energy and nuclear testing should not be disregarded. As others detail, approaches to nuclear proliferation are never homogeneous and resistance to nuclear-armed states is not simply a mirage. From soon-to-be Hollywood movies to anti-nuclear manifestos, these five books do much to pluralize the discussion of all things nuclear.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;1) Nuclear war&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/630/0*WXP8sSS7OAgL71lx.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Annie Jacobsen. Published in London by Torva.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;em&gt;Nuclear war&lt;/em&gt;, Pulitzer prize winner Annie Jacobsen describes a hypothetical scenario based on factual information. Drawing from interviews with highly relevant stakeholders, from individuals tasked with developing nuclear strategy to those dealing with the aftermath of a nuclear attack, Jacobsen outlines the terrifying outcome, retaliation and potentially planet-devastating war that would be unleashed if North Korea launched a surprise nuclear attack on the United States. In a masterful storytelling style, the book drives home the timely point that, in ‘a world with more than enough nuclear warheads to kill the planet several times over’, it will not matter who started the war because there will be no winners. Hurry and grab this book before Denis Villeneuve’s rumoured Hollywood adaptation comes to the big screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf158"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;2) Rule &amp;amp; resistance in the nuclear order&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/630/0*H2JgPviL-BCWBatG.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Sascha Hach. Published in Bielefeld, Germany by transcript publishing.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If Jacobsen’s book has left you slowly veering towards nihilism, Sascha Hach’s reinterpretation of the Humanitarian Initiative (HI) and the Treaty on the Prohibition of Nuclear Weapons (TPNW) as collective acts of resistance will breathe hope back into your life. The author combines sociological, critical and postcolonial approaches in a hybrid framework that spotlights how non-nuclear weapon states, particularly in the global South, have sought to overcome their marginalization in global nuclear governance and to subvert proliferation. The book’s offerings are bountiful: mapping several actors and alliances beyond states; offering a clear conceptual framework and in-depth theoretical engagement without sacrificing accessibility; and empirically investigating the resistance tactics employed in the processes of the HI and TPNW. Hach delivers a powerful reminder that coordinated acts of rebellion can rely on lawful means, while remaining careful not to overstate their limited disruptive potential.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf160"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;3) The ocean on fire&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/630/0*FycCOjYHPaxMTWnL.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Anaïs Maurer. Published in Durham, NC by Duke University Press.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Speaking of marginalization in the nuclear sphere, &lt;em&gt;The ocean on fire&lt;/em&gt; brings the discussion from the material to the epistemological realm, while adding a much-needed human dimension to the conversation. As Anaïs Maurer warns and our reviewer puts it: ‘The challenges for which overindustrialized countries seek to prepare are already the lived reality of Pacific peoples.’ The author painstakingly demonstrates how environmental degradation and the impacts of nuclear testing have long been felt in Oceania, and how its Pacific communities have been largely sidelined as the Pacific has been conceived as existing ‘outside of history’. In bringing back the contributions of Pacific epistemologies, Maurer paves the way for alternative understandings of how we relate to the environment in light of nuclear and climate related crises.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf161"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;4) Nuclear is not the solution&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/630/0*BXDlqlb-9JNncc8U.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by M. V. Ramana. Published in London by Verso.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If no good can come from nuclear weapons, is atomic power worth pursuing? In the context of climate change, M. V. Ramana’s rigorous and well-researched book argues that &lt;em&gt;Nuclear is not the solution&lt;/em&gt;. Methodologically, the author discredits and disproves existing arguments in favour of investing in or scaling up the use of nuclear energy. The book extensively details the key issues with pursuing nuclear energy as a power source, from its temporal and financial costs to the negative impact of uranium mining, and to the liability of power plants and reactors in the contexts of armed conflict and natural disasters. This telling myth-busting exercise not only sheds light on the dangers and costs of nuclear energy, but it also exposes the flawed rationales underpinning the false promise of atomic power.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf081"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;h4&gt;5) The global third nuclear age&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://cdn-images-1.medium.com/max/630/0*_TGwYA5mVO-Ank9N.png" /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Written by Andrew Futter, Ludovica Castelli, Cameron Hunter, Olamide Samuel, Francesca Silvestri and Benjamin Zala. Published in Abingdon and New York by Routledge.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last, but certainly not least, &lt;em&gt;The global third nuclear age&lt;/em&gt; takes the interrogation of ‘global’ as its starting-point to displace ‘western nuclear ethnocentrism’. In this open-access book, the authors criticize the existing focus within contemporary nuclear politics that limits analysis to the nine nuclear-armed states and overlooks regional sensitivities. In this way, it shares Hach’s impetus to pluralize the study of global nuclear governance. The main contribution is a nuanced categorization of 20 states according to how the elites in each country shape and respond to three different factors: technological change, shifts in global power balances and global nuclear norms. Moreover, the analysis of responses to shifting trends will benefit policy-makers and academics alike.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the full review &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1093/ia/iiaf128"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mariana Vieira is the Book Reviews Editor of &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia"&gt;International Affairs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Find the latest book reviews section in our September 2025 issue &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/ia/issue/101/5"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For more reading suggestions, check out the &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/tagged/ia-bookshelf"&gt;&lt;em&gt;IA Bookshelf series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you are interested in reviewing a book for the journal, register your interest in our book review application form &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd6ZOiHKZ2WYj8UEaaXy9-gVuv_0ONmB2x2pv1x9-VcSWwCdg/viewform"&gt;&lt;em&gt;here&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Follow us on &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://x.com/IAJournal_CH"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Twitter/X&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt;, &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/company/international-affairs-journal/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; and &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://bsky.app/profile/iajournal.bsky.social"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bluesky&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;em&gt; where we post call outs for specific books and experts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All views expressed are individual not institutional.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;img alt="" height="1" src="https://medium.com/_/stat?event=post.clientViewed&amp;amp;referrerSource=full_rss&amp;amp;postId=82c1467b9d36" width="1" /&gt;&lt;hr /&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-ia-goes-nuclear-82c1467b9d36"&gt;Top 5 books: IA goes nuclear&lt;/a&gt; was originally published in &lt;a href="https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog"&gt;International Affairs Blog&lt;/a&gt; on Medium, where people are continuing the conversation by highlighting and responding to this story.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://medium.com/international-affairs-blog/top-5-books-ia-goes-nuclear-82c1467b9d36?source=rss----914f4a3521ea---4</guid><pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 14:11:47 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The FY2017 Defense Budget and Strategic Outlook</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/fy2017-defense-budget-and-strategic-outlook</link><description>&lt;span&gt;The FY2017 Defense Budget and Strategic Outlook&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please join the CSIS International Security Program for a half-day Defense360 conference on the recently released FY2017 defense budget request and strategic priorities.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Mon, 02/29/2016 - 13:48
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/john-j-hamre" hreflang="en"&gt;John J. Hamre&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/tina-w-jonas" hreflang="en"&gt;Tina W. Jonas&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/mark-f-cancian" hreflang="en"&gt;Mark F. Cancian&lt;/a&gt;
          Todd Harrison
          Andrew Philip Hunter
              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;International Security Program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/34/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS International Security Program (ISP) is a constant source of reliable analysis on the international security and defense landscape, particularly with growing competition between the United States and such countries as China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/about-international-security-program"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/experts-and-affiliates"&gt;Experts and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/isp-programs"&gt;ISP Programs&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/media"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/archives"&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense Budget Analysis&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/61248/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;GettyImages-2186280635_Crop1.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Defense Budget Analysis Program leads the Center’s efforts to provide in-depth, nonpartisan research and analysis of defense funding issues&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/defense-futures-simulator"&gt;Defense Futures Simulator&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59030/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_DS_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Defense and Security Department&amp;nbsp;tackles&amp;nbsp;the most complex issues shaping the global security landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid a rapid shift in the global balance of power, our research&amp;nbsp;offers practical solutions&amp;nbsp;to the hardest national security strategy questions—from the state of U.S. readiness to the role of emerging tech in defense, and beyond. We get&amp;nbsp;national security, and we aim to make it stronger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-budget-and-acquisition" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Budget and Acquisition&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/defense-industry-acquisition-and-innovation" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Industry, Acquisition, and Innovation&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/defense-strategy-and-capabilities" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Strategy and Capabilities&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/geopolitics-and-international-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Geopolitics and International Security&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Mon, 03/07/2016 - 19:00
 - Mon, 03/07/2016 - 21:30

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Event Format
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3007" hreflang="en"&gt;In Person&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/fy2017-defense-budget-and-strategic-outlook</guid><pubDate>Mon, 29 Feb 2016 18:48:29 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Defense Outlook: A CSIS Series on Strategy, Budget, Forces, and Acquisition</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/defense-outlook-csis-series-strategy-budget-forces-and-acquisition</link><description>&lt;span&gt;Defense Outlook: A CSIS Series on Strategy, Budget, Forces, and Acquisition&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;In January of 2016, CSIS launched a new International Security Program initiative examining the dynamics and interlinkages of strategy, budget, forces, and acquisition on the current and future state of the U.S. Armed Forces.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Fri, 01/15/2016 - 15:33
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/john-j-hamre" hreflang="en"&gt;John J. Hamre&lt;/a&gt;
          Todd Harrison
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/mark-f-cancian" hreflang="en"&gt;Mark F. Cancian&lt;/a&gt;
          Andrew Philip Hunter
          Kathleen H. Hicks
              
      

  
    Downloads
          
              
  
      
            Defense Acquisition Trends, 2015
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/attachments/Defense Acquisition Trends, 2015.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;Defense Acquisition Trends, 2015.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

          
  
      
            Defense Modernization Plans through the 2020s
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/attachments/Defense Modernization Plans through the 2020s.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;Defense Modernization Plans through the 2020s.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

          
  
      
            Defense Outlook 2016
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/legacy_files/files/attachments/Defense Outlook 2016.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;Defense Outlook 2016.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;International Security Program&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/34/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Alex Wong/Getty Images&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS International Security Program (ISP) is a constant source of reliable analysis on the international security and defense landscape, particularly with growing competition between the United States and such countries as China, Russia, Iran, and North Korea&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/international-security-program/about-international-security-program"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/experts-and-affiliates"&gt;Experts and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/isp-programs"&gt;ISP Programs&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/media"&gt;Media&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/former-programs/international-security-program/archives"&gt;Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-360" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense 360&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/37/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo credit: U.S. Navy from https://www.flickr.com/photos/usnavy/36162973322/in/photostream/&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Defense 360 is your one-stop shop for all things CSIS defense analysis - defense360.csis.org&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense Budget Analysis&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/61248/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;GettyImages-2186280635_Crop1.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The Defense Budget Analysis Program leads the Center’s efforts to provide in-depth, nonpartisan research and analysis of defense funding issues&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-budget-analysis/defense-futures-simulator"&gt;Defense Futures Simulator&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Center for the Industrial Base&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/65958/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;AdobeStock_88560614_cropped.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Reimagining government-industry collaboration to foster innovation, build capacity, and achieve victory.&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/about-center-industrial-base"&gt;About&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects"&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/project-archives"&gt;Project Archives&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects/evolving-partnership-between-dod-industry" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Evolving Partnership between DoD &amp;amp; Industry&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects" hreflang="en"&gt;Projects &lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1158/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Engaging in dialogue with DoD and industry partners as well as through focused research, CIB explores this critical partnership and its effect on important defense topics&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/defense-industrial-initiatives-group/impact-budget-constraints" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Impact of Budget Constraints&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base" hreflang="en"&gt;Center for the Industrial Base&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1142/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: SC Fiasco from https://www.flickr.com/photos/30352125@N00/2994921185&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Leveraging data and acquisition expertise, DIIG analyzes the effects of the defense drawdown on the defense industrial base&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects/improving-acquisition" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Improving Acquisition&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects" hreflang="en"&gt;Projects &lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1143/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Convening experts and policy makers to discuss the workings of the defense acquisition system, CIB explores potential reforms to deliver responsive, efficient acquisition in support of future missions&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects/leveraging-innovation" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Leveraging Innovation&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/center-industrial-base/projects" hreflang="en"&gt;Projects &lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/1144/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;Photo: Public Domain&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Understanding the new global innovation ecosystem and its implications for national security, CIB fosters critical dialogue on how to leverage technology in support of national security&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/defense-and-security" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59030/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;241009_DS_Banner.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;The CSIS Defense and Security Department&amp;nbsp;tackles&amp;nbsp;the most complex issues shaping the global security landscape.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amid a rapid shift in the global balance of power, our research&amp;nbsp;offers practical solutions&amp;nbsp;to the hardest national security strategy questions—from the state of U.S. readiness to the role of emerging tech in defense, and beyond. We get&amp;nbsp;national security, and we aim to make it stronger.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense and Security&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-budget-and-acquisition" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Budget and Acquisition&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/defense-industry-acquisition-and-innovation" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Industry, Acquisition, and Innovation&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/defense-and-security/defense-strategy-and-capabilities" hreflang="en"&gt;Defense Strategy and Capabilities&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Wed, 01/27/2016 - 20:00
 - Wed, 01/27/2016 - 22:00

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Event Format
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3007" hreflang="en"&gt;In Person&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/defense-outlook-csis-series-strategy-budget-forces-and-acquisition</guid><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2016 20:33:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Poland says ‘everything indicates’ Russia was behind rail sabotage incidents – Europe live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/nov/18/poland-russia-ukraine-rail-sabotage-incidents-zelenskyy-macron-merz-starmer-europe-live-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Security spokesperson says the incident at the weekend was a terrorist attack ‘initiated by special services from the East’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spain promised to roll out an unspecified “substantial” aid package for Ukraine as President Volodymyr Zelenskyy visited Madrid and met Spanish defence sector executives,&lt;/strong&gt; aiming to bolster Kyiv’s air defences against Russia’s invasion, Reuters reported.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Zelenskyy, who was due to meet prime minister Pedro Sánchez later, &lt;strong&gt;visited the headquarters of radar and anti-drone specialist Indra&lt;/strong&gt;, which is part-owned by the Spanish state, along with other defence firms and Spanish defence minister &lt;strong&gt;Margarita Robles.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/nov/18/poland-russia-ukraine-rail-sabotage-incidents-zelenskyy-macron-merz-starmer-europe-live-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/world/live/2025/nov/18/poland-russia-ukraine-rail-sabotage-incidents-zelenskyy-macron-merz-starmer-europe-live-news</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:14:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Building the digital front line: Understanding big tech decision-making in Ukraine</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/building-the-digital-front-line/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;In this report, author Emma Schroeder examines which factors most shaped tech companies’ decisions as to whether and how to lend their support to Ukraine throughout the war. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/building-the-digital-front-line/"&gt;Building the digital front line: Understanding big tech decision-making in Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/building-the-digital-front-line/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 15:35:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Special Operations News – Nov 17, 2025</title><link>https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/special-operations-news-nov-17-2025/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Access SOF News HERE. &amp;#160; Special Operations News – Nov 17, 2025 November 17, 2025 John Friberg Update 0 https://sof.news/update/20251117/ Curated news, analysis, and commentary about special operations, national security, and conflicts around the world. Photo / Image: A U.S. Air Force special missions aviator assigned to the 1st Special Operations Wing dons a helmet and night-vision goggles during a training exercise near &amp;#8230;&lt;br /&gt; &lt;a class="postReadMore" href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/special-operations-news-nov-17-2025/"&gt;Read more&lt;i class="fa fa-angle-double-right"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/special-operations-news-nov-17-2025/"&gt;Special Operations News – Nov 17, 2025&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://smallwarsjournal.com"&gt;Small Wars Journal by Arizona State University&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://smallwarsjournal.com/2025/11/17/special-operations-news-nov-17-2025/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 11:13:02 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Recommendations for coordinating US-EU policy</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/recommendations-for-coordinating-us-eu-policy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;To effectively counter China, the United States should prioritize closer coordination with the EU in key areas: economic security, supply chains, anti-coercion, and strategic investment. Joint efforts on trade and investment, technology, and security will be crucial to ensure aligned US-EU action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/recommendations-for-coordinating-us-eu-policy/"&gt;Recommendations for coordinating US-EU policy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/recommendations-for-coordinating-us-eu-policy/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Germany’s policy on China: From win-win to strategic competition</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/germanys-policy-on-china-from-win-win-to-strategic-competition/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Germany’s China policy has shifted from economic optimism to cautious competition—balancing trade interests with mounting security concerns. Once built on deep interdependence, Berlin now prioritizes “de-risking” and resilience in its approach to Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/germanys-policy-on-china-from-win-win-to-strategic-competition/"&gt;Germany’s policy on China: From win-win to strategic competition&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/germanys-policy-on-china-from-win-win-to-strategic-competition/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Hungary’s policy on China: Doing Beijing’s bidding</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/hungarys-policy-on-china-doing-beijings-bidding/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Under Prime Minister Viktor Orbán, Hungary has emerged as China’s closest ally within the EU, aligning its foreign policy with Beijing’s global agenda and repeatedly obstructing EU efforts to counter Chinese influence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/hungarys-policy-on-china-doing-beijings-bidding/"&gt;Hungary’s policy on China: Doing Beijing’s bidding&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/hungarys-policy-on-china-doing-beijings-bidding/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Greece’s policy on China: Debt-era deals and recalibration</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/greeces-policy-on-china-debt-era-deals-and-recalibration/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;From the port of Piraeus to Brussels, Greece’s China policy has evolved from enthusiastic engagement and post-crisis dependency to strategic caution. Today, Athens's is balancing economic pragmatism with transatlantic security commitments. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/greeces-policy-on-china-debt-era-deals-and-recalibration/"&gt;Greece’s policy on China: Debt-era deals and recalibration&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/greeces-policy-on-china-debt-era-deals-and-recalibration/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>France’s policy on China: Strategic autonomy and less naïveté</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/frances-policy-on-china-strategic-autonomy-and-less-naivete/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last decade, France’s long-standing engagement with China has transformed into a more nuanced and cautious dynamic, reflecting a growing emphasis on balancing. This shift is guided by France’s pursuit of strategic autonomy, its effort to “de-risk” economic and security ties, and the broader geopolitical realities unfolding in the Indo-Pacific.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/frances-policy-on-china-strategic-autonomy-and-less-naivete/"&gt;France’s policy on China: Strategic autonomy and less naïveté&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/frances-policy-on-china-strategic-autonomy-and-less-naivete/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>How Europe deals with China in trade, technology, and security</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/how-europe-deals-with-china-in-trade-technology-and-security/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;The EU’s approach to China is increasingly converging around “de-risking,” though progress remains uneven. While powerful member states set the overall direction, smaller ones drive change—and outliers slow collective action.  Whether the EU can turn this patchwork into a unified strategy will define its China policy in the years ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/how-europe-deals-with-china-in-trade-technology-and-security/"&gt;How Europe deals with China in trade, technology, and security&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/report/how-europe-deals-with-china-in-trade-technology-and-security/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Nov 2025 15:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Sapuppo in Kyiv Post on Hungarian exemption from US sanctions targeting Russian energy</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/sapuppo-in-kyiv-post-on-hungarian-exemption-from-us-sanctions-targeting-russian-energy/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 8, Mercedes Sappuppo, nonresident fellow at the Atlantic Council&amp;#8217;s Eurasia Center, was published in Kyiv Post on the one-year exemption for Hungarian imports of Russian gas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/sapuppo-in-kyiv-post-on-hungarian-exemption-from-us-sanctions-targeting-russian-energy/"&gt;Sapuppo in Kyiv Post on Hungarian exemption from US sanctions targeting Russian energy&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/sapuppo-in-kyiv-post-on-hungarian-exemption-from-us-sanctions-targeting-russian-energy/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 08 Nov 2025 20:34:52 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Wieslander on Deep Dish on Global Affairs Podcast</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/wieslander-on-deep-dish-on-global-affairs-podcast/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Anna Wieslander, Director for Northern Europe, featured on Thursday November 6 in the&amp;#160;Deep Dish&amp;#160;on Global Affairs Podcast by the Chicago Council on Global Affairs on the Arctic. Wieslander discussed how the Arctic from a European perspective has gone from a non-tension area with essentially no focus on security issues, to an area of increasing tensions [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/wieslander-on-deep-dish-on-global-affairs-podcast/"&gt;Wieslander on Deep Dish on Global Affairs Podcast&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/wieslander-on-deep-dish-on-global-affairs-podcast/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2025 23:37:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>A next-generation agenda: South Korea-US-Australia security cooperation</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/issue-brief/a-next-generation-agenda-south-korea-us-australia-security-cooperation/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Growing collaboration and cooperation between the United States, South Korea, and Australia could be key to maintaining security and prosperity in the Indo-Pacific. The Atlantic Council and the Korea Foundation gathered rising experts from the United States, South Korea, and Australia to identify obstacles to that cooperation and opportunities to overcome them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/issue-brief/a-next-generation-agenda-south-korea-us-australia-security-cooperation/"&gt;A next-generation agenda: South Korea-US-Australia security cooperation&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/in-depth-research-reports/issue-brief/a-next-generation-agenda-south-korea-us-australia-security-cooperation/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The Bio-Pharma Industry and Society</title><link>https://www.csis.org/events/bio-pharma-industry-and-society</link><description>&lt;span&gt;The Bio-Pharma Industry and Society&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;Please join the CSIS Global Health Policy Center on March 17, from 10:00am – 11:30am, for an exploration of how private bio-pharmaceutical firms can better support the critically important societal goals of improved affordability, access, quality, and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

          
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Drupal Admin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Thu, 03/03/2016 - 15:36
&lt;/span&gt;

  
    Featured Image
              
  
  
        
  
    Image
                



          


          

          

  
    Contributors
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/people/j-stephen-morrison" hreflang="en"&gt;J. Stephen Morrison&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Downloads
          
              
  
      
            Download Transcript Here
      
  
    Document
              &lt;span class="file file--mime-application-pdf file--application-pdf"&gt;&lt;a href="https://csis-website-prod.s3.amazonaws.com/s3fs-public/event/160317_The_Bio-Pharma_Industry_and_Society_Transcript.pdf" type="application/pdf"&gt;160317_The_Bio-Pharma_Industry_and_Society_Transcript.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;

          

  

              
      

  
    Programs &amp;amp; Projects
          
              

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Global Health Policy Center&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Parent
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/global-development" hreflang="en"&gt;Global Development&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/44257/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;220325_GHPC_Banner_0.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;CSIS’ Global Health Policy Center (GHPC) is the leading research institution focused on building bipartisan awareness and shaping policy debate about global health and its importance to U.S. national security&lt;/p&gt;

          

  
    Navigation
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/commissions"&gt;Commissions&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/topics"&gt;Topics&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/featured-projects"&gt;Featured Projects&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/analysis"&gt;Analysis&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/podcasts"&gt;Podcasts&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/events"&gt;Events&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/videos"&gt;Videos&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/staff-and-affiliates"&gt;Staff and Affiliates&lt;/a&gt;
          &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/programs/global-health-policy-center/archive"&gt;Archive&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  



          

  
      &lt;h2&gt;
      &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/global-development" rel="bookmark"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Global Development&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;
    &lt;/h2&gt;
    

  
  
    
  
    Featured Image
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/media/59252/edit" hreflang="en"&gt;hero-bg-human-security.jpg&lt;/a&gt;
          

  
    Listing Summary
              &lt;p&gt;CSIS’s Global Development Department is dedicated to strengthening U.S. national security and global prosperity through policies that promote human wellbeing and economic opportunity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our scholars conduct timely analysis and work directly with policymakers, industry leaders, and civil society to generate innovative solutions to today’s unprecedented&amp;nbsp;international development challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

          

  



              
      

  
    Topics
          
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/topics/global-health" hreflang="en"&gt;Global Health&lt;/a&gt;
              
      

  
    Event Dates
          
              Thu, 03/17/2016 - 10:00
 - Thu, 03/17/2016 - 11:30

              
      

  
    Featured Video
              
  
      
            

      
  

          

  
    Enable Registration
              Off
          

  
    Display Event Menu Bar
              Off
          

  
    Event Type
              &lt;a href="https://www.csis.org/taxonomy/term/3012" hreflang="en"&gt;Event&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.csis.org/events/bio-pharma-industry-and-society</guid><pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2016 20:36:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>House of Representatives to vote on release of Epstein files after Trump U-turn – US politics live</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/nov/18/house-vote-jeffrey-epstein-files-donald-trump-republicans-democrats-us-politics-live-news</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Move comes after Donald Trump dropped his opposition to a vote on releasing files on the late convicted sex offender Jeffrey Epstein&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/nov/18/house-vote-epstein-documents"&gt;Full report: House set to vote on release of Epstein documents&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/nov/18/epstein-files-release-vote"&gt;Explainer: what to know about the US House vote&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/2025/jul/24/what-are-jeffrey-epstein-documents-trump"&gt;Explainer: What are the Epstein files?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;The other big event for Trump today is the official visit of Saudi Arabia’s de facto leader Crown Prince Mohammed bin Salman, who has been welcomed back at the White House for the first time since the 2018 killing of Washington Post journalist Jamal Khashoggi by Saudi agents.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;US-Saudi relations deteriorated after Khashoggi’s brutal killing. He had been a fierce critic of the kingdom; US intelligence concluded that bin Salman had most likely ordered state agents to kill him.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/nov/18/house-vote-jeffrey-epstein-files-donald-trump-republicans-democrats-us-politics-live-news"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/us-news/live/2025/nov/18/house-vote-jeffrey-epstein-files-donald-trump-republicans-democrats-us-politics-live-news</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:19:21 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>California farms applied millions of pounds of PFAS to key crops, study finds</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/nov/18/california-pfas-forever-chemicals</link><description>&lt;p&gt;‘Forever chemicals’ sprayed on almonds, grapes, tomatoes and other crops as activists warn of ‘obvious problem’&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;California farms applied an average of 2.5m lbs of PFAS “forever chemicals” per year on cropland from 2018 to 2023, or a total of about 15m lbs, a new review of state records shows.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The chemicals are added to pesticides that are sprayed on crops such as almonds, pistachios, wine grapes, alfalfa and tomatoes, the review of California Department of Pesticide Regulation data found. The Environmental Working Group nonprofit put together the report.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/nov/18/california-pfas-forever-chemicals"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/environment/2025/nov/18/california-pfas-forever-chemicals</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 12:00:51 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Rocky Mountain Power announces 'internal investigation' of massive power outage</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ozy98t/rocky_mountain_power_announces_internal/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ozy98t/rocky_mountain_power_announces_internal/"&gt; &lt;img alt="Rocky Mountain Power announces 'internal investigation' of massive power outage" src="https://external-preview.redd.it/ZUfJi1np8Uf7fKbBgDigaLlyE1g2Nii1Dz00ePf3Gjg.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=b4b33b452705bfd1ed4dab2f2887464a2dc3e4f2" title="Rocky Mountain Power announces 'internal investigation' of massive power outage" /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/AnnaBishop1138"&gt; /u/AnnaBishop1138 &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://wyofile.com/rocky-mountain-power-announces-internal-investigation-of-massive-power-outage/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ozy98t/rocky_mountain_power_announces_internal/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1ozy98t/rocky_mountain_power_announces_internal/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 01:05:06 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Nestlé accused of ’risking health of babies for profit’ over added sugar in cereals sold in African countries</title><link>https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/nov/17/nestle-accused-of-risking-health-of-babies-for-profit-over-added-sugar-in-cereals-sold-in-african-countries</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Campaigners say the company is contributing to rising rates of childhood obesity, while the firm says it is helping to combat malnutrition&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nestlé is still adding sugar to most baby cereals sold across Africa, according to an investigation by campaigners who have accused the company of “putting the health of African babies at risk for profit”.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The food firm was accused of “double standards” over the researchers’ findings, which come at a time when rates of childhood obesity &lt;a href="https://www.afro.who.int/news/number-overweight-children-aged-under-5-africa-has-nearly-doubled-1990"&gt;are rising&lt;/a&gt; on the continent, prompting calls for Nestlé to remove all added sugar from baby-food products.&lt;/p&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/nov/17/nestle-accused-of-risking-health-of-babies-for-profit-over-added-sugar-in-cereals-sold-in-african-countries"&gt;Continue reading...&lt;/a&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.theguardian.com/global-development/2025/nov/17/nestle-accused-of-risking-health-of-babies-for-profit-over-added-sugar-in-cereals-sold-in-african-countries</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 23:00:17 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Russia-led Regional Integration Projects Continue to Flounder</title><link>https://jamestown.org/russia-led-regional-integration-projects-continue-to-flounder/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Executive Summary: The Eurasian Economic Union (EAEU)—comprising Russia, Belarus, Armenia, Kazakhstan, and Kyrgyzstan—continues to promote regional integration despite its decade-long existence yielding a resounding lack of results. A new set of procedures to deepen integration processes, known as the “Lead Protocol No.4” («IV Большой» протокол; “IV Bol’shoi” protokol), was approved by the Supreme Council—the trade [&amp;#8230;]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://jamestown.org/russia-led-regional-integration-projects-continue-to-flounder/"&gt;Russia-led Regional Integration Projects Continue to Flounder&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://jamestown.org"&gt;Jamestown&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://jamestown.org/russia-led-regional-integration-projects-continue-to-flounder/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2025 21:23:23 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>The year sunlight went global: how the Paris Agreement brought solar power to the world. The Paris summit ten years ago ignited the growth of solar electricity in major emerging markets, notably China, India and Brazil, helping turn solar into the world’s fastest-growing source of electricity.</title><link>https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oyqsbq/the_year_sunlight_went_global_how_the_paris/</link><description>&lt;table&gt; &lt;tr&gt;&lt;td&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oyqsbq/the_year_sunlight_went_global_how_the_paris/"&gt; &lt;img alt="The year sunlight went global: how the Paris Agreement brought solar power to the world. The Paris summit ten years ago ignited the growth of solar electricity in major emerging markets, notably China, India and Brazil, helping turn solar into the world’s fastest-growing source of electricity." src="https://external-preview.redd.it/BBVz4peflGJvZAy6yqCcrUuWvxZv8M9beUSg-kCD9pA.jpeg?width=640&amp;amp;crop=smart&amp;amp;auto=webp&amp;amp;s=9f4b94f14654102edad5d0d17be170df1937cd4d" title="The year sunlight went global: how the Paris Agreement brought solar power to the world. The Paris summit ten years ago ignited the growth of solar electricity in major emerging markets, notably China, India and Brazil, helping turn solar into the world’s fastest-growing source of electricity." /&gt; &lt;/a&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;td&gt; &amp;#32; submitted by &amp;#32; &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/user/mafco"&gt; /u/mafco &lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://ember-energy.org/latest-insights/the-year-sunlight-went-global-how-the-paris-agreement-brought-solar-power-to-the-world/"&gt;[link]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &amp;#32; &lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oyqsbq/the_year_sunlight_went_global_how_the_paris/"&gt;[comments]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/td&gt;&lt;/tr&gt;&lt;/table&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.reddit.com/r/energy/comments/1oyqsbq/the_year_sunlight_went_global_how_the_paris/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 16 Nov 2025 16:57:22 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Nov. 10-14, 2025)</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Veterans Day • Russia-Ukraine War • U.S. military / Immigration • Israel-Hamas War • Anti-corruption series • Afghanistan • Violent extremism • Trump executive actions • U.S. foreign policy / Nigeria • Data privacy • Latin America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/"&gt;Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Nov. 10-14, 2025)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Nov. 10-14, 2025)</title><link>https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Veterans Day • Russia-Ukraine War • U.S. military / Immigration • Israel-Hamas War • Anti-corruption series • Afghanistan • Violent extremism • Trump executive actions • U.S. foreign policy / Nigeria • Data privacy • Latin America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/"&gt;Digest of Recent Articles on Just Security (Nov. 10-14, 2025)&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.justsecurity.org"&gt;Just Security&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.justsecurity.org/124332/digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025/?utm_source=rss&amp;utm_medium=rss&amp;utm_campaign=digest-recent-articles-just-security-nov-10-14-2025</guid><pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 11:48:04 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Donovan, Nikoladze and de Kruijf cited in a report by the CFHK Foundation on Canada’s economic statecraft</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/donovan-nikoladze-and-de-kruijf-cited-in-a-report-by-the-cfhk-foundation-on-canadas-economic-statecraft/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;Read the full report here&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/donovan-nikoladze-and-de-kruijf-cited-in-a-report-by-the-cfhk-foundation-on-canadas-economic-statecraft/"&gt;Donovan, Nikoladze and de Kruijf cited in a report by the CFHK Foundation on Canada&amp;#8217;s economic statecraft&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/donovan-nikoladze-and-de-kruijf-cited-in-a-report-by-the-cfhk-foundation-on-canadas-economic-statecraft/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:20:19 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>'Weekend Snipers' Claims Reopen Wartime Trauma In Sarajevo</title><link>https://www.rferl.org/a/italy-probe-bosnian-war-human-safari-snipers-murder/33591128.html</link><description>For three decades, many people in Bosnia have sought an answer for how and why their loved ones were gunned down by snipers during the war. In recent days, their grief has been reignited by Italian media reports about an investigation being conducted in Milan into so-called "weekend snipers."</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rferl.org/a/italy-probe-bosnian-war-human-safari-snipers-murder/33591128.html</guid><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 18:31:33 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Recording: The Growth of Chinese Money Laundering Organisations</title><link>https://www.rusi.org/research-event-recordings/recording-growth-chinese-money-laundering-organisations</link><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;A panel discussion launching our research paper investigating the proliferation and success of Chinese money laundering operations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.rusi.org/research-event-recordings/recording-growth-chinese-money-laundering-organisations</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title>Grundman featured in Defense &amp; Aerospace Report on defense acquisition reform</title><link>https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/grundman-featured-in-defense-aerospace-report-on-defense-acquisition-reform/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;On November 11, Forward Defense senior fellow Steven Grundman was featured in a Defense &amp;#038; Aerospace Report podcast episode entitled "Deep Dive in to Sec Hegseth's Acquisition Reforms." &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The post &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/grundman-featured-in-defense-aerospace-report-on-defense-acquisition-reform/"&gt;Grundman featured in Defense &amp;amp; Aerospace Report on defense acquisition reform&lt;/a&gt; appeared first on &lt;a href="https://www.atlanticcouncil.org"&gt;Atlantic Council&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description><guid isPermaLink="true">https://www.atlanticcouncil.org/insight-impact/in-the-news/grundman-featured-in-defense-aerospace-report-on-defense-acquisition-reform/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 21:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>